I wonder...
Do we all know where we belong?
And if we do, in our hearts,
why do we so often
do nothing about it?
There must be more to this life--
a purpose for us all,
a place to belong.
You were my home.
I knew from the moment I met you...
that night, so many years ago.
Well, come on and let me know
Should I stay or should I go?
Should I stay or should I go now?
If I go, there will be trouble
And if I stay, it will be double
So come on and let me know...
Thanks a lot.
Should I stay or should I go now?
Thank you.
If I go, there will be trouble
And if I stay, it will be double
So, you've got to let me know
Should I stay or should I go?
Thank you!
Thank you very much.
Lovely.
I want to thank the band.
After that racket,
I can only appear good.
Now, Margaret Thatcher...
you've got to hand it to her.
Love her or hate her,
Margaret Thatcher is definitely
the strongest man in the Tory Party.
Charley!
Hi, sis.
Oh, you're freezing.
I know... I couldn't get a cab--
God's punishment.
You don't believe in God.
I know. So that's Henry, huh?
Hm-mm.
- Very handsome.
Hi, I'm Charlotte.
How are you? Oh...
Oh, it's good to meet you.
Likewise.
I'm so sorry I missed the wedding.
No, no, no, no.
I'm sure she's already told you,
I'm crap at appointments
and times and stuff.
Well, she did mention...
Mind you, she is absolutely nuts,
but you married her,
so you must know, right?
We should introduce you around.
Come with me.
Mom, Dad, may I introduce you
to Sarah's sister, Charlotte.
Yes, of course.
How do you do?
My parents, Mr. and Mrs. Bauford.
Oh, thank goodness, you both
have the same last name.
Good.
Pleasure to meet you, Charlotte,
or do you say Charley?
Um, right now, I'd say I'm a mess,
so if you don't mind...
I'll take you to the bathroom.
Okay.
Back in a sec.
Although, according to one
Ethiopian village log drummer,
it translates as "I've just
eaten a sodden grape pie."
Ha-ha.
Oh...
Sorry.
Look at you.
Oh, sweetie, you look beautiful.
Look at you... you're in a dress.
Oh, please, a dress.
I look like Ivana Trump
after a couple of rounds, baby.
Whew.
Come here.
What?
First, you've got to be kidding me.
You know this is pointless.
Oh, I hate this.
So what do you think of him?
I think he's an absolute sweetheart.
He's gorgeous, really, he is.
He is, and he's sweet
and he's funny and wild.
He's very English.
You married a very English Englishman.
You're blushing!
How's home?
Home's good. It misses you.
Work?
Oh, you know, very exciting.
They gave me a story
about a 10-car pile-up
on 54th Street.
You know, whatever.
Looking up?
Oh, top of the news pile, you know?
You will be.
Someday.
But on that note,
I think it's time I left the stage
and brought on someone
very special indeed.
Thank you very much.
Hi, um...
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but Mr. Bauford's son, Henry,
would like to make an announcement.
Thank you.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
as you know, one of the reasons
we're here tonight
is to show our appreciation
to Lawrence Bauford
for all the great work he's done
as Chairman of Aid Relief International.
Sir... Sir!
Sarah!
Oh, darling.
She's cut.
- Oh God.
Are you all right?
You ask me, it's a bloody rip-off.
1,000 quid for an over-cooked meal
and a dry hump on the dance floor,
but still, we're all
getting drunk for a good cause.
Right?
Cheers.
Get him out of here.
It's a bit difficult...
Well, bloody do something.
20 quid a head right there.
Diwy a room rental, maybe another 20.
30 on catering.
It's got to be 50 quid on overhead.
There you go, Jojo.
That's your cut.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You haven't met.
This is Jojo.
Actually, he's curious about your dinner
because when I met him,
he was so hungry
he was trying to eat his own tongue.
Funny enough, they don't do
Caesar salad with that.
No, listen,
I'll be honest, and I do want
to be honest.
He was a pile of bones
in a pool of shit,
and I don't mean civilized shit either.
This was the yellow stuff,
liquid fucking evil.
Anyhow, I've got 2,000 kids
in my camp in Africa
with the same problem,
and some fucking asshole here
has pulled our funding.
So I guess I'm just going
to have to feed them flies.
Now, Jojo here, he wanted to know why.
So I showed him this.
"Due to the repressive political climate,
"we can no longer sustain a relief presence
in Communist-supported Ethiopia."
Is that a fair description, Larry?
Or did you want a more positive spin?
All right, Dr. Callahan.
You've said your piece.
Now you can leave.
Why don't you come up here? Come on.
The kid just wants to hear
in words he can understand.
2,000 lives, what does that buy you?
A new car?
A new pair of tits for the wife?
Well, come on, don't be shy.
I've got a camp
with 30,000 people, dying at 40 a day.
I've got measles, typhoid, cholera...
every miserable fucking disease
known to man.
Six weeks from now, they'll all be dead.
Come on.
Talk to me.
Oh, I get it.
It's the monkey joke, right?
You want him to go...
for you, yeah?
Oh, he'll do that.
He'll do that for you.
Jojo...
300 calories in one banana--
more than he gets in a day.
He'll do whatever you want.
Jojo!
All right, you want to get down
out of the van now, please?
Sir?
Excuse me, sir.
Can you get down
from the vehicle now, please?
Come on. In you go.
Dr. Callahan, I presume?
I was there tonight.
I was compelled.
EGRIS.
Sounds pretentious enough to be a charity.
No, wait a minute, I remember.
I was in India when
you lot were working the
borders with Afghanistan.
Rumors were, you got in.
There's a lot of people
still dying over there.
They always do, Doctor.
Yeah, well, I'm no warrior.
I'm in the relief business.
So I gathered.
So, here we are--
you with your relief work,
me with my relief work.
And isn't it a strange coincidence,
because I need to get into Ethiopia,
and you're already there.
No thanks.
I'd fund your work
of course.
No.
"I've got a camp with 30,000
people, dying at 40 a day.
In 6 weeks time, they'll all be dead."
Slight exaggeration perhaps,
but very effective.
Since when did the CIA give a shit
about the starving in Africa?
I presume you are CIA, Mr. Steiger.
Idle curiosity...
Your performance tonight,
was it a cry for help,
or a cry for attention?
I'd call it a press conference.
No, a declaration of independence.
Freedom is an expensive commodity.
You should see what I paid for your bail.
No deal.
Passion is cheap, Doctor.
If you're looking for a dancing bear,
try the fucking circus.
Hmm. Cigarettes at dawn.
Either you're deliriously happy,
or you haven't slept.
Do you need me to call you a cab?
No, I already called one.
How's your hand?
Oh, it's fine.
So, Henry, is he, uh...?
Oh, he's-he's still sleeping.
Oh.
So...
I'm going to miss you.
Yeah, me, too.
But, you know, listen,
if it gets too English over here,
you give me a call, and l'll send you
a nice American care package
full of macaroni and cheese
and apple pie, and a pair of sneakers.
That'll go over well here in
fashionable London, I'm sure.
Hello?
Cab for Ms. Jordan.
- Okay, thank you.
Well, it's here.
Tell Mr. Sleepy Pants,
that I said good-bye, pip-pip, cheerio,
or whatever the hell they do here.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Bye, sis.
Take care.
- You, too.
...the boy escaped while being transferred
to the immigration
facility at Heathrow Airport.
His body was found early this morning
here under Junction 5.
Initial reports suggest
he died of hypothermia.
A spokesman for the Immigration Department
blamed the security lapse
on staff shortages.
We are told that the boy
was arrested the previous night
in a disturbance at a charity
ball in a London hotel.
A man identified as Nicholas Callahan,
a relief worker in Ethiopia,
interrupted the event
with an emotional plea
for more help in Africa.
At Junction 5, Aidan Pickering, LNS.
When Dubuque started,
you could see how much
she owed to Van Gogh.
She didn't hide it;
it's in all her landscapes,
But if you look here, what she's
doing in this abstract
is something much more
calculated, more developed.
The way she takes the-the theme
of attraction and repulsion,
dark against light.
Over here, another piece, which I think
has even more emotional depth.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Now, we do have...
other examples of her work,
which I think you should see.
Sweetheart, are you sure you
know what you're doing?
Yes, I do.
And before you say anything, I've spoken
to all the relevant relief
organizations and embassies,
and with 40,000 pounds...
40,000 pounds?
What are you talking about?
Where are you going to find 40,000...?
...and supplies from surplus
regions in Southern Sudan.
And from there, I transport them to Tigre.
I've cleared out my savings,
I'm still short about 8,000.
But, Sarah, this isn't how it's done.
You don't go...
Henry, Henry. I've made up my mind.
Well, then send the money,
do charitable work, whatever,
but don't go roaring off
to some godforsaken hole in Africa
just to salve your conscience.
It's just too...
Too what?
Well, it's not the most
grown-up way to deal with
this situation.
Well, maybe I don't want to grow up.
Fine...
Fine.
If that's what you want,
It is.
- Then fine.
Then...
I'll help you find the money.
Thank you.
I'll talk to Dad.
He knows everybody.
Mind you, Ethiopia is a bit...
It'll be fine.
It'll be fine. We'll find the money.
Come with me.
Honey, even if I could...
You can't?
No, it's not that.
You know me, I'm not made
for that kind of thing.
I'm a city boy. I need 4 walls and a bed.
Besides, I've got meetings up to here
for the next month.
You should go.
You've got the right attitude.
Listen, I know this sounds
like Little Miss Bleeding Heart
and all that... I just, I don't care.
I know I'm being crazy
and driving you crazy,
and of course I understand
you can't come, but...
you meet me off the plane?
You meet me off the plane?
Of course l'll meet you off the plane.
Three years and no rain, not a drop.
That, and war.
People leave their homes,
they walk for many days.
We only have 10 camps on the south side.
Too many people, not enough camps.
Measles, you know measles?
Yes, of course.
We lose more people
to measles and diarrhea.
Many die, no vaccine.
We brought some vaccines...
- Also cholera, everywhere.
We dig very deep now for good water.
Starvation everywhere, death is everywhere.
You speak English very well.
Missionaries teach me.
Yeah?
So are you married?
Do you have a husband?
- Man? Bullshit.
I need no man.
They beg to marry me, many times,
but I drive truck.
Lazy man, good-for-nothing.
I'm too old now anyway.
No man in my village want woman over 18.
In my tribe, it's 30.
Stop.
Stop the truck. Stop. Stop!
Abraha!
Abraha...
Is this your son?
This your son?
Abraha...
Abraha?
Ab-Ab...
No baby.
We go. Too dangerous to stop.
We go now.
Is a waste.
Child and mother, both a waste.
Stupid baby woman.
Tula, shut up.
I'll give you 4 bags.
4 bags not enough.
I take 1 truck.
You want to tell them that
you're taking half their food?
How many are you? 50? A hundred?
My men fight...
I know, I know-- for the people.
Mm.
It's good.
No. No, no, no, no.
8 bags.
4 each truck.
This is fair.
Hmm, Mr. Elliott?
Fair, yes?
Welcome to famine relief.
Okay, kill it!
Hold his legs, okay?
Excuse me.
This child, his mother's in the truck.
She's wounded.
Too late.
- What?
Too late, as in no point.
Why?
Well, quite apart from
any illnesses they may have,
they're too weak to survive.
You, just...
You just decide that?
It's called triage. I'm a doctor.
I've got 30,000...
- I know.
I heard that already in London.
You did?
Yes. I still think you should help them.
Oh, you do, do you?
Yes, I do.
I see. You pay for these trucks,
so I have to indulge
some fucking white girl's idea
of heroism, right?
Well, why stop there?
Do you want a picture?
I can get you a picture
of "poor little rich girl
holds dying black baby."
You do your hair right, you'll look great.
I saw the child from the truck.
I picked him up,
his mother was wounded.
I brought her, too.
Can you please look at them?
Seems fair.
Kat.
Hi.
Hi. I'm Kat.
Okay, so... I'm the chief administrator
and logistician, if that
doesn't sound too pompous,
and you've met Nick,
who's our team leader and full-time doctor.
He's got a lot on his hands right now.
So this is the food-distribution center.
Low-tech but effective,
like the rest of us.
The food supplies I brought,
how long will they last?
Oh, 3 or 4 days, maybe.
That's it?
I'm afraid so, yeah.
What are you going to do
when the food runs out?
Well, we usually find a way.
Same old story really, you know--
money, or the lack of it,
but with help, we get by.
Um, I don't think you want to go...
Is it all right?
Sure. Yeah.
Well, if it isn't Mrs. Bauford.
Sorry about the mess.
You won't see this in medical school.
Cut.
If you're going to throw up,
close your eyes.
Think of ponies
and ice cream.
Is that... perfume?
You're wearing perfume in the
middle of the fucking desert.
Ha-ha.
The boy, has he been looked at?
Yes, ma'am. Checking him now.
One shed over.
As you instructed.
What does it mean?
- Sew it up.
Monica, get her a Fanta.
It's weird isn't it?
All those plans you have,
places to go, people to meet.
All that matters
in her whole world is that.
Just one suck of soda,
that's all she lives for.
She's in pain--
can't you give her something?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Monica, call down to the pharmacy
for more morphine, could you?
Where do you think you are, Saint Elsewhere?
She's in pain.
She's beyond pain.
Have you asked her that?
Hamadi.
Ask her if it hurts.
She, uh...
says she feels the pain of hunger, but
she knows that death more hungry than pain,
so, she gives thanks.
She gives thanks to you.
She calls you by a new name.
Matanay.
"He who steals from Death."
He's got a fever, and he's in shock.
Increase the fluids. Antibiotics.
You really think he's going
to sit up and take a drink?
I was just...
He's dying.
You'd better move his lips,
or he won't take a cup.
I was just trying to help.
To help, you have
to know what you're doing.
Look, I know you think I'm stupid,
and you want me to go home.
You don't have to waste any more time
trying to make that clear to me.
Get some H.E.M.
High Energy Milk.
Monica will give it to you.
You tease around his mouth with your finger.
You let him suck it out, small amounts only.
If he revives, call the nurse.
If he doesn't...
at least he'll have someone
with him when he dies.
How many?
Kat?
11 from last night.
12.
The 10-year-old.
That makes 39.
So there's more than yesterday.
I know.
Right, and you'd better hire
extra men from the camp
and get them digging more holes.
Put them on night shift
so nobody sees them.
Can't have people dying
of depression, eh?
How's the water coming, Joss?
Nothing so far.
Drive shaft is close to buggering,
and we're down to 2 liters
per person per day.
What about the tankers?
Yeah, sure. That's piss in a bucket, mate.
Basically, if we don't get the new well
up and running, we're knackered.
Okay, so what do you need exactly?
I just told you.
A new drive shaft.
Okay, I'm going to see what I can do.
Well, the good news, boys and girls,
is that the government's
finally coming tomorrow.
I got confirmation today
that Mr. Ningpopo himself will be here.
For about an hour.
That long?
Well, you never know.
We might get lucky.
- Right.
Here's what we're going to do.
First thing in the morning, we're going
to break open the new supplies,
start immunizing all the children
against measles, youngest first,
up the line, until we run out.
Okay? Kat, Monica: I want you
to get onto that as early as possible.
All right.
I'll set up the call chain
and check the syringes.
No, I'm going to need you
with me, and you, Tula.
Joss.
- Yeah.
Sanitation.
I think you need to take your team
and cut a new defecation area
somewhere beyond the camp.
Yeah, and let's just
chlorinate all the water, okay?
All of it.
Yeah, the tankard water is absolutely fine.
Fuck the tanker water.
Just chlorinate the lot.
There's too much infection
to risk leaving it, okay?
Okay.
Good.
All right, make sure
you get me your requests
for Ningpopo as soon as possible.
Two hookers and a single to Melbourne.
Business or coach?
Good night, Sarah.
Good night.
Oh, I forgot.
The boy's mother.
She died.
We've got about 10 days left.
Maybe 2 weeks, if we're lucky.
What happened with USAID?
Nothing.
CARE?
CARE, USAID, the OXFAM, WFB...
they don't want to know.
Everyone I spoke to
in Addis had an acute case
of compassion fatigue.
How 'bout the old man?
The trust fund?
My father was the politest
"fuck you" I ever got.
What about Steiger?
Some small favors,
a little info on...
Yeah, stash a shitload of weapons...
So what if he's fucking over the Marxists...
I'm not getting into business
with those people.
Listen, Elliott, if it's
all we got, I don't see why...
There is no way...
- Why not for, Christ's sake?
Because that's not how we started!
And because I wouldn't
have it any other way.
What the hell is that?
Schumann, I think.
Hi.
"I dream of childhood.
"I dream of love.
"Of a garden where a boy plays,
forever young."
"Themes from Childhood."
Part of a series
from Schumann's "Lederhosen."
Lederhosen are trousers.
Ah.
The German for song is lieder.
Lieder.
Yes, correct.
Is there something you wanted?
The baby.
You tried the H.E.M.?
Yes.
And?
And no change.
Sometimes it takes a while.
Hey, woman, come, come.
Yes.
One life.
Ningpopo's here.
Look right now
we're at 800 calories a day.
In a few days it will be down to 500.
The bottom line is,
we're not going to make
next week's distribution.
Not a chance.
And that raises the issue of security.
If I can't get these people more food,
I can't guarantee the safety of my staff.
Food, security.
I believe these are listed
as separate issues.
Yes, but I'm sure you'd
agree they're connected.
Well, if we could get some emergency corn,
that'd be a start.
I will raise it with the WFB.
Thank you.
They owe us since August anyway.
Excuse me?
- Any emergency corn
would be greatly appreciated.
I'm sorry, excuse me, who owes you?
The WFB. 3 months of corn.
It'll be in your notes.
There's no reference to the WFB in my notes.
Then your notes are wrong.
Okay, we can move on...
to the issue of security.
Our soldiers have no experience
of this order, Mr. Hauser.
Please, we have another meeting
at Kromer Camp at 4:00 p.m.
If we can deal with
these matters separately
and in the proper order.
It is no good to jump from food to security.
This is not coherent.
Not coherent?
Listen, they don't get
enough food, they get hungry.
If they get hungry, they get desperate,
they wreck the camp.
That is a security issue.
Please do not raise your voice.
For Christ's sake, they're
all fucking dying out there.
Will you please stop talking bollocks
and start getting some food delivered now.
No excuses, no money changing hands,
just do it.
I find this innuendo most
disturbing, Dr. Callahan.
I can assure you, not
a single dollar changes hands
without authorization.
Procedures of the utmost importance...
Procedures, my fucking ass.
You've got friends
in the water-trucking business
whose sole aim in life
is to hike up the price
by restricting delivery.
You seriously telling me
those shitheads are following procedure?
I find this outrageous,
especially coming from you.
What do you mean especially coming from me?
To take a refugee boy from the camp
without authorization
to die like an animal
in a country he does not know?
The death of a child
is not a minor violation, Dr. Callahan.
I can assure you,
you are under serious investigation.
What?
He'd never have given us anything anyway.
Well, he certainly isn't going to now.
What happened to his car?
Will that fit our wellhead?
Do kangaroos crap in the bush?
We've got no choice.
We need Steiger.
Dr. Callahan?
Sorry, I...
I just have some traveler's checks.
I'm leaving tomorrow, so I...
I thought I'd leave them here.
Elliott usually deals with all that.
Should I give them...?
No, I mean, it's okay,
I'll give them to him.
Okay.
So... is he going to shut you down?
Maybe.
But we always turn up again... somewhere.
I really admire you for the work you do.
Oh, Jesus. "Admire," what does that mean?
Why are you so difficult
to talk to?
- Why are you?
Why do you never say my name?
Sorry?
You never say my name.
Why?
What's the first thing you
do when you get a cold?
What?
What is the first thing you
do when you get a cold?
Chicken soup, aspirin, scotch.
You ever just have the cold?
I don't under...
Taken nothing, just have the cold.
No.
- No.
And that's us, right?
We drown it, kill it, numb it.
Anything not to feel.
You know, when I was a doctor in London,
no one ever said "matanay."
They don't thank you
like they thank you here
'cause here they feel everything.
Straight from God.
There's no drugs, there's no painkillers.
It's the weirdest, purest thing-- suffering.
And when you've seen that
kind of courage in a lit...
...in a child...
how could you ever want to do anything
but just take them in your arm?
You remember that boy in London. Jojo?
Yes, of course.
He was my first save, 10 years old.
So thin he could barely stand.
But he still found the strength
to bury the rest of his family.
We have no idea what courage is.
He used to write me these little notes.
He helped me in the clinic.
He was good.
He was sweet, he was good.
He wanted to be like me, I liked that.
I mean, it was silly and childish,
but it made me feel good about myself.
So I took him with me to London,
you know, my talisman, my courageous Africa.
How could I be so bloody stupid?
How could I be so totally selfish?
The point is...
he was my friend.
He had a name.
So now I have to remember him.
If everyone I lose has a name...
Hey.
You all set?
Yeah.
Said your good-byes?
Well.
Yeah.
Oh, um,
this is my friend at UNHCR.
She'll always know how to get ahold of us.
And that's a very good group of people.
If you ever want to jump in there...
Okay.
Um...
I'm so glad that you came, Sarah.
It meant a lot to us.
Oh, thank you.
No, no, I'm thanking you.
Mikanalay.
It means "thank you."
And then you say, "Genzubka,"
which means, "You're welcome."
Genzubka.
Yeah, pretty good.
Well, very Buddhist.
Do Buddhists hug?
Sure I hug, I'm American.
I hug everything.
Ah, Nick's up at the well.
You want me to get him?
- No, no.
Good-bye.
You take care of yourself...
and everybody else.
I'll try.
Keep in touch.
Jim.
Hey, come on.
Jim!
Baby, Mommy's got some work to do.
Come on, honey. Come here.
It's okay. It's okay, sweetie.
Honey, I'm going to count to 5.
No.
- One...
two, three...
I'll read you 2 chapters.
No. 3.
Okay, 3.
You are nothing
but a minx-ish minx.
Daddy!
Yeah, hello.
Mommy says I can have 3 chapters.
3 chapters?
Excellent.
Would you mind reading to him tonight?
I have some work to do.
Sure.
Jim, go on, jump into bed.
Oh!
- Quick kicks!
Dad'll be there in a minute.
So what's he reading?
It's on his bedside table.
Right.
About tomorrow...
I'm in the office all day.
It's just, I need
to keep looking for work.
I thought you were going
to make calls from home.
Well, I-I just should go in.
Half the city is looking.
I can't compete unless I'm there.
Can't your father call somebody?
He's already done everything he can.
Dad lost everything in the market crash,
like everybody else.
I know that.
I know, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
So...
I think I should go in.
Henry, I arranged meetings,
especially because you said
you'd do the school run.
Well, can't we ask someone?
There must be people at his school...
You call.
I'm sick of asking for favors.
Don't. Don't!
You didn't bother doing it
in the first place,
don't do it now.
I was trying to help.
No, you were bargaining.
What if I was?
Is that a crime?
You know, because I can argue...
I can shout.
I hate this situation.
I hate not having a job.
I don't see what good
it does to make each other
feel worse than we already do.
Sarah.
Look at this room-- it's a mess.
We'll sort it out.
Things will pick up.
There's a chance, I've got
a meeting with this guy
who's really big in futures,
and I'm going to try
and get a meeting with him.
We will sort it out.
He's waiting for you to read to him.
Okay.
Thanks.
I understand.
Michael... Michael, that's bullshit.
UNHCR sends more aid to Honduras
than any other UN agency.
Even as I speak...
Well, most people don't even
know where Honduras is.
...East and West Berliners alike
are tearing down
the greatest symbol
of Communist repression...
No.
North of Panama in the Caribbean Sea.
But you must keep repeating it
to yourself to believe it.
The Berlin Wall is finally coming down.
And the sense of hope you get here...
Which is precisely why I need aid.
November 9, 1989,
a night that marked the opening
of a new chapter
in world history.
Michael, I have to call you back.
Okay.
UNHCR.
Sarah?
Yes. Who's calling?
Uh, it's me, Elliott.
Elliott?
Hi.
Hi!
How... how are you? Are you okay?
Oh, oh, yeah.
Where are you?
Um, Oh, I'm actually, believe it or not,
I'm here in a phone booth in-in London.
Oh, my God.
You know, I'm sorry,
there's a terrible connection...
but nothing seems to work
in this shitty place.
When can I see you?
Oh, uh, well, um...
I'm in the Holland Park
Tube Station right now.
Uh, could you meet me
by the entrance to the park?
Yeah.
Oh...
- Yes, yes, of course!
Great.
- Um, uh...
1:30, is that... is that okay?
Sounds perfect.
Henry?
Hi, honey.
Bea just popped around to say hello.
Do you remember Bea?
She used to work with Dad.
Hi, there.
Hi.
I thought you had job interviews today.
Uh, they all got canceled.
Oh.
I-I just came by to get
some warm stuff for Jimmy,
so I'm going to go pick him up.
Hello.
Hey.
He-He-Hey.
Oh...
Oh, my gosh. Look at you.
Here, come, sit.
Oh, gosh, it's good to see you.
Well, you, too.
So you got my last letter?
Yeah. You were in Pakistan.
Pakistan?
That was months ago.
Haven't I...?
You've been busy saving lives.
It's okay, I forgive you.
Well... well, we're not in Pakistan anymore.
We're in Cambodia, by the Thai border.
You okay?
How's home?
Fine.
Jimmy?
Gorgeous.
But bien sur.
So, you're in London, and you
called me out of the blue.
Is that because I'm with the
United Nations or just because
I'd never forgive you if you didn't?
Both.
Tell me.
What do you know about Cambodia?
There's a civil war going on,
Communist coalition forces
headed by the Khmer Rouge
versus Communist Vietnamese
running the government.
I believe the British
calls it political irony.
Yeah. Well, Nick calls it a clusterfuck.
But that's Nick,
not one that minces words.
How is he?
Is he good?
He's Nick.
Was it his idea for you to come here?
No. No, both of us.
I mean, I... I wanted to see you anyway,
and you know, I always do this...
Nick can't pitch to... save his life.
Well, you saw that.
Sorry, where, where, where was I?
Cambodia.
Ah, right.
Well... according to Washington,
the place doesn't officially exist,
although there's something
like half a million people
living under Khmer Rouge domination.
Dysentery, measles,
pneumonia, no vaccines, of course,
so death rates run 15 to 20 people a day
in every village, and there's
land mines, lots of them.
So, we have amputees without prosthetics.
It's not a happy place.
So what do you need?
Well, I put together
a shipment of supplies,
vaccines, medicines, the usual.
But there's so much corruption
out there, I was wondering,
I mean, the thing would be if...
Elliott, just... just say it.
If we could put a UN stamp on it.
I mean, the point is, the UN
name still means something.
You know, just a little bit
of extra protection.
Obviously, I would take
full responsibility.
You just do the paperwork.
Well, we do have shipments going
into Thailand and Cambodia.
So, I'll attach your name to the list.
Thank you.
And I'll go with it. I'll see it through.
Oh, no, you don't need to.
I know, but I do this now.
Yeah, but Cambodia is different.
I'll see it through.
So, what is it, what do they want?
Money, Miss Sarah.
Shit! They see you, they want more.
Always more money, huh?!
I'm not playing their games.
- What?
I'm not giving them any more money.
They want their money.
They've already gotten the 10%
that's written in the contract.
- Contract shit, you pay.
No.
- Miss Sarah.
I'm not giving them any more money.
They need more, you pay. You no say no.
Tell them to get the rest of that shipment
off the boat right now.
- What? Or what?
What you do?
This not Chelsea football.
This Cambodia.
You pay. You pay!
It's 2 weeks late.
What the hell is going on, Steiger?
You want a beer?
I want to know what's going on.
Crates were late, so...
Shit happens. So what?
Have you got any idea how fast
a measles epidemic spreads in 2 weeks?
I've got enough stains
in my laundry, Callahan.
You're not my only child.
Just give me the money.
Bringing your titty
from the UN was a smart idea.
You want to screw? Take your pick.
25 thousand.
And tell that sorry excuse for a colonel
that it's 25 more than he deserves.
Mrs. Bauford is waiting.
Listen, you piece of shit.
Fucking with me is one thing,
but if anything happens to her...
Then what?
Remember, Callahan, I'm the guy
that makes you possible.
You owe me, you took the fucking money,
now you will do this,
and you will do this right.
What's the matter? Scared of the dark?
Now fuck off and save lives.
How'd that happen?
If I can ask.
Oh.
Before time,
I was sick, bad lung, TB.
At this time no doctor where I live.
Khmer Rouge kill our doctor.
So, I walk to border for medicine,
but I must cross the mine field first.
You never forget that sound.
The first thing you hear is click.
It's your foot priming the land mine.
Soon as you hear it,
it's over.
But your mind go crazy, you know?
You thinking, maybe if I jump,
maybe if I find a rock
to match my weight...
But it's nothing you can do.
You hear the click and big bye-bye.
But,
I was lucky.
Just lose my leg.
Any problems?
None.
You're not wearing perfume.
So, are you going to tell me
where we're going?
A place near Pailin,
by the border.
And the boat's the best way to travel?
You don't like my boat?
I think it's very you.
It's safer.
Avoids the road blocks,
the Viet troops,
plus other assorted madness.
You know, heart of darkness.
The horror.
Actually it is.
Horrible.
And now you're going to tell me why.
Well, Elliott's no good, is he?
All he gives you is the Buddhist version,
all fucking temples
and gentle people, which is bollocks.
The Khmer Rouge--
rouge being very much
the appropriate color--
used Pailin as a hideout.
Everyone lives in absolute terror.
They use the women
as baby-making factories,
the kids as mine sweepers,
and just in case
we actually help anybody,
they come and steal everything
that we don't hide.
So why do they let you stay at all?
They've got no doctors.
I should be singing "Old Man River."
Please don't.
Colonel Tao, how are you doing?
It's good to see you again.
The boxes, they for who?
Well, you know who they're for.
I give you my word.
This goes only to the women and children.
Wait, easy, that's medicine,
for Christ's sake!
I don't understand, what's the problem?
It's a laptop.
Every NGO has got one.
That's the way we do business here.
Don't throw those away.
People's lives depend on that,
for fuck's sake!
Colonel...
- Sarah...
I'm with UNHCR, United Nations.
This cargo is protected.
If this shipment is harmed in any way,
your name will surface
in the follow-up investigation.
I don't...
I promise you, I know nothing about this.
Somebody must have...
Colonel Tao, you know me.
I swear to God,
I don't...
Son of a bitch!
What was that?
You explain it to me.
I can't explain it to you.
We were set up.
I knew nothing about that book,
what was in the box, the equipment...
Did you know about the guns?
Answer me! Did you know...?
Yes, I knew about them.
I came here to help these people,
and the only way I can do that
is if I transport guns.
- You don't have
to transport guns to help people.
You do here.
Right. So fuck the next person
that tries to bring
a shipment full of medicine in for people.
Fuck them.
As long as you get what you need today,
fuck everybody else!
No one else comes here,
so what do you want me to do?
You want me to watch
thousands of kids die of measles
'cause l wouldn't bend the rules?
Is that a price worth paying?
Or am I actually killing more than I save?
You seriously believe that
I don't worry about that?
That I don't think about that
every minute of every day?
What's worse? You tell me.
You tell me what I should do.
What happened?
Never compromise another organization
for your own ever again.
I won't.
Sarah, you made it.
Oh, good to see you.
So, I believe congratulations are in order?
I know, can you believe it?
Oh...
What the hell happened?
No guns-- confiscated by Tao.
He found these intelligence files.
They freaked him out.
What intelligence files?
Well, how do I know?
He was tipped off.
He was waiting for us.
He found these documents.
He went fucking crazy.
Well, if we don't have anything
for the Khmer Rouge,
we're in deep shit.
We leave in the morning.
Take everyone with us.
No, we need to leave sooner than that.
We've got all this vaccine.
I'm not wasting it.
We don't have time. We need to go now.
Not until we vaccinate.
This is not worth risking our lives for.
You do whatever you got to do.
I'm staying.
Joss, remember to pack the iodine.
And the emergency kits-- how many we got?
Joss?
No, no. They...
He says that we're thieves,
that we stole his files
and his guns, and he wants them back.
Tell him the truth.
And tell him that we're trying
to save his bloody people.
He doesn't give a shit about the people.
He just want the file.
So tell him whatever he wants.
Just try and buy us some time.
He wants us to...
He wants us to what?
He wants us to make amends now.
He wants us to go to Pailin.
You know what that means.
He say now.
Okay.
Tell him that Sarah is from the UN.
And that the UN is very
important to Big God Ankha,
and if anything happens to her or to us,
the UN will crucify him.
He say you are a CIA agent
working for Vietnam.
One of you must die.
English doctor, you say
all you care about is my people.
Life mean nothing.
We serve only Ankha.
Now you will see.
For God's sake, he's just a baby.
Tell them to drop their guns.
Tell them to drop their fucking weapons now!
No!
Tell them to back off. Back off!
Tell them to back off.
Look, as long as we hold due west,
we hit the river.
That's about 2 miles.
And the camp's up there.
About another 3 miles north,
just over the Thai border.
Oh, Jesus.
Shit. That's Khmer Rouge.
They've reached the village.
At this rate, they're going to catch up.
Keep them moving.
Keep them moving!
Tell them we're nearly there.
Sierra Tango 619.
This is Outpost Grade 7.
Sierra Tango, come in.
Me father. Me father.
Look! Look! Helicopter!
Helicopter!
Looks Vietnamese, mate.
Good, that will keep them busy.
Nick?
It wasn't your fault.
Yes, it was.
If I'd have listened to him,
none of this would have happened.
I couldn't even bury him properly.
I didn't even give him
a decent fucking burial.
Elliott wanted to dedicate his life
to helping other people.
And in the end, he died for them.
Be proud of him.
Miss him... but be proud of him.
I don't know what
I'm going to do without him.
I can't stop; I've got to keep going.
There's so much...
- I'm worried about you, here.
I'm worried that something
is going to happen to you.
Every day for 4 years,
every morning, I wake up and I wonder
if you're okay, if you're still alive,
where you are.
Shall l ring down for some room service?
Chocolate cake...
and some air-conditioning.
That'd be lovely.
How did you meet Henry?
I was staring at a Roscoe.
What's that, some sort of dishwasher?
It was a painting.
I used to work at an art gallery.
And one day, Henry came in.
How old were you?
Too young.
But you stayed together?
Yeah.
We've both known that
the marriage has been over
for a long time.
But we stayed together for Jimmy.
You love him very much, don't you?
He's amazing.
I'm going to have to start making plans
to go to New York.
See Elliott's parents,
tell them what happened.
How long will you be gone?
I don't know, no idea.
What is this?
What are you doing?
I'm absolutely crazy about you.
I can't stop thinking about you.
You're always in my mind;
you're in my heart;
you're in every fucking bit of me.
But I can't go there with you.
I can't do it.
Look at what happens to people around me.
It's not good.
I'm not good for you.
- That's not true.
Listen, believe me,
if I could live this life again,
I would never leave you for a second.
But you belong with your family,
and I belong here,
and there's nothing we can do about it.
Because whichever way you look at it,
somebody gets hurt.
One, two, three.
Oh.
- Oops.
Oh!
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Sarah
Happy birthday to you.
Thank you.
Thank you, baby.
Oh, that was lovely.
Lovely playing, lovely cake.
My playing
was lovelier than his cake.
Mom.
They were both exactly
as lovely as each other.
I think you better blow the candles out
before the cake catches fire.
Wait until they do you
a candle for each decade, dear.
Then you'll know you're past it.
Didn't forget to make a wish.
Got it.
Oh!
Mom, when are we going to open the presents?
Now.
Many of you know her from her work
with the Elliott Hauser Foundation
for the International Promotion
of Human Rights.
In more recent years however,
she has become an active
lobbyist at Whitehall
on issues of asylum
and refugee protection.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it gives me great pleasure
to introduce our new spokesperson
for the UNHCR in the United Kingdom,
Mrs. Sarah Bauford.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I feel very nervous to be
standing in front of you today.
I also feel very honored.
In particular, because
UNHCR was the organization
to which I was first introduced
by my friend Elliott Hauser.
I know that my being offered this post
would have given him enormous pleasure.
Over 50 million people
are refugees or displaced
persons in the world today.
And because of closed minds
and funding shortfalls,
we are only able to reach
half of those in need.
So we rely on our partners,
the network of aid groups
blazing a trail across crises,
like El Salvador, Angola,
Chechnya, Sri Lanka...
those NGO's, the non-
governmental groups from OXFAM
right down to the smallest outfits
run by people like Elliott and...
...and I pray for those who survive him--
who continue his work--
without certainty or security--
wherever they may be in this world.
Excuse me.
Hey.
Thanks for coming.
Listen, I travel thousands of miles
to hear my sister give a speech,
I got a backache and jet lag.
What's a taxi ride to the park?
Sorry. Are they angry?
No. They don't care, Sarah.
I think they actually kind of enjoyed it.
"She's nuts" makes
for much better conversation
than "Nice speech."
I got a letter from Nick,
and I think he's in trouble.
Why? What did he say?
Nothing, really. Just little things.
Well, where is he?
He's in Chechnya.
He's running some sort of camp.
I'm really not sure.
I need to find him.
So, you have contacts.
You can find out where he is.
So, please?
Sarah, sweetheart, you know as well as I do
that Chechnya is a very dangerous place.
Yes, I can angle a story there, I'm sure.
If I find out anything,
I will let you know. Okay?
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Thank you.
Perhaps we are all refugees from something,
but I see now there is nothing to fear;
that the world we hold on to,
the lives we cherish,
are a part of something greater
--something more.
When I look at my children,
I see it so clearly--
that hope--
that chance of life--
and I know it's worth fighting for.
"The wedding was a splendid affair.
"Everyone attended--
"the dwarves, and the animals of the forest--
"and there were tears of joy
"and songs of happiness,
"and the prince and the princess
lived happily ever after."
How does it really end, Mummy?
What do you mean?
What do you think happens, honey?
She wakes up, looks at the prince,
and goes, "Eww! Boys. Yucky!"
Hello.
Hi, Henry. It's Charlotte. Is Sarah there?
Charlotte, hi.
Uh... well, she's upstairs
with the kids right now.
Can I take a message?
Oh. Okay. Um...
Then could you just, uh...
Just let her know that
I will call her later, okay?
Well, I can take a message.
Um... well, then, just tell her
that I've got some news, uh...
and that I will... I will fax it
to her office in the morning.
Okay?
Right. Okay.
Um... I'll pass that on.
Okay. Thanks, Henry. Bye, now.
Bye.
That was Charlotte.
She said, um... she has some news.
She'll fax you at the office.
So this is it, is it?
You kiss the children good-bye,
scribble a quick note, and then
sneak off into the night.
Have you any idea
how fucking cruel that is?
I'm not sneaking off.
I'm not leaving the children.
You could have talked to me.
I mean, writing a note-- it's, uh...
I just thought it would be easier.
Than what?
Than having this conversation again.
God, this is so...
I should be back by Friday.
Dinners are in the freezer.
Their swimsuits are in the dryer.
They have swimming tomorrow at 4:00.
It's all in the note.
I want this to be as easy
as possible for them.
And we'll talk about this.
We'll talk about everything when I get home.
Sniper!
Oh, God...
This is total carnage,
and not a single western leader
has said a thing
about what's going on here.
There's no threats, no criticism,
no fucking comment.
This place might as well not exist.
And now that we're all they have,
they want us to save face for them.
Well, fuck that. They should
get off their fucking asses
and get the fuck out here. Shit.
Sorry. I'm still swearing.
Freeze it there.
Can we cut?
Okay.
Roll tape.
Basically, nothing has changed.
People keep saying that
everything has changed.
Not from where I'm standing.
Chechnya, Somalia, Cambodia,
Ethiopia-- it's the same shit every time,
and it's just going to go on
and on until we stop pretending
that our loyalty ends with the asshole...
You okay?
What do you know?
An English news crew filmed it 6 days ago.
The sound man is dead,
the cameraman is in a coma,
and Nick has disappeared.
We think it's bandits--
Chechens looking for money--
but there's been no ransom demand.
Sarah, I want you to meet Bob Strauss.
He's with the ICRC here.
He's been helping us.
Hi.
No, sit. Sit, please.
So, the, um... net result right now
is we don't know who took Nick.
We don't know if he pissed off
the Russians or the Chechens.
We're pretty sure there was a motive.
What was he doing?
I think you know
he wasn't just a doctor anymore.
He, uh... I'd have to say--
and this is well known--
Nick's activities went quite a way
beyond what you'd call famine relief.
How do we find him?
Well, nobody I've spoken to
has any leads yet.
Can we offer a reward?
Can... can... can we do something?
The best thing for you to do is to stay
in the hotel for
a couple of days. Be patient.
No. No.
No.
Sarah.
Sarah, listen to me.
This place, they will take journalists,
Red Cross, anybody.
Don't think for one second
that you are immune.
I don't.
Just listen to what Strauss said.
I don't care what Strauss said.
Sarah, I love you.
I want you to be safe. Go home.
I swear to God, I will let you
know if we hear anything.
Say it.
What?
People disappear here;
they don't come back.
I'm not leaving until I find him.
Okay.
Charley?
Who is it?
Mrs. Bauford?
My name is Jan Steiger.
I'm a friend of Nick's.
May I?
We work together.
On and off.
You should move your bed.
It's too near the window.
Were you working together here?
Yes, in a manner of speaking.
How'd you know where I was?
My sister?
Oh, no, I'm not a journalist, Mrs. Bauford.
I'm more import/export.
Cambodia, we nearly met.
Actually,
Nick mentioned you a few times.
I most certainly would have.
What do you want?
What do you want, Mrs. Bauford?
I want to know where Nick is.
Last I heard,
he was being held in the mountains--
a rebel position,
about 5, 6 miles northeast of here.
Whole area's under heavy
Russian shelling now,
but I managed to make radio contact.
They were negotiating, they knew who he was.
But that was yesterday, been nothing since.
Chances are that he's dead.
So why are you telling me this?
I'm curious.
I mean, you come to this shit-hole in hell,
and you think you can find him?
What is it?
Is this... love?
Is that what it is?
Okay, whatever.
You're here.
Now...
if I get him back alive.
I'll lose one less operative.
If he's dead, he's dead.
Of course I'm not stupid enough
to risk my own ass
for some fucked-up big mouth.
But you, you're willing
to risk your life for love.
I'll trade with anything, Mrs. Bauford.
Anything at all.
Fine.
What do I do?
I have a friend, a local.
He can get you into the mountains,
but after that, I'm just a spectator.
Love.
I'm looking for Nick Callahan,
the English doctor.
Come.
Five minutes.
Nick?
Nick, it's Sarah.
I'm going to get you out of here.
We're going to get out of here right now.
There's a Red Cross camp on the border.
It's about 4 miles west of here.
We can walk it.
Damn it!
Come on, get up. Get up!
Nick, get up!
Nick? Remember?
Remember I wrote to you?
And I told you
you have a daughter.
Anna. You remember?
You're a dad.
And she needs you.
She needs you to get up
and walk out of here.
So get up.
Get up, Nick.
That was close.
What?
We need a lot of money to do...
It won't be hard to track us.
I can't make it-- go!
- You can...
Go, you've got to go. Listen to me.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
They're not going to kill me.
They need me alive.
I'm worth money to them.
If they get you,
they will rape you, they will kill you.
Y-You've got to go and get help.
Okay. Okay.
Sarah!
Sarah, go!
Go! You can make it.
Go!
What are you...
What are you doing?!
For God's...
Sarah, please!
Stay. Stay.
Go!
I hope when you're reading this letter,
that I'm sitting there next to you
and you're telling me
that I'm stupid for writing it,
and crazy for trying to find you.
But how could I not?
It's you.
All this time, so many years apart...
I've missed you,
but I have never been without you.
I've woken up with you every morning
and gone to sleep with you every night.
You have always been with me.
Your courage, your smile...
your damn stubbornness.
There has never been
any distance between us,
and there never will be.
I love you, Nick.
I love you.