There's something I wanna tell you.
After I got shot...
...you wanna know the very first thing
that entered my mind...
...before I blacked out?
Coins.
I'm 8 years old again
on a tour of the U.S. Mint.
I'm listening to a guide explain
how coins are made.
How they're punched
out of sheet metal.
How they're rimmed and beveled.
How they are stamped and cleaned.
And how each and every batch
of coins are personally examined.
Just in case any have slipped through
with the slightest imperfection.
That's what popped into my head.
I am a coin
in the United states Army.
I was minted in the year 1 980.
I've been punched from sheet metal.
I've been stamped and cleaned.
My ridges have been rimmed
and beveled.
But now l have
two small holes in me.
I'm no longer in perfect condition.
So there's something else
I wanna tell you.
Right before
everything went black...
...you wanna know the
very last thing that entered my mind?
You.
Why not? Because there are
a lot of things you'd be doing.
Just like playing tennis.
Wimbledon? I don't know.
Just gonna go.
I'm gonna host the thing. Six-thirty.
And you and I could go at 10?
- Oh, shit!
- Oh, no!
- Oh, no, Randy, no!
- I'm sorry.
I'll get it, I'll get it,
I'm on it. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Okay? I'm on it.
My whole life is in that bag.
I got it. I got it.
You got it.
Dude. I was gonna get that.
I mean, thanks for jumping in.
Yeah, no problem.
But I mean, hey, I'll take it.
Thank you so much!
Who jumps off a 20-foot pier?
Gosh, I'm a mess.
You are a lifesaver. I'm Savannah.
- John.
Brave man. This is my life in here,
so I owe.. I owe you.
Don't worry about it.
- Nice to meet you.
You all have a good night.
Yeah, thanks.
I was in the water for that.
I was seriously getting it for you.
This guy's crazy.
Yeah, no, I swear I'm not. I'm not
stalking you. I just gotta get my board.
- Are you staying here?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm from around here.
Hey, John, do you want to--?
My house is right over there.
We were actually going back
right now. Do you want to join us?
We're having a barbecue.
It's okay. I don't want to intrude
on y'all. My dad's making dinner.
Okay.
Well, I could at least give you
a beer for the walk home.
- Where is it?
- Right over there.
- You in the military or something?
- Yeah.
Really?
What branch are you in?
Army, Special Forces.
Oh, Special Forces.
That's impressive. That's....
Is that like a Special Forces ring they
give you? ls that what it says on it?
It looks nice on you.
Aren't you supposed to be wearing
a hat too? Like a French hat, a beret.
- That's what it's called?
- Randy.
I'm just joking with him.
You shouldn't make fun of a guy
who can kill you with his bare hands.
Big guy.
Rock them, sock them, let's go.
How about that?
You know, I'm gonna go get a beer.
Soldier. Pleasure.
I'm sorry about him.
He thinks he likes me.
Yeah, I think he likes you too.
No, I'm not his type.
He just doesn't know it yet.
What?
Come on, I just think
you're probably everybody's type.
See what I mean?
Is this who I think it is? Alan, Alan.
Hey, buddy, I want you to meet John.
John, this is Alan.
- Alan, nice to meet you.
- Say hi.
He's a little bit shy, isn't he?
Hey, where's your dad?
- Over there.
- Two steps behind, as usual.
Sorry, he's like a heat-seeking missile
every time he sees you.
- Oh, hey, I'm Tim.
- John.
Sorry.
Nice to meet you.
Oh, you Special Forces, huh?
Yes, sir.
You stationed out at Fort Bragg?
No, Germany, actually.
- Oh, you're on leave.
- Yes, sir.
I hope you're enjoying yourself.
Yeah, I think I am.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
It's nice to meet you though.
- Nice to meet you too.
- Come on, son. Let's go.
Let's go.
Hello. Hello, John.
Hello, Alan.
- Wow, that was really amazing.
- Yeah?
He never talks to anybody.
Only his family.
He talked to you.
Yeah, but I'm practically his family.
I've known him since he was born.
Yeah?
When do you go back?
Two weeks.
It must be scary what you do.
Boring mostly.
You know, long stretches of boring.
Occasional flashes of scary.
Full moon tonight.
Do you ever notice how big
the moon is when it's rising?
And how little it gets
when it's up in the sky.
You know,
that's just your perspective.
It doesn't matter where it is
in the sky or where you are...
...if you hold your hand up
and close one of your eyes...
...it's never bigger than your thumb.
Where'd you learn that?
I don't know.
Somewhere.
You just made your own fire.
That's very impressive.
Very primal.
But you're still not gonna
be able to cook that hot-dog, I fear.
I fear that as well.
I should probably
be getting going anyways.
I'm sorry. I hope you don't get into
too much trouble.
I think it's probably too late for that.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah. No, you're welcome.
Would you wanna maybe
do this again tomorrow night?
Tomorrow is chicken.
I don't think you're gonna wanna try it.
I was kind of hoping maybe we'd let
somebody else do the cooking.
Type of thing.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
So maybe I'll come by around
6 or something?
- Okay.
- All right.
So I'll see you soon, then?
I'll see you soon, then.
Yeah. Soon.
- Hey.
- Hey, man.
We're headed into town
for some ice cream. You want a ride?
No, no, no, it's fine.
I don't mind walking at all. It's fine.
Sure?
- All right. I appreciate it.
- Yeah.
Hey, Alan, move on over here.
Here, I'll undo your belt.
Five, six, seven, eight...
- So how long are you in town for?
- ...nine.
We live here year-round now.
Yeah, we were driving down
every weekend anyways...
...so I finally just convinced my wife
this just made the most sense.
- She didn't want ice cream?
- Who?
Oh, my wife. No.
No, actually
she's on vacation herself.
White sheep, white sheep,
white sheep.
- It's difficult to take trips together.
- White sheep.
It's fine. We make it work.
I'm up here on the left.
Hey, John.
For the record,
if you do anything to hurt Savannah...
...I'm gonna
have to break something.
Something in your leg.
Some.. One of the bones in there.
Okay.
It's just I know her father and he would
expect me to say something like that.
It'd just sound a lot more natural
coming out of his mouth.
It sounded fine.
- No, it..
- Yes, it did.
- No, it didn't.
- It did. It really did.
It didn't. But thank you.
- It really did.
- You think so?
Yeah, it did.
Okay.
Hey, don't honk the horn,
it's nighttime.
- Good night, John.
- Good night, Tim.
- Thanks for the ride.
- Yeah, no problem.
Hey, Dad, I'm not gonna be able
to stay for dinner.
Well, I made lasagna.
I know you made lasagna.
It's Sunday.
Can I borrow the car?
Thanks.
- Best seafood you'll ever have.
- Yeah, I know.
- I used to come here all the time.
- Really?
Are you sure you don't wanna go
somewhere, I don't know, nice?
Nice? No, I wanna go
somewhere good.
Okay.
What the hell you doing here?
Come on, Steve.
It's been three years already.
I don't want any trouble here.
You're not gonna get any. I promise.
All right.
Thank you.
What happened
with that guy out there?
- What guy?
- What's the story with him?
- No story.
- Really?
Yeah.
He's an old buddy of mine.
What?
Your dad get mad at you
for coming home late last night?
No. He's not really the type
that gets mad.
What kind of guy is he then?
Quiet one?
- Could be worse, I guess.
- I guess.
And your mom?
Nope, just me and my dad.
Did he raise you all by himself?
Yeah.
Why do you wanna know
about my dad?
Just curious.
Curious about
where you come from.
I wanna meet your dad.
Tonight.
Look, you're-- You're not
gonna get very much out of him.
So, I don't know,
just don't take it personally, okay?
Hey, Pop.
I got somebody I want you to meet.
Hey.
- This is Savannah.
- Hi.
It's nice to meet you, Mr. Tyree.
He.. This is my.. He collects coins.
He.. It's kind of like his big hobby.
This is amazing.
You have so many coins.
How did you get started in all this?
Through John, actually.
Not his thing anymore.
- Hey, we should probably maybe go.
- What is this coin?
That's a Sacagawean mule.
It's actually....
- Do you want to see some more?
- Absolutely, yes, if you don't mind.
- Put this glove on then.
- Thanks.
This is a humorous one.
This is a satirical coin.
This is massive.
Yeah, William Jennings Bryan,
when he ran for president...
...he was.. He believed in..
No, don't turn it over.
Leave it here.
Do you remember that he had
the free silver policy. You remember.
And McKinley was his opponent
and he's.. Wait, here.
Now see, that's a real silver dollar.
That's the size of a silver dollar.
And McKinley said that if
Bryan had his way...
...then the silver dollars
would be that big. Yeah.
- That's amazing.
- Can you imagine...
...walking around with that
in your pocket?
- That's really funny.
- That's humorous.
Now, these..
Pop, we can't do this right now.
We can't be here all night.
I have.. I have some to show you.
This is fascinating.
These are all matched in color.
I had fun tonight.
I like your dad.
You shouldn't be too hard on him.
He loves you.
I can tell even if you can't.
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
Wait, Savannah. I mean....
So I guess I'll see you soon, then?
I'll see you soon, then.
Where you been all day?
- I've been busy.
- You're on spring break.
You're supposed to be
lounging on the beach all day.
You're not supposed to be busy
doing things.
I want to show you something.
The family that lived here, their home
was damaged by the hurricane.
- What, so now you're rebuilding it?
- Yup. Well, not just me.
You're starting to make me
a little nervous.
Why am I
starting to make you nervous?
Because I'm starting to think you
might be too good of a person for me.
No, I'm not that good of a person.
You're sneaking off every day to do
manual labor on a house for charity.
- On your spring break.
- Yeah, you're right.
It's selfish, really,
me being this generous.
- You don't drink, you don't smoke.
- Nope. Nope.
- You probably don't sleep around.
- Absolutely not.
Okay, look, you gotta have a fault.
- I do.
- Okay, care to enlighten me?
I curse.
- No.
- I do.
- No, you don't.
- I haven't heard you.
- Well, that's because it's in my mind.
There's a never-ending stream
of curse words...
...that I'm thinking at all times.
Okay, fine, just say one then.
No, I can't tell you because it's filthy.
- Right.
- Yeah.
Okay, all right. Fair enough.
No, I have faults, John.
Trust me, I have plenty of them.
You'll see.
I hope so.
We have to be finished
with this in three weeks.
Hope that actually happens.
These are to be the bedrooms,
parents' room...
...the boys' rooms,
two boys, 7 and 9.
Living room and the bathroom.
And then this is the kitchen.
This is the best room because
the mom's a really good cook.
We're gonna make it really beautiful
with white tile floors and tiles...
...on the counter tops
and there's gonna be a roof.
- Here, John, come here.
- A roof would definitely be good.
It's gonna be like this,
but it's gonna be everywhere.
It's the only cover we have.
Nice, we're gonna be here
for a while.
Where'd you get your scar?
That one?
A knife fight.
It was five years ago, we were really
drunk and the guy went for my eye.
That's terrible.
Why? He missed.
The way people act around you, the
way they treated you at that restaurant.
- It's like they're scared of you.
- They're not scared of me.
They might be scared
of who I used to be.
And who is that?
Somebody different?
So when did you change?
When you went into the Army?
Yeah. Yeah, I mean, partly yeah.
And the other part?
I don't know,
I'm still working on that.
So you used to be tough.
And maybe you still are a little bit.
- You don't scare me, John.
- No?
Well, you scare me.
Don't worry about him.
John!
What, you think you're safe
in there? Okay.
No!
It's all right.
Everybody understands.
What are you doing over here?
You're missing the party.
The party's just managing fine
without me.
What's wrong?
Why are you all the way
over here by yourself?
I'm dying, John.
What?
That's not even funny.
I'm gonna miss you.
It's almost over.
No, it's not almost over.
Yes, it is.
I leave tomorrow.
I have to go back to school.
- So?
- And you.
No, and me nothing.
My commitment's up in 12 months.
And then I'm back. For good.
A lot could happen
in 12 months, John.
You don't think I know that?
I know that.
And I'm not afraid at all.
I promise you...
...that it'll all be over
sooner than you think.
Then I'll be back for good.
You promise?
I promise.
I'm probably gonna be out of the Army
way before you're out of school.
Am I gonna be in the audience
when you graduate?
I think I might take
a little longer to graduate.
Been spending so much time
around your dad...
...and I think now
I want to teach special education.
- You don't say.
- I don't know why it's taken me...
...so long to realize. I mean,
I've lived next to Alan my whole life..
I'm sorry, back up. What does
that have to do with my dad?
Well, there's....
I mean, there's an explanation
for why he is the way he is.
Forget it. Never mind.
- No, no, no.
- No, let's go. Come here.
What?
So, just, what were you saying?
I grew up next to a kid with autism.
- I have a frame of reference.
- Whoa, autistic?
You saying my dad's like Alan?
You're saying my dad's retarded?
No, Alan's not retarded, John.
He's autistic.
There are milder forms of it
and these things go undiagnosed.
Is this what you've been doing?
You've just been studying my dad?
No. How could you even say that?
I've lived with my dad my entire life.
Put up with him my entire life.
You think I don't know
that he's not normal?
Yeah?
You think I need you to tell me
he's not normal?
Yeah.
Hey, soldier, leaving so soon, huh?
Here, have a beer. It's on me.
Come on, you should drink.
It'll make you feel better.
- Now's not a good time, all right?
- You sad?
No, come on. You just need to relax.
Come on. Just relax a little bit.
What's going on with Savannah?
- Just leave me alone.
- What's with Savannah?
- How about you get your hands off?
- Come on.
What is happening
with you and Savannah--?
Hey, man, what are you doing?
John!
Oh, my.. Oh, my God!
- John!
- Stop him. What is he doing?
- Help him!
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
I don't think she's home now.
But she hasn't
gone back to school yet.
She normally comes by and says
goodbye before she heads back, but....
Oh, shit, Tim.
Jesus, I'm sorry, man.
Hey, I like it.
I think it makes me look
pretty tough.
I just.. I had no idea
it was you back there.
Hey, it was my fault.
I don't know what I was thinking,
sneaking up behind a green beret.
Hey, if you see her...
...can you give her a message
for me?
Yeah.
Just tell her I came by...
...and that I....
You wanna write it down?
Yeah.
I'll make sure she gets it.
Thank you.
Hey, Pop.
I didn't know if anyone
else was coming so...
...I made double.
No, I'll do it.
- I got it, Dad. Lt's okay. I got it.
- No, I'll do it.
- They're clean.
- I'll do it. I'll do it.
Okay.
Looks like you're gonna have
leftovers for once.
Oh, I'll have it next Sunday.
Excuse me, Pop.
Got your note.
- Short, sweet, to the point.
- I'm sorry.
John, I'm sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to make you feel that.
I have no idea what I'm talking about.
No business pretending I'm a doctor.
- I was watching him today.
- John.
Please, I'm serious. I don't know
what I'm talking about.
I really don't. It means nothing.
Okay?
I'm headed back to school.
And I just wanted
to make sure that, you know....
Make sure that what?
I made you a promise, didn't I?
Yeah.
You wrote your first note
so I wrote mine.
Don't read it now. Wait till I'm gone.
Okay.
- Hey, can you..? You hungry?
- Yes.
Yeah? My dad made
a little extra for you.
You know, it's Sunday.
Okay.
- I can only stay a little while.
- I know.
Come on.
Dear John...
...two weeks together...
...that's all it took.
Two weeks for me
to fall in love with you.
Now we have one year apart.
But what's one year apart
after two weeks like that together?
- All right, Pop.
- Okay.
I gotta go.
- You be good, okay?
- Okay.
So....
- We're good. All right. See you later.
- Okay.
You made me a promise.
A promise I know you'll keep.
So I only want one more promise from
you during this time we spend apart.
Tell me everything.
Write it all down, John.
Scribble it in a notebook.
Type it out, e-mail it to me...
...I don't care,
but I wanna know everything.
Then we'll be with each other all the
time even if we're not with each other.
That way before we know it,
I'll see you soon, then.
- What's up, girls?
- Johnny!
What up, man?
- Hey, there he is.
- Look who it is.
- Welcome back, John.
- Look at you.
Welcome back.
Take a look at your voucher.
All right.
How was Atlantic City, man?
No, laugh it up. That's great.
Yeah. That's the one thing I ask him.
I didn't say.
First time I've seen him.
- Wouldn't ask if you didn't know.
- How could he know?
Don't even bother unpacking, guys.
We move out bright and early.
Enjoy.
Well, I'm excited.
Dear Savannah, L promise.
I promise I'll see you soon, then.
I promise I'll write all the time.
I promise I'll tell you everything.
Be patient with me, it may take a while
for these Letters to get back to you.
We've already been deployed
out on a mission.
Come on, soldier, move it, move it.
Let's go!
The problem is we can't exactly
use the local postal system here.
And there's no such thing
as Internet connection.
So I have to send everything
from here out by airmail.
- Can you get this out for me?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Don't lose it, all right?
- Yeah, I gotcha.
Unfortunately, I'm not allowed to say
exactly where here is.
All I can tell you is
where we've been sent...
...makes me miss America
very much.
And the lack of anything resembling
an ocean makes me miss Charleston.
And everything around me
makes me miss you.
We move around a Lot. so letters
tend to come late and out of order.
We may want to number
our letters...
...just so we know which order
we wrote them in.
But when they do finally get here...
...it's a good day.
- Whenever they don't...
- All right, let's see here.
Not for me. Not for me.
Not for me. And not for me.
Figures.
- ...it's not.
- Nothing for you either.
But I know they'll still come.
I know it.
That's right.
Letter Number 8.
Dear John, I'm back at my
parents' farm for the weekend.
And they have some house guests
you may know.
Savannah!
I think that horse suits you just fine.
I took Alan out riding with me today.
It was his first time on a horse.
You look good on that horse, Alan.
You've heard of horse sense, horses
are somehow able to sense danger?
Sense out evil?
Well, I think autistic kids
have that too...
...so I had this idea.
This dream.
I wanna open up
a summer camp for autistic kids.
I've never seen him
act like this before.
Are you hungry?
Where they can ride horses
as much as they want.
Are you hungry?
For once in their life, a place where
they won't have to worry about a thing.
What do you think?
Pipe dream, huh?
No, it's not a pipe dream.
It's a perfect dream.
Erget. Merry Christmas.
John, to a Mr. John Tyree.
- Shut up, man.
- Seven?
- Stop moving around.
- Can I keep this one?
Letter Number 33.
Dear Savannah, the good news is
we've been sent somewhere new.
Although I can't tell you
where that is either.
The bad news is, this place actually
makes me miss the old place.
But it's a full moon here tonight,
which makes me think of you.
Because I know that no matter what
I'm doing, no matter where I am...
...this moon will always be
the same size as yours.
Half a world away.
Dear John...
...most nights I fall asleep
worrying about you.
Wondering where
you may be out there.
Not tonight.
Tonight you're here with me.
I visited your dad yesterday.
Summer's almost over and I wanted to
see him before I went back to school.
I hope that's okay.
Hey.
I made you a pie.
He made me dinner.
It was Sunday so we had lasagna.
And I got him talking about his coins.
So we had plenty of conversation.
This one is kind of a cull,
a coin that's in really bad shape.
- Worthless to most collectors.
- But not to you.
No, not to me.
What is your favorite coin?
Out of all the coins that you have,
what is your absolute favorite coin?
Do you have one?
'Seventy-eight Jefferson mule.
That'd be my favorite.
Definitely.
Why? Is it worth the most?
Well, it's worth a lot, not the most.
But, you know....
What's the story behind it?
Here's one....
So I'll ask you instead, John,
wherever you may be.
Dear Savannah, only because
I promised to tell you everything.
Thank you.
When I was 7 years old,
I bought an ice cream cone.
On the way home, I noticed one of
the pennies wasn't actually a penny.
I don't know.
Never seen anything like it.
Did you find this, son?
Yeah?
No, it's a mule.
- It's a what?
- A mule. An error coin.
Every now and then
they make mistakes...
...batch accidentally slips through,
this thing...
...head's a nickel, tail's a penny. Mule.
Really more of a novelty than anything.
Remember the horse sense
you were talking about?
..the kid found it
I will buy it anyway.
Twenty bucks.
- No, thank you.
- Well, my dad has it too.
Now, wait a minute. Hang on.
Let me take another look
at that real quick.
John, let's go.
I'll be damned.
- Do you know what this is?
- No.
Look at that.
That's your coin.
You want my advice?
Dad to Dad?
Keep it.
Hold on to it.
Pass it down to your son.
Let him pass it to his son
and on and on, I'll tell you what...
...30, 40, a hundred years
from now...
...you're gonna have something
worth a whole lot more than $4000.
I promise you.
Hey.
Do you want to keep it?
- Good for you.
- Thank you. Thank you.
At first I Loved chasing after
those mules with my father.
We finally had something
to talk about.
You know, something
we could do together.
But he became obsessed with them.
You know how he is.
And then I became a teenager
and you know how I am.
All the way up to Wooster
for another coin show. I'm just..
No, I'm not doing that.
You're going to one
every weekend now.
Oh, that's good.
I love warm milk. That's nice.
You spend all of our money on coins.
Get a fricking fridge that works.
Eventually he stopped talking
about coins with me altogether.
And when that happened...
...we found there wasn't all that much
left to talk about.
So that's the story.
I miss you so much it hurts.
Sorry, sorry.
Oh, my God.
My brother was in the towers.
- I love you too, babe.
- Please call me as soon as you can.
- Susan. Susan, is my dad there?
- Just calm down.
All right, fellas, here's the deal.
Requesting permission
to extend my tour, sir.
to extend, sir.
Requesting permission
to extend as well, sir.
to extend, sir.
Requesting permission
to extend as well, sir.
Okay, guys, listen. We're gonna get
our orders from Operations on Monday.
Before we do anything rash, let's take
the weekend to mull this over, all right?
I got a wife and kids to think about.
Nobody's asking you
to stay on too, captain.
Yeah, you are. This is my team.
Where you go, I go.
Where we go, we all go.
If everyone still wants to extend
on Monday, then we'll do it.
Together.
Don't get into trouble over there.
- Take care of yourself.
- Always.
Let's go, man.
The plane to Paris leaves in an hour.
You ready? Are you ready?
- It's gonna be amazing.
- I can't go.
What? Of course you're going.
I gotta go to Charleston.
- You're going to Charleston?
- Yup.
What are you, nuts?
We got two days off, man.
By the time you fly there and back,
you're gonna have like 18 hours.
It's 18 more than I had this morning.
I don't know when
I'll get that again...
...so I gotta go.
Nothing I can say
to change your mind?
Nope.
John!
John. John.
You sure he--? He actually said that?
He wants to come?
I think he will.
- He wasn't so sure about it, but....
- Yeah, I'll bet he wasn't.
..has asked President Bush
to activate...
...thousands of military reservists.
Hey, Pop!
Hey, what are you doing in here?
Look at you.
Spiffy.
Are you coming with us?
Please. My parents are so excited
to meet you, Mr. Tyree.
Yeah.
You hungry?
I made meatloaf.
I know you made meatloaf, Pop.
It's Saturday.
We can take it with us.
You mind if we take it with us?
Well, I don't....
Is that okay? I'll wrap it up.
I don't mean.. I'm sorry, but could..?
Could you stop the car,
because I need to go back.
- Should I turn around?
- Stop the car, please. Stop the car.
- Forget something?
- Okay.
No, I need to get out
of the car. Please.
- All right, just.. Just relax, okay?
- Yeah.
I don't think I can do this.
- Look, you're fine. You're fine.
- No, I just.. Please. I need to get out.
You're okay, Pop. It's fine.
- Look, stop the car, I can't..
- Okay, I'll turn around.
We're fine, we're fine, we're fine.
- I gotta get out. Stop the car.
- Okay, all right.
- Come on, Dad, stop!
- Okay.
Pop. Come on, don't do that.
Hey, Mr. Tyree.
Hey, you all right?
- You okay?
- I'm sorry.
It's okay.
But hey, let's....
We're gonna wait for you
in the car, all right?
- No, I'm fine, I'm fine.
- No, don't, honestly,
We can stay. Let's just stay.
Okay? Let's stay,
because I can go next year.
Pop, I only got one night.
I mean, I gotta go back.
Do you understand that?
You should go. You both should go.
New York Mayor RudoIph Giuliani said
Wall street will re-open on Monday.
He tried. At least he tried.
Hello, welcome.
My girl.
Mom, this is John.
John, I feel like I already know you.
Where's your father, did he come too?
- No, ma'am.
- Oh, that's okay.
I'm just glad
that you made it home safe.
We thought about canceling
with everything that's going on...
...but we felt like
everybody should be together.
I've been briefing him in the car
and I think he's good.
It was good Intel. With solid tactical
training, I'm as ready as I'll ever be.
I love him already.
Mrs. Curtis, Savannah.
- Hey, dude, how's it going?
- John.
It's good to see you again.
All right, You know what?
You look like you could use a drink.
- I'll grab one for you.
- Yes, thank you.
- John.
- What's he doing here?
He's here because I invited him.
His family lives just up the street.
What are you, like,
hanging out now?
He's really not that bad once you get
to know him, I swear to you, John.
Here you go.
It's bourbon, it's not gonna kill you.
Be right back.
We got off on the wrong foot and I want
to apologize for the way I treated you.
If I had known that Savannah
was actually gonna stay with you...
...I wouldn't have treated you that way.
In all seriousness, I'm sorry.
Fair enough.
If you need anything and....
- Enjoy yourself.
- Right.
So this is him.
Yup. No tough-guy routine
from you, Dad.
Routine?
I bench press refrigerators, honey.
Your boyfriends
need to know these things.
He's absolutely right.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Curtis.
But l think Tim here might have
already beat you to the punch.
He said he'd rough me up
if ever I hurt her.
I was very convincing too.
I think I made quite an impact.
Well, cheers, son.
Glad you could join us.
Thank you, sir.
- Billy! You actually showed up!
- See, hard part's over.
- Good to see you again, John.
- How you doing, Tim?
Hi. Hey, Tim, how are you doing?
- Good.
- I haven't seen your wife. Is she here?
Yeah, she's on vacation actually.
- So I'll tell her you said hello.
- Please do.
I will.
Alan, remember
what we talked about?
Another vacation?
Yeah.
Alan ever ask about her?
Yeah, he does.
I just don't know what to say.
Hey, look, I'm not a father.
You know, I'm really in no position
to give you advice at all.
When I was a kid,
I waited around every day...
...hoping that today
would finally be the day...
...that my mom would come home.
I waited around 15 years.
So I know how painful
it might have been for my dad to...
...just tell me the truth.
It would have saved me
a lot of waiting around.
You know?
Well, I guess if the worst thing
you can say about your father...
...is he tried to protect you
too much then...
...that's a pretty good father, isn't it?
I'm sorry.
You're John, right? Savannah's John?
- Yes, sir.
- I wanna thank you for what you do.
Know our prayers are with you.
I hope whatever happens...
...it'll be over soon. So you boys
can come home safe and sound.
Oh, it won't be over anytime soon.
Afghanistan will just be the first stop
of many.
He's right, you know. Pretty soon they'll
ask y'all to reenlist for another tour.
Slowly but surely they'll
stop asking and start telling.
None of the soldiers I know
need to be asked, sir.
And we sure don't need to be told.
What do you mean by we?
It was great to see you guys.
See you next year.
Savannah....
So you're gonna reenlist,
just like that?
It's something we should talk about.
Two more years, John.
Have you already done it?
Have you already re-upped?
No.
But you decided
that you're going to?
Do I have a say?
Do I have a say in this?
- You don't understand.
- Don't ever tell me I don't understand.
Leave me alone, John.
Please.
What do you...?
What do you want from me?
Savannah, I mean....
Just tell me what you want from me.
I mean, you want me to quit?
Is that it?
Look, I don't know how we got here.
I don't know what happened.
Just woke up and...
...there's buildings falling and....
I mean, I had a plan..
I had a plan, but now I don't.
And I have no idea what to do.
I don't know what to do and l just--
All I know is I wanna stay here.
I just wanna stay right here with you
as long as I possibly can.
You're just all that matters, okay?
You're all that matters to me.
I'm trying to figure out what
the right thing is and I don't know.
I don't have any idea how to get there.
I just-- Because I need you to tell me.
I just need you to tell me, okay?
Can you just tell me, please--?
Just tell me what you want me to do.
I want you to come with me.
Hey, Pop.
Thank you. Thank you for coming.
Well....
So you think you're gonna be
okay by yourself this time?
Yeah, why wouldn't I be?
I should probably be getting going.
Take care of yourself.
So are we...?
I mean, we're okay though.
Right? Nothing has changed?
Be careful not to step
in any fires, okay?
Okay. I will.
So I'll see you soon, then.
I'll see you soon, then.
Welcome back, guys.
Hope you had a good weekend.
Wish it could've been longer...
...but sometimes you got
to take what you can get.
So that's it then?
It's unanimous?
Okay.
I'll start the paperwork.
Thank you, sir.
O'Neill, here you go!
This smells pretty good, Russ.
And we got Daniels. Where's he at?
Move, move, move, up and shoot!
- Hey, yo.
- Yeah, nothing today, man. Sorry.
Go, go, go.
Yo, you guys seen John?
Is he back here?
Yo, John.
Got one for you, dude.
- Yeah?
- That's it, though.
Dear John, I know it's been
way too long since I last wrote you.
I've been staring at this blank page
for the last two hours.
Well, if I'm being honest...
...I've been staring at it
for the last two months.
Please forgive me
for what I'm about to say.
And know that this is
the hardest thing I've ever had to do.
My life without you has no meaning.
And I cannot Live.... I'm sorry.
Yo, listen to this, hedge fund manager
on Wall Street, right?
How much do you think he made
at his regular job?
Twenty-seven million dollars, he ran
a hedge fund. Works on Wall Street.
That is amazing.
You making mud pies, buddy?
What's going on, man?
You wanna talk about it?
Nothing to talk about.
She found somebody else.
You got any idea who it is?
No, she didn't say.
I mean, I got a pretty good idea.
Look, man...
...you know, this happens, dude.
I mean, you'll get her back.
You get home, she comes running.
- It's the whole cycle, dude.
- They already got engaged.
Jesus.
Hey, I'm sorry, man.
Let me know if I can do anything,
all right?
..off the bottom rim. You wouldn't think
a squirrel could swim, but I swear...
...swam 20 yards to the shoreline.
- Swimming squirrel.
- That's crazy, dude.
Hey, notice that. Did y'all see that?
I mean, that's as sexy as it gets
around here.
They can't show their legs,
so they got fishnets on their faces.
I'm gonna bring that back to the States
and make my girl wear that.
How mysterious.
Back up, back up!
- What's he saying?
- Hey, he's speaking Turkish.
- What is he saying, though?
- I don't know. I don't know.
Come on, specialist, figure it out!
Look, man, I speak Pashtu,
I speak Farsi, I speak all kinds of shit.
What languages you speak?
Come here.
- Good work, man.
- Stay right there.
- Hey, where are you going?
- Somebody's gotta figure it out.
- Noodles, go with him.
- Yeah.
Back up, back up.
Tyree!
Wait for further instructions.
Let's move out.
- Good?
- Yeah, you?
We got a man down! Noodles, you
gonna be all right, man! Hold on, man!
Copy that, man down! Man down!
- Come here.
- You see it?
I got you. Get your hands up!
Tyree, do you read?
Talk to me, Tyree.
Lucky SOB. It hit your plate.
Jesus, l never loved a piece of clothing
more in my entire life, I swear to God.
John!
Man down! Medic!
Medic! John.
Come on, man.
Medic!
Look, come on, you're gonna
be fine, all right? It's nothing.
It's nothing. You got this.
Stay awake, okay? You just look
in my eyes, just look in my eyes!
Keep your eyes open, okay?
Eyes, awake, awake,
right at me, okay?
Jakes!
Welcome back, Sergeant Tyree.
Rest easy, okay?
You're in the hospital in Germany.
And you're gonna be just fine.
Tyree.
- You look good, man.
- Thank you, sir.
I just wanted to come by
and let you know I'll be extending.
Extending.
Tyree, it's been three months.
I'm impressed, but I'm not stupid.
Go home, John. Get some R&R.
Keep your dad some company
for a while.
Have a seat.
Listen, I'm being transferred.
Now, this has nothing to do
with what happened.
My captain duties are done here.
Going back to Fort Bragg.
I actually miss my family.
That's good, sir.
Berry and Daniels are getting out, the
others, coming down on assignment.
- And you've got less than four months..
- I'm definitely extending.
Your war is over, John.
You served your country well.
You know what?
I might just make this a career.
No talking you out of this, huh?
Mark, on my mark!
Mark!
Where you thinking next?
Oh, man. I don't know,
wherever they send us.
Actually, we're sending you home
to the States, John.
I'm sorry, we just got the news.
He's conscious, but he's not lucid.
And he's hardly ever responsive.
It's hard for me to say
how severe the stroke really is...
...because we don't know how long
he was down before they found him.
If I'd have been there
to find him like that earlier...
...do you think it would've
made a difference?
I doubt it. I really doubt it.
- Hey, Jeff, here's that scan.
- No problem.
Hey, Pop.
What--? What the heck do you--?
Ma'am, why do you have him out here?
You okay? How you feeling?
I....
I mean, it's nothing, but I wrote you--
I wrote you a letter.
No, no, don't read it now.
You don't have to--
I didn't think you'd-- Why don't you
read it when I'm not around?
You know what? The hell with it.
I'll just read it to you.
"Dear Dad.
There's something
I've been wanting to tell you.
You remember a few years back...
...when I got shot.
Well, you wanna know
the very first thing...
...that entered my mind
at that moment?
Right before I blacked out?
Coins.
Suddenly I was 8 years old again.
I was on that tour of the U.S. Mint.
I was listening to the guide explain
how coins are made.
How they're punched out of sheet metal
and how they're rimmed and beveled.
How they're stamped and cleaned.
And how each and every batch
of coins are personally examined...
...in case any have slipped through
with the slightest imperfection.
Do you remember that, Dad?
I mean, do you remember that trip
to Philadelphia we took?
That's what popped into my head.
I'm a coin of the United States Army.
And I was minted in the year 1980.
I've been punched from sheet metal.
I've been stamped and cleaned.
And my edges have been
rimmed and beveled.
But now I have
two small holes in me.
So I'm no longer
in perfect condition."
How about it, Dad? You know,
we're just a couple of culls here, huh?
"But there's one--
There's one more thing...
...that l want to tell you too.
After l got shot, you know,
right before I blacked out.
You wanna know the very last thing
I thought of?"
I'm sorry.
The very last thing I thought of....
You wanna know the very last thing
I thought of?
I'm so sorry,
I don't want to rush you...
...but we have another service
coming in.
John.
What brings you home?
It's my dad.
How's your dad?
He....
I'm sorry.
I wish I had known.
It's okay.
It wouldn't have made
any difference.
I'm so sorry.
He's-- He was a really good man.
You finally did it, huh?
Camp Horse Sense.
No.
I didn't. I tried.
It only lasted one summer after we
took over this place from my parents.
It was.... It was expensive.
Do you want to come inside?
It's just me.
When do you have to go back?
As soon as I get my dad's stuff
squared away.
Have you settled down yet?
No.
But you must be dating a lot, huh?
No. I don't think you can call it
dating exactly.
It's so good to see you.
Here. Alive.
Hold on. I'm just gonna-- I'm sorry.
Hello?
Hey.
No, I'm fine.
I....
Well, John-- John is here.
Yeah, John Tyree.
Yeah, I'm gonna leave soon.
Okay, I'll see you.
I'll be there in like
20 minutes, okay?
I love you too. Bye.
He wants to see you.
Wait, what?
It's Tim?
Initially after he was diagnosed,
he was so optimistic.
He wasn't concerned,
all he cared about was Alan...
...which was inspiring.
It wasn't until after the cancer spread to
stage four that I noticed a big change.
What kind of cancer is it?
Lymphoma.
He's had it with being cooped up
in that room...
...so he basically just spends
all his time out here.
Sometimes with Alan.
- Can I have a crumble cake?
- Alan, do you remember John?
Hello, John.
Hey, Alan.
He's gotten big.
- How are you?
- Good.
I'm gonna get him a crumble cake.
Oh, that's a good idea.
He's been talking about that.
Come on, Alan.
I guess you must want to
kick my ass, huh?
There's not a lot I can
do about it here, is there?
It's all part of my master plan.
Hell of a plan.
I love her.
Everything that happened
in my life before, it's gone now.
It's been wiped clean.
I wanted to tell you that.
And I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for how it happened
with you so far away.
But l know now that Alan will always
have someone to take care of him.
He will always be in good hands.
She still loves you, you know.
Why is it black?
It's plain as day, you can see it
all over her face.
I wish that weren't the case...
...but she's never looked at me
the way she used to look at you.
You should know that.
Be careful, Alan.
He still loves those horses, huh?
Yeah, he'll be out there till bedtime.
I gotta get him out of that hospital.
He needs to come home.
There's a company in Texas
with an experimental drug.
That might help.
But the insurance companies
don't pay for it, of course.
My parents sold their beach house
a year ago.
Which was a godsend.
We've done a few fund raisers.
But l never would have guessed
that we would run out so fast.
Stay for dinner, okay?
So you drink now.
Just a glass or two at dinner.
Tim got me started
a couple years ago.
Why are you looking at me
like that?
What do you mean?
How am I looking at you?
Differently.
I don't know, how do you
want me to look at you?
You're different.
I don't know--
I don't know why I came here.
I mean, what are we doing?
We're sitting here
and we're eating and we're talking...
...but no one's
actually saying anything.
What do you want me to say?
What do you want to talk about?
Why didn't you call?
Why didn't you call me?
I mean, did I not deserve any more
explanation than...
...that letter?
You couldn't have called me?
You couldn't have given me some
sort of chance to change your mind?
Don't you think you owed me that?
I couldn't.
You couldn't?
You thought that little of me
that you couldn't have just called me.
Why?
Because I couldn't.
Give me an answer.
Why? Why not?
- Because I couldn't.
- An answer.
Because just hearing your voice,
I would have changed my mind.
Is that what you wanna hear, John?
What you came all this way to hear?
You think it was tough out there?
Think it was easy for me without you?
You thought that
every single day it wasn't...
...a goddamn marathon
of my life without you?
Tim was sick.
He was sick and he needed me.
He needed me to help him.
He needed me to help him
with Alan, with everything.
I was alone and I had no idea
what I was doing.
I didn't plan this. I didn't know
that it was gonna happen to me.
But it did.
You don't think I've tried--?
I picked up the phone
a thousand times to try to call you.
You think that I really wanna be
standing here in front of you like this?
I had no choice.
I know.
I saved every single one of them.
You've been so many places.
I think the yellow envelopes
are from Africa or something.
Really?
I even have your first,
your very first letter to me.
Tim's water bill.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Hope you have more
where that came from.
I'm gonna put a pot of coffee on.
I should go.
I'll see you soon, then?
Say it back.
When I say it, you say it.
Remember?
John?
Just say it.
Goodbye, Savannah.
I don't think you remember me. But I
believe you knew my father, Bill Tyree.
Oh, yeah, of course I did. I haven't
seen him in a while, though. How is he?
He recently passed.
I'm sorry.
I think you might've offered to buy his
coin collection one time. ls that right?
Sure did. More than once.
Just out of curiosity, how much do you
think a collection like his is worth?
A collection that big?
I don't know, I'd have to see it.
Look, I only got about one condition.
All the mules,
they gotta stay together.
You can sell them as a set
or keep them for yourself.
They have to stay together.
You're really going to sell me
all his coins?
Yes, sir.
All but one.
This comes up nickel, we're gonna
set up right here. We got shade.
It comes up penny, we'll be up
on the ridge. We got visibility.
- That'd be penny side.
- All right, let's go to the ridge.
Sergeant.
Thank you.
Dear John...
...it's been almost five years
since I wrote with an actual pen...
...on an actual sheet of paper.
I thought I could write and tell you...
...all that's happened
since I saw you last.
A few weeks
after you showed up here...
...Tim received
an anonymous donation.
A donation that was enough
to give him...
...what the insurance companies
wouldn't:
Time.
Time to finally come home.
Time to spend with his son.
Time to say goodbye.
The problem with time,
I've learned...
...whether it's those first two weeks
I got to spend with you...
...or those final two months
I got to spend with him...
...eventually time always runs out.
I have no idea where you are
out there in the world, John.
But I understand that I Lost the right
to know these things long ago.
No matter how many years go by...
...I know one thing
to be as true as it ever was.
I'll see you soon, then.