[Car Trunk Lid, Door Closing]
[Car Engine Starts]
[Sighs]
[Sighs, Groans]
[Groans]
[Exhales]
[Horn Blows]
[Man On P.A.]
Montauk train on track "B."
[Man]
Random thoughts
for Valentine's Day, 2004.
Today is a holiday invented
by greeting card companies...
[Man On P.A. Continues]
Last call...
to make people
feel like crap.
I ditched work today.
Took a train out to Montauk.
[Man On P.A.]
Montauk train boarding
on track "B."
I don't know why.
Aah!
I'm not an impulsive person.
[Panting]
I guess I just woke up
in a funk this morning.
I gotta get my car fixed.
Hi. Cindy?
It's Joel. Joel!
Listen, I don't
feel very well today.
No, food poisoning,
I think.
[Joel Continues]
It's goddamn freezing on this beach.
Montauk in February.
Brilliant, Joel.
Page is ripped out.
Don't remember doing that.
It appears this is
my first entry in two years.
Sand is overrated.
It's just tiny little rocks.
If only I could
meet someone new.
I guess my chances of that happening
are somewhat diminished,
seeing that I'm incapable
of making eye contact
with a woman I don't know.
Maybe I should
get back together with Naomi.
She was nice.
Nice is good.
She loved me.
[Woman Speaking, Faint]
[Chuckles Softly]
[Joel Continues]
Why do I fall in love
with every woman I see...
who shows me
the least bit of attention?
[Train Horn Blows]
Hi.
I'm sorry?
- I just said hi.
- Hi. Hello. Hi.
Okay if I sit closer?
How far are you going?
Uh, Rockville Center.
Get out! Me too!
Really?
What are the odds?
Do I know you?
Do you ever shop
at Barnes & Noble?
Sure. Sure.
That's it!
Yeah?
I've seen you, man!
Book slave there
for, like, five years now.
Ah. I would have thought
I would've remembered you.
Jesus! Is it five years?
It might be the hair.
What might?
It changes a lot.
The color.
That's why you might not
recognize me.
It's called Blue Ruin,
the color.
Right. Yeah.
Snappy name, huh?
I like it.
Yeah.
Anyway, this company
makes a whole line of colors
with equally snappy names.
Red... Red Menace,
Yellow Fever,
Green Revolution.
That'd be a job,
coming up with those names.
You think there could
possibly be a job like that?
I mean, how many hair colors
could there be? Fifty, maybe.
Someone's got that job.
Agent Orange!
I came up with that one.
I apply my personality
in a paste.
Oh, I doubt that very much.
Well, you don't know me,
so...
you don't know, do you?
Sorry. I was just...
I'm trying to be nice.
Yeah. I got it.
[Inhaling]
[Sniffs]
[Sighs]
My name's Clementine,
by the way.
I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
Hey.
No jokes about my name.
Oh, no, you wouldn't do that.
You're trying to be nice.
I don't know any jokes
about your name.
Huckleberry Hound.
I don't know what that means.
Huckleberry Hound?
What are you, nuts?
It's been suggested.
[Chuckles]
# Oh, my darlin', oh, my darlin'
Oh, my darlin' Clementine #
# You were lost
and gone forever #
# Dreadful sorry
Clementine ##
[Laughing]
No?
I'm sorry. Just...
It's a pretty name, though.
It really is nice.
It's, uh...
It means "merciful."
Right? Clemency?
Although it hardly fits.
I'm a vindictive little bitch,
truth be told.
Gee, I-I wouldn't
think that about you.
Why wouldn't you
think that about me?
I don't know.
I just...
I just, uh...
You seem nice, so...
Oh, now I'm nice?
Oh, God. Don't you know
any other adjectives?
I don't need "nice."
I don't need myself to be it,
and I don't need anybody else to be it at me.
Okay.
[Clementine]
Joel?
It's Joel, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I'm a little out of sorts today.
[Exhales]
My embarrassing admission is,
I really like
that you're nice right now.
I mean, I can't tell
from one moment to the next
what I'm gonna like,
but right now...
I'm glad you are.
[Giggles]
I have so much stuff
that, uh, I probably should, uh...
Oh! I'm sorry. Okay.
I-I'm writing, and...
No, no. I just...
Sure. No. That's okay.
I just have...
You know, this is...
Okay.
- Ohh! Hey!
- Take care, then.
Jesus!
## [Radio: Pop]
Hi. I could, uh,
give you a ride, if you need.
It's cold.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah?
It is frosty.
You're not a stalker
or anything, right?
I'm not a stalker.
You're the one that talked to me.
Remember?
That is the oldest trick
in the stalker book.
Really?
There's a stalker book?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I gotta read that one.
Look, I'm sorry if I came off
sorta nutso. I'm not, really.
Oh, it's okay.
I didn't think you were.
Did you wanna have a drink?
I have lots of drinks,
and I could, um...
Um...
[Chuckles]
Never mind.
Sorry. That was stupid.
I'm embarrassed now.
No, no, no, no.
Good night, Joel.
Two Blue Ruins.
Thank you.
Drink up, young man.
It'll make
the whole seduction part
less repugnant.
I'm just kidding!
[Laughs]
Come on.
[Exhales]
You're kinda closed-mouthed,
aren't you?
[Whispers]
I'm sorry.
It's just, you know,
my life isn't that interesting.
I go to work, I come home.
Don't know what to say.
You should read my journal.
I mean, it's just... blank.
Really?
Does that make you
sad or anxious?
I mean, I'm always anxious,
thinking I'm not living
my life to the fullest,
taking advantage
of every possibility,
making sure
I'm not wasting one second
of the little time I have.
I think about that.
Yeah?
[Both Laughing]
You're really nice.
Ohh!
God, I have to
stop saying that.
I'm gonna marry you.
I know it.
[Slurps Drink]
Um... okay.
Joel, you should come up
to the Charles with me sometime.
It gets frozen this time of year.
That sounds scary.
Exactly.
I'll pack a picnic.
A night picnic.
Night picnics are different.
And, um, we could...
Sounds good.
But I... I should, uh, go.
Now.
You should stay.
No, I really... I'm... I...
I have to get up so early.
I would like you
to call me.
Would you do that?
I would like it.
Yes.
Wish me a happy Valentine's Day
when you call!
That'd be nice.
[Beeping]
[Line Ringing]
[Clementine]
What took you so long?
I just walked in.
Mm-hmm. You miss me?
Yeah.
Oddly enough, I do.
Oh!
[Laughs]
You said "I do."
I guess that means were married.
[Laughs]
I guess so.
Tomorrow night?
Honeymoon on ice?
It's really solid
this time of year.
Whoa! I don't know.
Come on.
Eee!
Come on, come on.
[Sighs]
Whew.
Oh. So beautiful.
[Clementine]
Isn't it?
[Sighs]
[Giggling]
Uh, don't go too far.
- Whoo! Oww! Ow!
- Whoa! Oh!
- Are you okay?
- Ouch! Fuck it.
Ohh! Oh, my ass!
[Grunts]
I think I should go back.
Come on. Come on!
What if it breaks?
- "What if"?
Do you really care right now?
- Huh?
Come here. Please.
[Whispers]
Come on.
[Mutters]
Ohh.
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Slidy-slidy.
Whoa! [Chuckles]
This is good.
Here, let me show you
this one thing.
What are you doing?
Whoa.
[Sighs]
Come on.
Think I heard a crack.
[Laughing]
It's not gonna crack
or break or...
It's so thick.
Show me which constellations
you know.
Um... Oh.
I don't... know any.
Show me
which ones you know.
Okay.
Oh. Here's Osidius.
Where?
Right there.
See?
Sort of a swoop
and a cross.
Osidius the Emphatic.
[Laughs]
You're full of shit.
Right?
Nope.
Osidius is right there.
Swoop and cross.
[Laughing]
Shut the fuck up!
[Whispers]
Clementine.
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
Hey.
Sorry to wake you,
but we're... here.
[Sighs]
Ahh.
Can I come over
to your house...
to sleep?
I'm so tired.
[Sighs]
Okay. Um, yeah. Sure.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Yeah. Oh.
Just...
Yes?
Can I help you?
What do you mean?
Can I help you with something?
[Sniffles]
No.
What are you doing here?
I'm not really sure
what you're asking me.
Oh.
Thanks.
# I need your lovin' #
# Like the sunshine #
# Everybody's gotta learn sometime #
# Everybody's gotta learn sometime ##
## [Stops]
[Man #1]
We're looking for 159.
[Man #2] What number's that?
[Man #1]
I don't know where that is.
Jesus Christ, you'd think
they'd light the number,
or at least put a number on...
[Man #2]
Is that him?
[Man #1] I think so.
Yeah, that's him.
Wait. That's him.
[Giggling]
Hey, Joel.
Frank.
Oh, shit.
Jesus. The only
Valentine's Day cards I get
are from my mother.
How pathetic is that, huh?
You're lucky
you have Clementine, man.
She is way cool.
Hey, you got any big
Valentine's Day plans with her?
No.
Well, it's only a day away.
Better make some reservations
or something.
Don't want to end up
at Mickey D's. Right?
[Chuckling]
McRomance!
You want some fries
with that shake?
I have to, uh,
go to sleep now, Frank.
It's 8:30.
## [Man #1 Singing, Falsetto]
[Man #2]
Patrick, stop it.
[Sighs]
Ohh! Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Whew. Okay.
[Man #1]
Showtime at the Apollo.
Shh, shh, shh. Hey.
[Whispers]
Quiet.
[Grunting]
[Equipment Dropping Onto Floor]
[Frank]
Hey, Joel. What's up?
[Joel]
Oh. Hi, Frank.
[Mailbox Door
Opening, Closing]
[Keys Jingling]
[Sighs]
I only get Valentine's Day cards
from my mom.
How pathetic is that?
[Man's Voice Echoing,
Indistinct]
You're lucky
you have Clementine, Joel.
Hey, you got, uh, any, uh, big
Valentine's Day plans with her?
[Whispers]
No.
It's only a day away.
Better make a reservation
or something.
Don't wanna end up
at Mickey D's.
[Chuckling]
[Woman]
Oh, no!
[Joel] Yes! Valentine's Day
is three goddamn days away!
I want it resolved.
I'm willing to be
the one to resolve it.
So I call her,
and she's changed her number.
[Joel]
So I walked over to Antic Attic,
you know, to get her something.
I thought I'd go over to work,
give her an early valentine, and...
You won't believe it.
She's there with...
this guy,
this really young guy.
And she looks at me like
she doesn't even know who I am.
Excuse me?
Can I help you
find something, sir?
[Chuckles]
Hey, Clem-ato.
Patrick! Baby boy.
What you doing here, baby?
[Patrick]
Just came to surprise you.
Let me know
if you need something, sir.
You look good.
- [Patrick] Hi.
- [Kiss]
How are you?
[Clementine] Pretty good.
Pretty bored. Pretty tired.
[Patrick]
Uh-huh.
[Clementine]
I so want what's in your suit.
Oh, good.
[Panting]
Why?
Why would she do that to me?
Hey, does anybody want a joint?
Oh, God, Rob, give it a rest.
Oh, God.
She's punishing me.
I know, honey.
For being honest.
It's horrible.
I should just go to her house.
No! No, no, no.
You don't wanna go there, man.
You don't wanna go there.
Get off. It's too...
Right.
Yeah.
I don't want to seem desperate.
Joel, why don't you just see this as a sign,
make a clean break. Right?
Right?
[Joel Groans]
All right, Joel,
look, man, seriously.
[Woman]
Rob!
Here's the deal.
Don't do that.
Rob, what are you doing?
No, no, no, no.
What's your fucking suggestion, Carrie?
What's your brilliant, reasoned solution?
You're gonna make this
about our shit now?
This isn't about us.
I agree. It's not about us.
It's about Joel, who's an adult.
Okay?
Not Mama Carrie's kid.
- What are you...
- That's your laundry!
That's great.
That's good.
[Dog Barks]
Okay.
What is it?
[Rob] I don't know.
It's some place that does a thing.
[Woman]
Good morning. Lacuna.
No, I'm sorry.
That offer expired
after the new year.
Yeah, sure.
We can fit you in...
How about on the fifth?
That's a Wednesday.
All right, great.
Could you spell that, please?
Okay, and we'll need
a daytime phone number.
Great. Have a nice day.
See you then.
May I help you?
I'm Joel Barish.
Excuse me?
I'm Joel. Barish.
I have an appointment with Dr...
Mierzwiak.
- Here. Could you please fill this out?
- I just want to talk to him.
You still need to
fill the form out, sir.
Really?
- Thank you.
- [Mutters] Great.
I don't have a pen.
There's a pen right there.
[Phone Rings]
Good morning. Lacuna.
Oh.
Oh, yeah, that offer. That's done now.
That expired after the new year.
Mr. Barish?
How are we today?
Not too good, actually.
Boo!
Oh, my God! Stan!
Sorry.
Sorry, I was just...
I'm working!
[Mutters]
Sorry. Sorry.
[Whispers]
Here, Doctor.
Thank you.
You should not
have seen this.
I apologize.
This is a hoax, right?
I mean, this is Clem...
I assure you, no.
[Woman]
No.
Mm-mmm.
There's no such thing as this.
Look, our files are confidential,
Mr. Barish,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say that Miss, uh...
Miss Kruczynski was not happy,
and she wanted to move on.
[Dr. Mierzwiak]
We provide that possibility.
"Miss Kruczynski was not happy
and wanted to move on.
[Banging]
We provide
that possibility."
What the hell is that?
Nicest guy
she ever went out with.
[Rob]
Oww! Fuck!
God, Rob! Give it a rest!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Carrie, I am making
a birdhouse.
What can I say, Joel?
You know Clementine. She's like that.
She's impulsive.
She decided to erase you
almost as a lark.
[Sighs]
A lark.
[Sobbing]
Why? Why? Why?
Why did you do that?
[Woman]
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
I'm sorry, Doctor.
He just barged right in here.
Okay. I want it done.
I told him pre-Valentine's Day
is our busy time.
- Oh, th-th-that's... that's okay, Mary.
- But there are people waiting.
Mr. Barish, if you'd like to, uh...
to come inside.
And, Mary, if you could take care of Mrs. Woo.
Good-bye, Mrs. Woo.
Yes, of course.
Now, the, uh...
the first thing
we need you to do, Mr. Barish,
is to go home...
and collect everything you own
that has some association with Clementine.
Anything.
And we'll use these items to create
a map of Clementine in your brain.
Okay?
So we'll need, uh,
uh, photos, clothing, gifts,
books she may have bought you,
CDs you may have bought together,
journal entries.
We want to empty your home...
We want to empty your life
of Clementine.
And after the mapping is done,
our technicians will do the erasing
in your home tonight.
That way, when you awake
in the morning,
you'll find yourself in your own bed
as if nothing had happened...
a new life awaiting you.
[Tires Screech]
[Driver]
Wake up, buddy!
[Mary]
No, I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
You can't have the procedure done
three times in one month.
Well, it's just not our policy...
How are you today, Mr. Barish?
Hello. I'm right here.
I know it's an emergency,
and we'll do everything we can...
We can fit you in on the first of March.
Maybe you could talk to the doctor,
a- and he...
All right, so let's make an appointment.
What day would you like
to come in this week?
Mr. Barish.
Um, he's really busy
this afternoon.
Maybe tomorrow would be better.
Around 12:15? Can you do that?
February is very busy for us
because of Valentine's Day.
[Chuckles]
[Knocks]
## [Dixieland Jazz]
This is, uh, Stan Fink,
one of our most experienced
and skilled technicians.
## [Continues]
He'll be handling
your case tonight.
Great to meet you,
Mr. Barish.
My name is Joel Barish,
and I'm here to erase
Clementine Kruczynski.
Very good.
Now, tell me about, uh, Clementine.
Uh, I was...
living with this woman, Naomi,
uh, a couple years ago,
and my friends Rob and Carrie
invited us to this party at the beach...
I don't like parties.
Naomi couldn't go, but I went...
and I, uh, met Clementine.
[Pencils Clattering On Floor]
I'm sorry.
Let's start with
your most recent memories...
and work backwards from there,
more or less.
There's an emotional core...
to each of our memories,
and when you eradicate that core
it starts its degradation process.
By the time you wake up
in the morning,
all the memories we've targeted
will have withered and disappeared,
as in a dream upon waking.
Is there any risk
of brain damage?
Well, uh, technically speaking,
the procedure is brain damage,
but it's on a par with
a night of heavy drinking.
Nothing you'll miss.
Comfortable?
What we're doing here, Mr. Barish,
is actually creating a map of your brain.
[Mierzwiak]
Okay, let's get started.
If we want to get
this procedure underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I want you to react
to these objects, Mr. Barish,
if you will.
[Clementine Whooping, Laughing]
There's a good story
behind this one...
Uh, actually, Mr. Barish,
I'll get a much better
emotional readout...
if you refrain from any sort of
verbal description of the items.
Just try to focus on the memories.
Oh. Sorry. Okay.
[Stan]
Healthy activity up there again.
Healthy readouts. Very good.
- Here's another object.
- [Clementine's Voice]
That's so...
Next item. Okay.
Potato head.
[Chuckles]
- Next item. Okay.
- [Electronic Crackling]
[Stan, Voice Electronically Processed]
Just focus on the memories.
Patrick, do me a favor.
[Stan] Hey, Patrick,
do me a favor, will ya?
[Patrick] Yeah.
[Stan]
Can you check the voltage regulator?
What do we got there?
Uh, voltage looks fine.
Really?
Well, I'm not wiping
as clean as I like here.
I'm... [Scoffs]
[Mierzwiak's Voice, Distant]
Well, uh, technically the procedure
is brain damage.
Check the, uh...
Check the connections, please.
Oh, there you are.
I...
Why am I...
I don't understand
what I'm looking at.
Why am I
standing here and...
Oh, my God.
Deja vu.
This is so...
All right, we should get started.
If we're gonna get the procedure...
[Simultaneously]
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
[Whispering]
I'm in my head already,
aren't I?
I suppose so.
Uh, this is about right.
This is what it...
This is what it would look like.
Very good.
[Simultaneously]
We'll dispose of these mementos
when we're done here.
That way you won't be confused later
by their unexplainable presence in your home.
[Stan]
Ah, there we go.
Patrick?
Yeah?
[Stan's Voice, Echoing]
Patrick, can you check...
Patrick?
I'm getting some sort of readout
of my own voice.
Patrick? Patrick?
- Why are there so many wires?
- [Stan] A lot of equipment.
- Does that help?
- [Stan] Are you sure
you set that thing up properly?
[Patrick] How's that?
[Mary] How are you today,
Mr. Barish?
There we are,
Mr. Barish.
[Stan's Voice] That's better.
- I don't know if I like this.
- Think I might try this, then.
We're almost done now.
Mmm. Journal.
That would be invaluable.
[Stan's Voice, Electronically Accelerated]
"I met someone tonight.
I don't know what to do.
Her name is Clementine,
and she's amazing."
- [Screaming]
- Whoa! Jesus!
What? What?
Come on! Careful!
Step back!
Just take it easy.
[Beeps]
That's fine.
Let's not roach the guy.
[Sighs]
All right, you got that one.
This place is sort of a dump,
don't you think?
It's an apartment, Patrick.
[Whispers]
Patrick.
Well, not a dump, then,
but sorta plain. Uninspired.
And there's sort of
a stale smell.
Patrick, can we just please
get through this?
We got a very long night
ahead of us. Come on.
Yeah. Yeah.
[Door Unlocking, Opening]
[Joel Whispering]
This is the last time I saw you.
[Joel Clears Throat, Sighs]
[Heavy Sigh]
It's 3:00.
I kinda sorta wrecked your car.
[Sighs]
Were you driving drunk?
It's pathetic.
I was a little tipsy.
Don't call me pathetic.
Well, it is pathetic.
It's fucking irresponsible.
Could've killed somebody.
[Sighs] Oh, God.
Maybe you did kill somebody.
Should we turn on the news and see?
Oh, Christ!
Should I check the grill to see
if there's any children or small animals?
I didn't kill anybody!
It's just a fucking dent, Joel.
You're like an old lady or something.
Well, what are you like?
A wino?
[Laughing]
Jesus, are you from the '50s
or something?
A wino?
Face it, Joely.
You're freaked out because
I was out late without you,
and in your little wormy brain...
you're trying to figure out,
did she fuck someone tonight?
No, see, Clem,
I assume
you fucked someone tonight.
Isn't that how you get people
to like you?
[Sighs]
I'm sorry. Okay?
Clem, I didn't mean it.
All right?
Clem?
Your keys.
I was just... I was just...
[Sighs]
I won't need them anymore.
Angry or annoyed or something,
I don't know.
[Door Slams]
Clem?
[Computer Beeps]
[Stan]
Got it.
Mary's coming over tonight.
[Patrick]
Yeah?
Yeah.
Just thought you'd wanna know.
[Patrick]
I like Mary. I like when she comes to visit.
I just don't think she likes me.
She likes you okay.
Maybe I should invite my girlfriend over.
I have a girlfriend now.
Do whatever you want.
Did I tell you I have...
[Clicks Tongue]
Yeah.
[Keyboard Typing]
Did I tell you
I have a new girlfriend?
We gotta focus here,
Patrick.
Yeah, the thing is,
our situation is...
is a little weird.
My girlfriend situation.
I'm sure it is.
[Laughs]
You gotta be...
[Engine Starts]
Clem, let me drive you home.
Get out of my face, faggot!
Look at it out here!
It's all falling apart!
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
You did it to me first!
I can't believe
you did this to me.
Goddamn it.
Clem! Can you hear me?
By morning you'll be gone!
The perfect ending
to this piece-of-shit story!
[Engine Knocking]
[Patrick] Is there something wrong
with a girl being attracted to me?
Is that a problem?
[Stan]
No, I think it's... funny.
[Patrick]
So, who do you think's better-looking,
me or this guy?
[Stan]
Patrick, let's focus, buddy.
[Patrick]
Remember that girl
we did last week?
The one with the... potatoes?
[Stan]
That girl?
That's this guy's girl.
[Patrick]
Right.
[Stan] Yeah.
[Stan Chuckling]
Was. We took care of that.
Oh, God!
Well, uh...
I kinda fell in love with her
that night.
[Laughing]
What? You little fuck...
What?
She was unconscious, man.
Well, she was beautiful, and...
I stole a pair of her panties
as well.
Jesus!
What?
It's not like...
I mean, they were clean and all.
Don't tell me this stuff, man!
I don't wanna hear this shit!
[Patrick]
They were clean!
[Stan] What? D-Don't! Stop!
[Patrick]
Okay. Yeah! All right!
[Stan] We got work to do.
[Computer Beeps]
[Stan]
Give me my papers.
[Crunching]
[Slurps]
[Patrick]
There's, um...
[Sighs]
There's more.
After we did her, I kind of...
went to where she works
and asked her out.
[Stan]
You what?
[Mutters]
Jesus.
Jesus, Patrick!
Do you have... any idea...
how unethical...
[Laughing]
It's not really that bad.
What? Get that look off your face.
What's wrong?
[Stan Continues, Echoing]
Patrick, you stole a girl's panties!
[High-pitched Giggling]
[Laughing]
There's someone here.
He stole your underwear.
[Voice Wavering, Electronically Altered]
I don't see anyone.
[Clock Ticking]
[TV: Man Talking,
Audience Laugh Track]
[Clementine]Joel?
Where are my boots?
[TV: Man]
Why are you showing me poisons?
Can't you understand English?
"Potions," I said.
Potions.
[Laugh Track Continues]
[TV: Grandpa Munster]
Love potion, please.
I'm fucking crawling
out of my skin!
Should've left you
at the flea market.
[TV: Grandpa Munster]
First thing to do is...
[Chuckles]
sift in a cup
of powdered whale heart.
Wanna go?
I want to have a baby.
[Chuckles]
Let's talk about it later.
No! I want to have a baby.
I don't think we're ready.
You're not ready.
Clem, do you really think
you could take care of a kid?
[Scoffs]
What?
[Mutters]
I don't wanna
talk about it here.
I can't hear you.
I can never the fuck understand
what you're saying.
[Whispering]
I don't wanna talk about this!
Fucking ventriloquist!
We're fucking
gonna talk about it!
I... don't... want... to...
You can't just say something like that
and say you don't wanna talk about it!
[Whispering]
I'm sorry, Clem.
I'd make a fucking good mother!
I love children, I'm creative and smart,
and I'd make a fucking great mother!
Oh, God... Mmm!
[Voice Echoing]
It's you, Joel. It's you
who can't commit to anything!
It's going! It's going!
You have no idea how lucky you are
I'm interested in you!
[Voice Fading, Echoing]
Maybe I should end this
right here, Joel!
Leave you at the flea market
with this stupid costume jewelry!
It's done. This is crap.
Maybe you could find yourself
an antique rocking chair to die in!
All the pain, confusion...
[Doorbell Rings]
Oh. Hi, Patrick.
Hi, Mary. How's it goin'?
Hey, you.
Oh, it's freezing outside.
[Stan]
Find us okay?
[Mary] Yeah.
Mmm.
Hot!
Poor guy.
Mmm? Oh.
Don't you have
anything real to drink?
Uh, we haven't really
checked yet.
Patrick?
Uh, yeah.
Uh, let me do the honors.
Mary hates me.
Never really had much luck
with the ladies.
Maybe if you stop
stealing their panties.
[Typing On Keyboard]
[Patrick Whispering]
Stan. Stan.
There's more.
No!
Yes.
Hey, hey!
[Mock Whispering]
[Stan Laughing]
Oh, you didn't want any,
did you, Patrick?
Uh, no, that's okay.
Wait.
"Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better
even of their blunders."
[Clink]
[Laughing]
Oh.
Oh!
[Patrick Laughing]
Mmm!
[Groans]
That's Nietzsche.
Beyond Good and Evil.
I found it in my Bartlett's.
What's your Bartlett's?
It's a quote book, Patrick.
It's a book of quotations.
I think Howard
will be in Bartlett's
one day.
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
[Crash]
[Mary Laughs]
God!
[Patrick Laughing]
Can you wake him up?
You can't wake him up.
[Patrick Continues Laughing]
[Stan Yells]
Mmm.
[Moans]
You don't tell me things, Joel.
I'm an open book.
I tell you everything.
Every damn embarrassing thing.
You don't trust me.
Constantly talking
isn't necessarily communicating.
I don't do that.
I want to know you.
Hmm?
I don't constantly talk.
Jesus!
People have to
share things, Joel.
Mm-hmm.
That's what intimacy is.
I'm really pissed
that you said that to me.
I'm sorry.
It just... really just
isn't that interesting.
[Clementine]
I wanna read some of those journals
you're constantly scribbling in.
What do you write in there
if you don't have any thoughts
or passions or...
love?
[Joel's Voice]
November 19, 2003.
Dinner at Kang's again.
Are we like those poor couples...
you feel sorry for in restaurants?
Are we the dining dead?
I can't stand the idea of us being
a couple people think that about.
[Whispers]
I like that.
How's the chicken?
Good.
More?
No. No. Thank you.
[Joel's Voice]
She's gonna be drunk
and stupid now.
Hey, would you
do me a favor...
and clean the goddamn hair off the soap
when you're done in the shower?
Yeah. Oh. Yeah.
It's really...
- Gross.
- gross.
- It's just...
- Repulsive.
It's repulsive.
[Phone Beep Dialing]
[Line Ringing]
[Stan]
Patrick, can we get through this?
Patrick.
[Patrick]
Hey, Tangerine.
[Clementine On Phone]
Oh, Patrick, it's you.
[Sighs]
I'm so miserable right now.
[Patrick]
Why? What's wrong?
[Clementine] I don't know.
[Voice Electronically Altered]
Excuse me?
I'm so confused!
Can I help you
find something, sir?
[Patrick]
Confused? What are you confused about?
Everything's fine.
[Voice Electronically Altered]
Baby, come here.
[Patrick]
Scared of what?
[Clementine]
Do you love me?
[Patrick] Of course I do.
[Whispers]
Where's the self-help section?
[Clementine Sobbing]
Do you think I'm ugly?
[Patrick]
No! You're beautiful!
[Dishes Rattle]
Maybe I should come over.
[Clementine]
No, no.
I don't know.
I- I'm a mess, Patrick.
[Patrick]
Well, just let me come over.
I'll cheer you up.
[Clementine]
Okay.
Stan, can I leave for a while?
My girlfriend's really upset.
We're right in the middle
of erasing this poor man's...
[Garbled]
Let him go, Stan!
Let him go. I'll help.
See?
How hard can it be?
- She hates me.
She wants me to go.
- Go.
All right.
I'll be right over, Tangerine.
You like?
[Laughing]
Oh, man!
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
I like it.
You do?
You look like a tangerine.
Ohh!
"Clemen-teen" the tangerine.
Mmm! Juicy!
And seedless.
I like that.
I like tangerines!
Can you see me doing ducks?
Tangerine.
Joel. Ducks.
Quack-quack.
How does he know
to call you that?
How did who know?
Oh, my God. Clem?
[Mary]
This is pretty cool.
That's what
they called themselves.
The Clash...
the only band that mattered.
They called themselves that
for a reason.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Like social justice...
Yeah, it's totally incredible.
What Howard
gives to the world.
Yeah.
[Beeping]
To let people begin again.
[Punches Keys]
It's beautiful.
You look at a baby,
and it's so pure and so free
and so clean.
And adults are, like,
this mess of sadness...
and... phobias.
Howard just makes it all go away.
Oh, my God.
Baby, what's going on?
I don't know.
I don't know!
I'm lost, I'm scared,
I feel like I'm disappearing.
Disappearing?
My skin's coming off!
I'm getting old!
Nothing makes any sense to me!
You're not getting old.
Nothing makes any sense.
Ohh, Tangerine.
Nothing makes any sense, Patrick.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey, let's go out dancing. Yeah?
You wanna go out to Montauk with me?
Montauk?
Yeah.
No! Come up to Boston with me.
Sure. Yeah.
We can go next weekend.
No, no. Now. Now.
Yeah. I have to go now.
I have to see
the frozen Charles now.
## [Rock]
[Giggling]
[Answering Machine: Joel]
Hi, it's Joel.
Um, leave a message after the beep
and I'll get back to you.
[Beeps]
[Patrick On Answering Machine]
Pick up! Pick up, man!
W-W-W-W-Whoa.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
[Laughing]
## [Continues]
Hello? Yeah, what's up?
I got into a little situation
with the old lady.
Can you handle things tonight alone?
I'm really sorry, man.
Don't worry about it.
I got it under control, man.
[Continues Giggling]
He's pretty much on autopilot
right now anyway.
Thanks, Stan. I owe you big-time.
Dude, I gotta go.
I gotta go.
[Muttering]
Charles.
Come on, Charles.
"Look! You and me on the Charles River.
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm just exactly where I want..."
I'm so excited. Yea.
I'm excited too!
Cool.
Oh, uh, I, uh...
I got you this...
What?
thing, um...
Happy early Valentine's Day.
Oh!
Wow. What is it?
Uh, I don't know.
Open it up.
Oh.
It... It's gorgeous!
- You like it?
- Yeah. It's just my taste. Really.
I've never gone out with a guy
who bought me a piece of jewelry I liked.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Okay.
Joely?
Yeah, Tangerine?
Am I ugly?
Mm-mmm.
When I was a kid,
I thought I was.
[Sighs]
Can't believe I'm crying already.
Sometimes I think people
don't understand how lonely it is
to be a kid.
Like you don't matter.
So, I'm eight...
and I have these toys,
these dolls.
My favorite is this ugly girl doll
who I call Clementine.
And I keep yelling at her:
"You can't be ugly! Be pretty!"
It's weird.
Like if I can transform her,
[Sniffles]
I would magically change too.
You're pretty.
Joely, don't ever leave me.
Pretty. Pretty.
[Joel's Voice]
Mierzwiak, please
let me keep this memory.
Just this one.
[Clementine]
I don't wanna hold your hand.
Come on.
Whoo!
Whoa!
[Clementine Whoops]
Stop it!
[Clementine Laughing]
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just...
happy.
I've never felt that before.
Mmm.
I'm just exactly...
where I wanna be.
Clem?
I wanna call it off.
I'll give you a sign.
I wanna call it off!
Can you hear me?
I don't want this anymore!
I wanna call it off!
[Stereo: Man]
# When you ain't got nothing to do #
# I think I'll marry you ##
[Screaming]
Is anybody there?
[Loud Groaning]
Clementine?
Joel?
Clement...
Joely?
Clem!
Joel?
What?
We gotta go.
What? Where?
I have an idea
of how to stop this.
Stop what?
Joely.
Come on, Clem.
Smell my armpit!
No!
Don't tickle me!
Don't make me smell you.
Smell my pits!
No.
Good.
Concentrate, Clem.
We gotta get back
to the office.
There was a tape recorder.
No, not the picture.
Not the picture.
Where is it? Back here.
Come on!
[Clementine]
Oh, look at me.
Hey, I look good there.
[Mierzwiak]
Look, our files are confidential,
Mr. Barish,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say that Miss, uh...
Miss Kruczynski...
was not happy
and she wanted to move on.
Good. Now, tell me about Clementine.
[Joel]
Just tell me everything you remember.
That's what he said. Then...
What did we see that day?
No, wait.
Oh, look! Hey!
Shit!
We're going to see
my grandma.
Joel, why... No, I don't want to...
Joel, please!
We're not going on a train.
Don't make me run anymore.
Come on!
Mierzwiak!
Do we always have to run?
[Dog Barking]
Please.
So, why don't we begin
by you telling me...
everything you can remember.
[Joel]
Mierzwiak! Wake me up!
Oh, I-I'm sorry, Mr. Barish.
I thought you understood
what was going on here.
I don't know.
You're erasing her from me.
You're erasing me from her...
I don't know.
You've got this thing.
I'm in my bed. I know it.
I'm in my brain.
I'm part of your imagination too, Joel.
How can I help you
from there?
Uh, I'm inside your head too.
I'm you.
[Grunts]
Sorry.
Look. Who's that?
Oh, he-he works for us.
That's, uh, Pa-a-a-a-atrick,
baby boy.
He's stealing my identity.
He stole my stuff.
He's, uh, seducing my girlfriend
with my words and my things.
He stole her underwear.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
[Door Closes]
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm just exactly where
I want to be.
I want to go home.
Hey. What?
Clem!
[Grunting]
Wait. Clem!
Clem?
They're erasing you.
[Dog Barks]
I'm here!
[Screams]
Clem, focus.
I hired them, okay?
[Laughing]
I'm so stupid.
Sweetie, calm down.
Enjoy the scenery.
I need it to stop before I wake up
and I don't know you anymore.
Okay, well, you know,
just tell them to cancel it then.
What the hell are you talking about?
I can't just cancel it. I'm asleep.
Wake yourself up!
Okay. You want me to wake up?
Okay. Great. All right.
Okay, here we go.
This make you happy if I try?
Yeah.
I'll try really hard. Here we go.
That was a great idea.
Yeah. Okay.
Boy, that's working
like gangbusters.
[Mary Laughs]
Don't! That tickles me!
[Stan] Oh, my goodness.
Oh, my God. What is that?
Jesus Christ! What the...
[Mary]
It's a birthmark!
It did work, for a second,
but I couldn't...
I couldn't move.
See?
Oh, well, isn't that just another one
of Joel's self-fulfilling prophecies?
It's more important
to prove me wrong
than to actually...
Look, I don't want to
discuss this right now, okay?
Fine.
Then what? I'm listening.
I don't know.
You erased me.
That's why I'm here.
That's why I'm doing this
in the first place.
I'm sorry.
You... You!
You know me. I'm impulsive.
That's what I love
about you.
[Beeping]
[Clementine]
Joel?
[Joel] Mm-hmm?
I have another idea
for this problem.
This is a memory of me,
the way you wanted
to have sex on the couch after you
looked down at my crotch.
What?
Joel, the eraser guys
are coming here,
so what if you take me
somewhere else,
somewhere
where I don't belong,
and we hide there
till morning?
[Sighs]
Oh, man. I can't remember
anything without you.
[Scoffs]
Tsk, that's very sweet,
but try, okay?
Okay.
# Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream #
# Merrily, merrily
merrily, merrily #
# Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream #
# Row, row, row your boat #
[Both]
# Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily #
# Life is but a dream #
[Boy]
# Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily #
# Merrily, merrily
merrily, merrily #
# Life is but a dream
Row, row, row your boat #
It's working!
# Row, row, row your boat #
# Gently down the stream ##
[Clementine]
I'm a genius!
[Giggling]
Joel?
Where'd you go?
I'm supposed to come too!
[Woman] Listen, I'm just gonna
go get a salad bowl. Can you stir the soup
and keep an eye on Joel?
[Woman #2]
Sure.
He just likes to be near me.
Absolutely!
Clem?
It worked.
My God, look at this! Wow!
It worked! Look!
Look at this dress, man!
Oh, my God! Look at it!
I wish I could take it with me.
Who am I?
Mrs. Hamlyn.
Right. Mrs. Hamlyn.
I must be about four.
Oh, my gosh.
Found the salad bowl,
so I'm serving salad and string beans.
Is he okay under there?
Peanut, are you all right?
God, honestly, I feel like
I could clean up all day.
Listen, would you hate me if I asked you
to clean some string beans?
No, not at all.
Oh, my God.
I love this kitchen.
Thank you so much.
She's not looking at me.
She's busy.
[Laughing]
No one ever looks at me.
I want my mommy.
Oh, baby Joel.
Hey, Joely! Joely!
Is every little peanut
under there okay?
Mm-hmm! He's fine.
Do you have something to drink?
Would you drink
a cocktail at this hour?
I mean, I know it's not 5:00.
I would die for a vodka.
Oh, hang on.
Let me check if I have that.
Okay! I'm just
gonna wait right here.
Joel! Hey, no, sweetie.
[Grunting]
Uh, Joely.
Your mother wants me to mind you.
Get back under the table.
Ice cream.
No, not until after, you know,
you've had your dinner.
[Angry Grunt]
Come on, Joel!
Joel, grow up!
Don't leave me, Clem.
Oh, my God, Clem.
[Sobbing]
This is sort of warped.
I'm scared.
[Crying]
I want my mommy!
Don't cry, baby Joel.
Baby Joel, it's okay.
Joel. Joely. Joel!
Stop it! Look, I think it's working.
Look, we're hidden, Joel. Look!
Hey, honey, look.
Wait there.
My crotch is still here,
just as you remembered it.
Yuck.
[Buzzing]
It stopped.
What?
It stopped erasing.
Oh, shit.
This is terrible.
He's off the map.
Where?
I don't know where!
What do you mean? I don't know where!
This is bad.
This is very, very bad news.
Where are my glasses?
Okay. Crap.
Okay. What do we do?
What do I do?
What shall we do?
I don't know what to do.
- What shall we do?
- Crap. Crap. I don't know!
- I just said that I don't know what to do.
- I'm sorry. What do we do?
I don't know.
Now, look, you're freaking me out.
Mellow out.
Well, you have to do something.
He could wake up all half-baked.
Quiet. You're freaking me out.
Shh. Shh.
All gooey and... and half-baked.
Hmm, that sounds so good.
Oh, shit!
I'm hungry.
Oh, shit.
Oh! Oh!
What? Oh! What, what?
What?
- We should call Howard.
- No way. No, sir, man.
This is my...
I can handle this.
I can't call Howard.
He's an unbaked cookie.
He's... There's no time
to fuck around.
I got this under control.
What are you talking about?
Stop fucking around!
Okay, I'll call Howard.
[Phone Rings]
[Rings]
Hello.
Hello, Howard?
Hey, it's Stan.
Um, I'm working on this guy
down here, and we seem to have
lost him for a moment,
and, uh, I can't...
I can't bring him back up.
Okay, uh, tell me what happened
before he disappeared.
Well, I wasn't sure, really,
'cause I was away from the monitor
for a minute...
and I had it on autopilot
because I had to, uh...
I had to pee.
Where's Patrick?
Patrick? Patrick had to
go home sick.
Ah, geez.
Okay, what's the address?
I know. I'm so sorry.
That's okay. Come on.
[Stan]
I'm at 159 South Village.
Yeah.
Apartment 1 E.
Rockville Center.
Mary?
He's coming right now.
Yeah?
I'm staying.
[Bottles Clinking]
- Get your stuff, Mary.
- I'm staying.
I think you should go.
Hell, no.
Mary... Shit.
I am so stoned.
Please, Mary.
You have to go.
Stop being stoned, Mary.
I don't want him
to see me stoned.
Mary, you have no idea how much trouble
we're gonna get into if Howard comes...
I look like shit!
Joely, stop it! Joel!
Look! Hey, Joel!
[Blubbering]
Joel!
I want her to pick me up.
It's weird how strong
that desire is.
Joel, look at me! Look.
You'll remember me
in the morning,
and you'll come to me,
and you'll tell me about us,
and we'll start over.
Pat? I just... Pat?
I thought we could have
a little cocktail.
That Patrick guy...
he's copying me.
What Patrick guy?
That guy!
What?
He's here in my apartment.
He's one of those eraser guys.
He fell for you when they were doing you,
and now he's introduced himself
like he doesn't even know you,
and you guys are dating.
Really? Is he cute?
Clem,
there's nothing wrong with you.
You're the most wonderful
person I've ever met.
You... You're kind,
[Sobbing]
beautiful...
and smart and funny...
and... nice.
What?
Okay. All right.
Okay. Oh!
Move, move, move!
Come on. Let's go.
Careful, careful.
Fine.
Oh, my God. I'm still stoned.
[Groans]
Those eyedrops you gave me
didn't do shit.
[Chuckles]
[Doorbell Ringing]
[Clears Throat]
Be cool. Cool.
Hello, Mary.
What are you doing here?
Oh, hi, Howard.
She was just here to help out.
I wanted to understand as much
as I could about the procedure
as possible.
I think it's important for my job
to understand the inner workings...
of the work that we do.
Well, not that I do,
but the work that is done...
by people... where I also work,
the work of my colleagues.
All right, well,
let's see if we can, uh,
get to the bottom of this,
shall we?
Uh, yeah. Um...
Well, that's odd.
I already tried that.
Did you try going
through the C-gate?
Yeah, of course.
I mean... yes.
Yeah.
[Clears Throat]
All right.
You want to get linked up?
Yeah.
All right.
I already... I ran
the utility programs,
and I had nothing there,
so I checked all the memories
against the printed logs.
Here, Howard.
Okay.
I got you a chair.
There you go.
Oh, thank you.
You're welcome.
Whew!
All right, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna go through
the entire memory,
see if something comes up.
# Oh, my darling
Oh, my darling #
# Oh, my darling Clementine #
# You were lost
and gone forever #
I love being bathed in the sink.
# Dreadful sorry, Clementine ##
Such a feeling of security.
I've never seen you happier,
baby Joel.
[Giggling] Hmm!
There it is.
I don't understand
why it's off the map like that.
What the heck
was he doing there?
[Grunts]
[Gagging]
[Coughing]
His eyes are open.
- Has this happened before with him?
- [Stan] No.
Oh, this is...
this is not good. No.
I'm gonna have to...
I'm gonna have to give him this.
[Gasps, Panting]
Can't you see I love you,
Antoine?
[Mierzwiak]
Okay, we're back in.
[Mary]
Wow. That was beautiful
to watch, Howard.
Like a surgeon
or a concert pianist
or something.
Thank you, Mary.
Um, Howard,
you should get some sleep.
I-I think I'll be fine now.
Why can't you see I love you,
Antoine?
Hmm. Lucky me.
Lay one on me.
[Kissing Sounds]
Don't call me Antoine.
My name is Wally.
Yes, I know,
but how can a woman love a man
with a name like Wally?
Oh! Oh! What was that?
Hey.
My God, there's people
coming out of your butt.
There is?
[Giggling]
- Got it.
- Tangerine!
[Crying]
What, Joel... What are you doing?
We gotta go.
Go on. Please, please, go.
Please go!
You can run,
but you can't hide.
Clem, come on!
There I am.
[Tires Screech]
That truck.
Doc? Please.
[Distorted Voice]
All right, let's begin
by you telling me...
everything you remember...
That's strange.
He's in a memory
that we've already erased.
Oh, well, at least
we know where he is.
He's back on track, right?
[Sighs]
Come on, Clem.
[Stan's Voice]
He seems to have developed some sort
of resistance to the procedure.
I don't want to run anymore.
Shit.
Come on, come on.
Hide me somewhere deeper,
somewhere really buried.
Where?
Hide me in your humiliation.
Humiliation.
[Boy]
Come on, you big baby!
[Joel's Voice]
I'm sorry, okay?
[Angry Voices Overlapping]
[Joel's Voice]
Let me drive you home.
[Child Yells]
No!
- [Mary] Bye, Howard.
- No, wait. Howard.
He's disappeared again.
Oh, dear.
[Mary]
I'm so sorry, Howard.
Humiliation.
Hu-mi-lia...
Joel.
[Sighs]
I don't like it either.
I'm just trying to find
horrible secret places to...
Joel, honey, I have a surprise...
I just... Oh, um...
Uh, you know what, honey?
I'm just gonna ask you in the morning.
[Wheezing Laugh]
Good night, sweetheart.
[Laughing Continues]
No.
I'm sorry, Joel. Joely.
Shut up.
Look! Joel!
Joel, look!
What?
Look where we are!
Whoo!
Clem, this isn't good.
Then hide me somewhere...
somewhere really buried.
[Children Shouting]
Hit it! Hit it!
[Joel]
I can't! I gotta go home.
I'll do it later!
[Shouting Continues]
Come on, you big sissy!
[Shouting Stops]
[Sobbing]
[Children]
Ooh!
Ooh, he has a girlfriend!
Wait. What am I doing?
You know something, Freddy?
And he loves her!
You don't scare me anymore.
Ow! Ow!
[Groaning]
Joel!
Joely, get up.
Come on, it's not worth it.
Hit him! Hit him!
They're not worth it, Joel!
Tra-la-la-la-la! He's not listening!
Come on, Joel.
Stupid!
[Joel's Voice]
I'm so ashamed.
[Clementine's Voice] It's okay.
You were a little kid.
Yeah?
Come on.
That's where I live... lived.
I wish I knew you
when I was a kid.
Do you like my pink hat?
Here, look, feel better.
You can really kill me this time.
It's my turn.
Go. One, two, three.
I can? You're really gonna die though.
Okay.
One, two, three.
You're dead.
[Both Groaning]
Oh, my mom.
It's... It's okay. We're playing.
Hi, Joel's mom.
He's killing me.
It's not real.
Okay, are you dead yet?
You're dead!
[Grunts]
Uh, I think I got the hang of this.
I still don't understand it,
but I'm finding him quickly enough.
Clem!
[Gasps]
[Grunting]
[Muffled Grunting]
[Groans]
[Growling]
Jo... Joely?
Are you okay, Joel?
Joel? Joel?
[Laughing]
Oh, my God.
That was terrible.
Okay, okay.
That was like three seconds.
All right.
Let me do it one more time.
One more, then I get to go.
Okay.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Whoo!
[Clementine Giggling]
Look at this.
This is so cool!
Cool. Look out! Look out!
Ah!
Shit!
It's fluff.
Our house!
Come on. Whoo-hoo!
Come on.
We gotta go!
Whoo!
Come on!
We gotta go. Clem?
We gotta go.
Aah! Come on!
No!
This is a really bad time
for this!
Get off me! Oh, God!
I don't even know
where we're going.
It's gonna be fun. Come on.
It's the best place.
No, this way.
No, no, no. This way.
You're no help at all.
[Shouts]
What's wrong with you?
[Laughing]
Let go of me, Joel!
[Grunts]
I like watching you work,
Howard.
[Chuckles]
[Grunts]
I guess, uh...
I guess I'll go out
for... for some air,
if nobody minds.
It looks like you have everything
under control here.
Yeah, that's, uh...
that's fine.
[Door Closes]
Do you like quotes, Howard?
What do you mean?
Oh, you know,
like famous quotes?
I find reading them inspirational,
and in my reading,
I've come across some
I thought you might like too.
Oh, well, I...
I'd love to hear some.
There's one that goes,
"Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better
even of their blunders."
That's Nietzsche, right?
Yeah.
And here I thought I could tell you
something you didn't know.
Oh, no.
It's... It's a good quote.
I'm happy we both know it.
Yeah. Oh, and there's
this other one I like.
It's by Pope Alexander,
and it goes...
Alexander Pope?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, shit.
It's just that I told myself
not to say "Pope Alexander"
and sound like a dope,
and then I go ahead and say it.
It's no big deal.
You're such a sweetheart.
The quote goes, "How happy is
the blameless vestal's lot?
"The world forgetting,
by the world forgot.
"Eternal sunshine
of the spotless mind.
Each prayer accepted
and each wish resigned."
I want to be
a great big, huge elephant...
with a huge trunk like that.
Clem? Clementine?
I haven't heard that one.
It's lovely.
I just thought it would
be appropriate, maybe.
I really admire
the work you do, Howard.
I don't mean to be so familiar.
Oh, it's fine. It's fine.
I- I- I- I- I...
I'm happy to hear...
[Sighs]
I'm sorry.
[Sighing]
I've loved you
for a very long time.
I shouldn't have said that.
Oh, Mary, no.
It's... You're a wonderful girl.
But I... You know,
I have a wife and kids.
You know
Oh, Mary.
Oh, Mary, we can't do this.
Oh, whoa.
Well, good morning,
Mrs. Mierzwiak.
[Honking]
[Mary]
What?
Oh, my God!
Who is it?
[Sighs]
Uh...
Thank you, Stan.
Thanks a lot.
Hollis. Hollis!
[Engine Starts]
Hollis!
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Hollis.
- I knew it, Howard.
- Hollis, it didn't start out
to be like this.
I came here to work.
Hollis, this is a one-time mistake!
I'm a stupid girl
with a stupid crush!
Yeah.
I swear I basically
forced him into it!
Don't be a monster, Howard.
Tell the girl.
Tell me what?
Oh, you poor kid.
You can have him.
You did.
What?
Oh, uh,
we have a history.
I'm sorry.
Y-You wanted the procedure.
You...
You wanted it done...
so you could get past, uh...
You could... Yeah.
Um, I have to, uh,
finish the work in there.
It's almost morning.
We'll talk later.
Okay?
[Stan]
Hey.
Let me give you a lift home.
Fuck this thing. Damn it.
Hi.
Didn't figure you'd show your face
around me again.
I guess I thought
you were... humiliated.
You did run away,
after all.
I just needed to see ya.
Yeah?
I'd like to, um,
take you out or something.
You're married.
Not yet. Not married.
No, I'm not married, no.
Look, man,
I'm telling you right off the bat
I'm high maintenance,
so I'm not gonna tiptoe
around your marriage...
or whatever it is
you've got going there.
If you wanna be with me,
you're with me.
Okay.
Too many guys think I'm a concept,
or I complete them,
or I'm gonna make them alive.
But I'm just a fucked-up girl
who's looking for
my own peace of mind.
Don't assign me yours.
I remember that speech
really well.
I had you pegged, didn't I?
You had the whole
human race pegged.
Hmm. Probably.
I still thought you were
gonna save my life,
even after that.
Mmm. I know.
It would be different...
if we could just give it
another go around.
Remember me.
Try your best.
Maybe we can.
[Mierzwiak]
Okay, so just tell me
what you remember,
and, uh, then we'll
take it from there.
[Mary]
Okay.
I liked you immediately.
You didn't
come on to me at all.
I liked that.
I was so tongue-tied
around you at first.
I wanted you to think
I was smart.
I couldn't wait
to come to work.
I had these fantasies
of us being married...
and having kids and... just...
Oh, Howie, I can't do this.
[Mierzwiak]
We agreed it's for the best, Mary.
[Mary Crying]
Yeah, I know.
Oh, God.
I'll take the bottom and you...
Uh-uh-uh! No, no, no. Here.
I can take that.
So you want me to carry that?
Help me with that.
Can you get the cooler?
Honey, the cooler is...
That's light, huh?
Oh, I can get that.
You can get it.
No, no, no, no!
Don't take anything.
I can take the plane.
Put the thing up.
Put the gate back up.
[Joel]
This is the day we met.
You were down by the surf.
I could just make you out
in the distance.
I remember being drawn to you
even then.
I thought, "Wow, how odd.
I'm drawn to someone's back."
You were in that orange sweatshirt
that I would come to know so well...
and even hate, eventually.
At the time I thought,
"How cool! An orange sweatshirt."
Hi there.
Hi.
I saw you sitting over here...
by yourself,
and I thought, "Thank God.
Someone normal
who doesn't know how to interact
at these things either."
Yeah.
I don't ever know what to say.
I'm Clementine.
Can I borrow a piece
of your chicken?
And then you just took it...
without waiting for an answer.
It was so intimate,
like we were already lovers.
I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
So, no jokes about my name.
You mean like...
# Oh, my darling, oh, my darling
Oh, my darling Clementine #
Huckleberry Hound,
that sort of thing?
Yeah. Like that.
Oh, no jokes. No jokes.
One of my favorite things when I was a kid
was my Huckleberry Hound doll.
Oh.
I think your name is magical.
This is it, Joel.
It's gonna be gone soon.
I know.
What do we do?
Enjoy it.
[Clementine]
You married?
No.
Let's move into
this neighborhood!
I do sort of live
with someone though.
Male or female?
What?
Female. Female.
At least I'm not barking
up the wrong tree.
You know these people?
No, of course not.
Come on.
They might have a dog.
[Giggling]
There's no dog.
What are you doing?
It's freezing out.
I can't believe this.
Hoo-hoo!
- Clementine!
- There we go. Whoo-hoo!
Come on, man.
The water's fine.
Nobody's coming here tonight.
Believe me.
It's dark.
So, uh, what's
your girlfriend's name?
Naomi, but we're not really...
I mean...
We're...
[Laughing]
Whatever.
So this is great.
Now I can look for, um,
candles, matches...
and the liquor cabinet.
Oh, God.
[Tapping Phone Receiver Button]
I think we should go.
There's no phone line.
What?
I think we should go.
Why?
It's our house...
just for tonight.
[Sighs]
We are "David and Ruth Laskin."
Which one do you want to be?
Uh...
I prefer to be Ruth,
but I can be flexible.
What are you do...
[Chuckling]
Alcohol!
Oh, boy.
So, are you okay with wine?
I don't know.
Well, you choose the wine.
I'm gonna go find the bedroom
and slip into something more... Ruth.
I'm Ruth-less at the moment.
I really should go.
[Wind Howling]
I've gotta catch my ride.
So go.
I did.
[Joel's Voice]
I thought maybe you were a nut,
but you were exciting.
[Clementine]
I wish you'd stayed.
I wish I'd stayed too.
Now I wish I'd stayed.
I wish I'd done a lot of things.
Oh, God, I wish I had...
I wish I'd stayed. I do.
Well, I came back downstairs,
and you were gone.
I walked out. I walked out the door.
Why?
I don't know.
I felt like a scared little kid.
I was like...
It was above my head.
I don't know.
You were scared?
Yeah.
Thought you knew that
about me.
[Joel's Voice]
I ran back to the bonfire,
trying to outrun my humiliation, I think.
[Clementine]
Was it something I said?
Yeah.
You said, "So go"...
with such disdain, you know?
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Joely?
What if you stayed this time?
I walked out the door.
There's no memory left.
Come back and make up
a good-bye, at least.
Let's pretend we had one.
Bye, Joel.
[Joel]
I love you.
[Whispering]
Meet me in Montauk.
[Rob] I didn't crash the plane.
The plane crashed.
I didn't crash the plane.
[Carrie] You were operating the plane
with the remote control,
and then it crashed.
[Rob]
It was fucking windy.
Come on, man.
[Carrie]
You're stoned, and you're driving.
[Rob]
Yeah, the pot balances it out.
The pot brings you back up.
That's why I smoke it.
If I'm going to be drinking,
then I'll smoke it.
It does.
That's a medical fact.
It was proven
on the Science Network.
[Carrie]
Honey, just watch the road.
[Rob] I can't see shit.
I saw you talking
to somebody pretty.
She was nice.
Yeah, man. Who was that?
She was, um, just a girl.
[Beep]
Okay.
[Groans]
[Line Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
So I gotta...
I gotta drop the van off.
Thanks, Stan. Thanks.
We'll talk.
[Horn Honks]
[Van Door Closes,
Engine Starts]
[Groaning]
[Sighs]
Hey!
Hey.
You got a lot
of your stuff there, I see.
Yeah, that's right. My stuff.
I take it you're not coming back.
I wouldn't come back if I was you either.
Do you swear you didn't know?
I-I swear.
So you didn't do the erasing?
Of course not. God, no.
And you never even suspected
we were together?
[Sighs, Clears Throat]
Once, maybe.
I was coming back from a job,
and you were at his car.
I saw you two talking.
So I waved to you,
and you giggled, you know.
How'd I look?
You looked happy.
Happy with a secret.
And after that?
I never saw you two together
again like that, so I just...
I don't know. I just figured
I was imagining things.
[Man On P.A., Indistinct]
Aah!
[Man On P.A.] Montauk train
now boarding on track "B." All aboard.
I really like you, Mary Svevo.
You know that?
Thanks.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Yeah. Just...
[Beeps]
[Patrick On Tape]
Where are you, Clem?
I'm worried.
La-la-la-la-la.
I feel like you're mad at me,
and I don't know what I did.
What did I do?
I love you so much.
I'll do anything
to make you happy.
Tell me what you want me to do,
and I'll do it.
Listen, I'm gonna stop by this morning
just to make sure you're okay.
Oh. Whew.
Vamonos, seor.
[Chuckles]
I-I had a really nice time
last night.
Nice?
I had the best fucking night
of my entire fucking life...
last night.
That's better.
This is weird.
[Mary's Voice] To all patients
of Dr. Howard Mierzwiak.
My name is Mary Svevo.
"We've met,
but you don't remember me.
[Mary's Voice Overlapping]
I worked for a company you hired
to have part of your memory erased."
I have since decided
that this is a horrible...
Some kind of teaser ad or something.
[Mary]
In order to correct this,
I'm sending everyone's file back to them.
[On Tape]
My name is Clementine Kruczynski.
I'm here to erase Joel Barish.
What is this?
I don't know.
He's boring.
Is that enough reason
to erase someone?
I've been thinking lately
how I was before and how I am now,
and it's like he changed me.
I feel like I'm always pissy now.
I don't like myself when I'm with him.
I don't like myself anymore.
I can't stand to even look at him.
That pathetic, wimpy, apologetic smile.
- That sort of wounded puppy shit
he does, you know?
- What are you doing?
I'm not doing anything.
The bloom is certainly
fucking off the rose at this point.
- Are you screwing with me?
- No!
- You are screwing with me.
- Joel, I'm not!
- You clearly are.
- Look, let's just take a minute and...
[Exasperated Sigh]
[Door Closes]
[Panting]
Patrick, get the fuck away.
Oh, sweetheart...
Get the fuck away from me!
Can we talk about it?
No! Get the fuck away!
[Sobbing]
[Sets Brake]
Joel Barish.
Hey, Clementine.
Hey.
Nice to see you. Yeah.
Yeah.
[Joel On Tape]
Really very educated.
I mean, she's smart, I think,
but not educated.
I couldn't really talk to her
about books, you know?
She's more of
a magazine-reading girl.
Her vocabulary leaves
something to be desired.
Sometimes...
I was embarrassed in public...
Hi.
because she would pronounce...
library "libary."
Hi.
Libary. Libary.
Look what I found.
[On Tape] I think if there's
a truly seductive quality
about Clementine,
it's that her personality promises
to take you out of the mundane.
You made me look skinny.
Amazing, burning meteorite...
will carry you to another world
where things are exciting.
But what you quickly learn
is that...
it's really an elaborate ruse.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
It's okay.
So flashy
in a kind of obvious way.
But still, it seduces you.
Joel, I really like you.
I hate that I said
mean things about you.
- Let me turn this off, okay?
- Hey, it's... it's only fair.
Where's the real Clementine?
I mean, the whole thing with the hair...
it's all bullshit.
- I really like your hair.
- Thank you.
I really like your hair.
Thank you.
I do.
The world's a goddamn mess.
Is it some kind of a revolt?
Change your hair color.
You want a drink or something?
Do you have any whiskey?
No, I don't think her sex
is... motivated.
I saw it clearly
the last night we were together.
It wasn't sex.
It was just sad.
Hey. Sorry.
I thought there was more.
The only way Clem thinks
she can get people to like her...
is to fuck 'em...
or at least dangle the possibility
of getting fucked in front of 'em.
And she's so desperate
and insecure...
that she'll, sooner or later,
go around fucking everybody.
I don't do that.
I wouldn't think that
about you.
- Because I don't.
- I know.
Because it really hurts me
that you said that
because I don't do that.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry about all this.
I'm gonna... go.
I'm a little confused.
I don't really think I can be here.
Um... bye.
Bye.
[On Tape]
I thought I knew her so well.
It was nice meeting you and all.
But I don't know her at all.
What a loss to spend
that much time with someone,
only to find out
that she's a stranger.
Wait.
What?
I don't know.
Just wait. Just wait.
What do you want, Joel?
I don't know.
I want you to wait for...
just a while.
[Quiet Sob]
Okay.
Really?
I'm not a concept, Joel.
I'm just a fucked-up girl who's looking
for my own peace of mind.
- I'm not perfect.
- I can't see anything
that I don't like about you.
Right now I can't.
But you will.
You know, you will think of things,
and I'll get bored with you
and feel trapped...
because that's what happens
with me.
Okay.
[Crying]
[Laughing]
# Change your heart #
# Look around you #
# It will astound you #
# Now, I need your lovin' #
# Like the sunshine #
# And everybody's
gotta learn sometime #
# Everybody's gotta learn
sometime #
# Everybody's
gotta learn sometime #
# Mm-mm-mm #
# Change your heart #
# And look around you #
# It will astound you #
# I need your lovin' #
# Like the sunshine #
# And everybody's
gotta learn sometime #
# Everybody's gotta learn
sometime #
# Everybody's
gotta learn sometime #
# Mm-mm-mm #
# Everybody's gotta learn
sometime #
# Everybody's gotta learn sometime #
# Mm-mm-mm ##