I've been thinking about what you
said about that concrete goal.
And?
I think, I've nailed it.
I'm feeling really good about this one, Al.
Lay it on me.
- It's a girl.
- Cool! What's she like?
You know, smart, beautiful, popular...
A classic TGFY.
- Too Good For You, Al.
- But not for you?
Well, I'm sort of outside the whole highschool
foodchain at this point, wouldn't you say?
- So you gonna ask her out?
- Ask her out?
No. Bad idea, no.
I mean...
Where's the therapeutic value in that?
- So, what's the plan?
- Simple.
I'm gonna have fun with her.
- Fun? What's that mean?
- Fun?
Fun means fun. Right?
Don't over think it, Al.
It's been nice knowing you.
- Next week?
- You know what, Al? You've made so much progress here,
- I think you're ready to face the world on your own now.
- Keith?
Don't worry, Al. You can cope.
Keep it in mind!
- Yo, Anderson! What's up?
- Not much, how are you?
- I'm good you know, I'm just chilling.
Can't believe they did that!
- Hi!
- Hello!
- You're Rafael, right?
- Yeah. And you're...?
- Natalie... Anderson.
- Oh, head of...
Everything.
- I try to keep busy, yes.
- All work and no play?
None. Zero.
- So you're working now?
- Oh, absolutely. It's a Key Club...
We're checking on the stranger students
making sure they're adjusting okay.
- Well I'm having it tough...
- I can tell.
- You've only made about 50 or 60 new friends.
- Hey, brother.
- 61.
- Yeah. It's nice to know somebody cares.
- Rain...
- Yeah.
- Natalie, come on!
Alright, so I'm gonna go.
It's nice meeting you. I'll talk to you later.
- Come on, let's go!
-Coming!
-Ciao...
Zach! Breakfast is on the table!
- Natalie! Please get him up!
- Okay, okay!
Zach! Wake up!
Didn't come home!
- Morning!
Natie! Miles is a lefty, you're gonna
have to work in your backhand!
We know, we're gonna spend the whole
practice filling backhand today.
- According to my records last year...
- I'm all over it, Dad.
- ...she got you with her serve. 11 aces.
- ...aces. Thanks for reminding me.
- Natie's quicker now.
- If you beat her, your ranking jumps at least 3 places.
- What's this "if" about?
- Bye.
- Natie, sit down have some breakfast!
- I've got Key Club this morning, Mom.
You need have some protein. Sit down, please!
I have a bar.
- A bar is not a breakfast.
- Bye!
And as for the states of
attraction experiments...
The couples are:
Hobbs, Mertin; Carlens, Stevens,
Brand, Aldridge; Anderson and
Zetterstrom; Brandon, Davins...
- Zetterstrom?
- I haven't lied to you this far. I'm not gonna start now.
You gonna help?
- We don't need that for this.
- Look, you're not gonna be disagreable, are you?
'Cause Walt specifically promised
me an agreeable lab partner.
- Walt?
- You need to relax.
- Actually I need to learn this.
- Because why?
Because you have to get a four on your AP exam
if you wanna get a college credit, in case you didn't you know.
Then you'll be ahead of the game, right?
Then I can focus on the things I'm
good at and keep up my GPA.
Okay, so we need to fill this one with
sodium-tiosulphate and this one with nitrate solution...
Gotta keep up that GPA.
- It's kinda help if you ever wanna get a job.
- A job?
- Can we just do the lab?
- I'd love to! Let's do the lab!
Except you're about ten years into the future.
We don't need chemistry, we...
...we need time travel
Mr. Miles, this is AP.
Keith is actually pretty sharp
when he applies himself.
Okay...
- But we kind of...
- Lack chemistry?
- Yeah.
- Try to make it work, okay?
- About this Natalie Anderson thing...
- Yes?
Walter, she's a complete anal compulsive control freak!
How do you expect me to work with that?
- But Keith, you were who...
- I'm kidding. Kidding.
We're in pretty good shape.
Who the hell do you think you are?
Who do you think I am?
Hey, Miss Key Club!
Hey!
- So how are you adjusting?
- Oh, well, you tell me how am I doing?
Well, you only got a 98 percent
on the history midterms...
...so you're pretty much falling apart
I hate people like you.
Hey, so listen, are you gonna be at the brick again, friday?
- Are you going?
- It could happen.
Alright, Keith.
Thanks, man!
Who's that guy?
Oh...
...he's just my lab parner. Nobody.
- So you don't remember?
- What?
Well, I sat behind you on the sixth great play
You were the princess and
I was Russian soldier number three.
- I don't remember that.
- Of course not.
Princess never remembers the little people.
- Excuse me, well I'll cry for you.
- You should!
You should cry for me from
your early-decision tower.
It's posted in the front office.
- Why do they do that?
- Why Duke?
- Great faculty, division one, that kind of stuff
- I'm sure, you get what you pay for.
- Actually I have a partial scholarship.
- Ah, that's right.
- There goes the positive...
- Tennis.
So they basically give you a bunch of money
for hitting a ball over a net.
Something like that.
Where did you apply?
Nowhere.
- Not going to college?
- Not in Judeo Christian sense. No, I'm not.
So, what are you doing after graduation?
The sky's the limit.
That's informative.
- Why are you taking an AP class if you...?
- I haven't picked.
Then "Advance Placement" or what?
- I'm sure there's a very simple explanation.
- Of course there is Natalie
and you're not gonna stop until you figure. it out.
That's on like a challenge. You're on.
So this's all based on one little conversation.
You don't even know if he'll be there tonight.
Oh, he'll definitely be there.
Oh, your power of positive thinking?
- Hey, Brooke.
- Howdy?
- Hey, Nat, can I borrow ten bucks?
- For what?
- Come on, I'll pay you back tomorrow.
- Get out!
Let's go!
- It's really cool. What happened?
- Who turned off the music?
- Can I help you?
- Ahh, yeah.
- Who's that guy?
- What is he doing?
Buddy, relax, you'll like it! I promise! Listen!
What, you think you can change that, huh?
Because you'll like it. See?
I'm just kidding buddy,
Just have a good time! Alright?
Senorita, let's go!
- What? Oh, oh, no...
- Turn away! Hey welcome back!
- Interesting choice of music.
- Yeah? Can you keep up?
'Course.
So what do you think you're gonna do after college?
I'm gonna own my own record label.
- You think big.
- Why not?
What about you, Natalie?
Oh, I wanna run a magazine.
I wanna be the editor.
Yeah.
Run a magazine. Why not?
Why not do something amazing?
- Hey there's the whole world out there.
- Everybody here just wanna go to state.
- No one wants to do anything, you know try anything new.
- Yeah.
Keith.
Keith!
- The lab report is due tomorrow!
- Ah, yes!
But the real pressing question is
how is Rafael Marquez? Your boyfriend.
He's not!
Great choice that Rafael!
Brainy stud! Perfect guy! Can't go wrong!
You were at the Brick!
No.
But you were.
- If you weren't then how would you know?
- Because that's where everyone goes.
- What about the lab report?
- Hop in!
- Come on, come on! I do my best work while I'm driving.
- I have your book.
By heating tin metal...
...in air
...at a high temperature
we are able to produce a tin-oxygen product
called...
Wait!
So we need to convert the masses to moles then
divide the greater mole quantity by the lesser.
Okay, so... 0.0173 tin,
and 0.0350 oxygen.
So the mole ratio is?
Mole ratio? What's that?
- It's the thing you have to figure out.
- But you are already know the answer.
Oh, come on, you're being a jerk!
I gotta be back in fifteen.
What's the rush?
We're here in a yellow truck,
a road ahead of us and nothing but opportunities.
- Okay, what opportunities...?
- Choose a place!
- Pick a place! Right now! At random!
- Okay, I choose...
...the third point on our lab report
calculating the mole ratio.
I can't concentrate driving in a straight
line like this, this is not gonna work.
- Then turn!
- Where?
Anywhere.
Whoa!
Very funny.
The mole ratio therefore is 2:1.
But now we need to find the potential
oxidation numbers of tin and oxygen.
Which are?
It's time for our picnic scene.
Keith!
There he is! How's it going?
Move along, dear!
In case you haven't heard, picnics
they usually take place outdoors.
Oh, is that what it says
in the official picnic rule book?
This isn't funny.
Do you think our check is ready?
I..I know pumpkin love, you know I'm pissed off too.
Can you believe this shit?
It's been three months since that accident.
The nerve...
- Take me back to school! Now!
- Yeah! Let's get back to the library
and finish our lab report in a safe,
acceptable way like everybody else.
Bone grafts are really starting to kick in now.
Hey, Ralph!
No, thanks.
- You said 2:1 right for the mole ratio?
- Yeah.
Duke.
- They'll give you a job in a place like this one day?
- God, no.
- My dad used to work in a place like this.
- Ah, yes. Daddy Anderson.
An accountant?
A salesman?
A Norwegian fisherman!
District manager for a phone company.
You're not very good at reading minds.
Well that's 'cause I wasn't really trying.
He manages stacks of paper. Moving them from
side to side every day, he hates his job.
When he was your age he dreamed of
going to Duke but they rejected him.
So he poured over every detail of your application,
night after night until you finally got it right.
Natalie Anderson, the star of the household,
who loves being in the center of the attention.
She just wished it didn't mean having
to play tennis all of the time.
How am I doing?
Okay...
It's actually not so bad.
Can I help you?
Oh, we're just...waiting for Mr. Richardson.
He said he had to finish a phone call.
Okay.
- Goddamn that Richardson!
- Yeah...
Who's he think he is, that little monkey?
I'm sick of this shit! You know what , baby?
We're going straight to the top!
We're getting this littlemonkey ass FIRED!
- ...lame excuses, bullshit! Never pay out.
- We just have to be patient, honey!
Okay, so you're an only child.
Your Mom works for a diaryfresh. Your Dad is a...
...a, the sir in construction and you live
in a ranch house. How am I doing?
Actually I have two brothers, three sisters,
Dad works in real estate, mom helps him out
and we live in a farmhouse.
A big old farmhouse.
Where?
- Where do you live?
- Beaver Creek, off the Route 10.
That old white house?
- With the big front porch?
- With the big front porch.
Oh, that's such a great place.
That's where I live.
Okay, this is nice, but that's not
enough to fill up two pages.
Okay, but this is all the
pictures that we have.
Oh, really? Okay, well then why don't you just
draw something, and throw it on page 2..
...because this is not gonna fit with what's...
- Okay, I'll take some more, okay?
- Okay, thank you.
- So, were you with the freak?
- He's not a freak. Did Raff come?
- Well, you said that you'll back to be there.
- It wasn't actually a definite plan.
I told to him you had to bait.
Did he say anything?
Oh, just that his parents are going out
tonight and he wanted to have a pool-party.
- Cool.
- And he sounded really pissed that you blew him off.
- Natalie, what are you doing with what's his face?
- A lab report.
Oh, really? And you just decided it'll be fine
if you left me here to deal with all this shit?
- I lost track of time.
- Because the lab report was so exciting?
I had to get it down. What's your problem?
- I'm just having a really shitty day.
- What?
- Skinny envelope.
- Notre Dame? Oh, shit!
- Wait-listed.
- Really?
Oh, they accept like three percent from the waitlists.
It's basically rejection.
- No, no, we can add stuff to the application.
- Yeah, and what good is that gonna do?
Well you tell them it's your first choice school...
...we'll get another letter of recommendation
from the faculty and make this happen.
- Your power of positive thinking?
Right!
Hey, Raff.
Who else is gonna go?
I do have a tennis match.
Maybe afterwards, if there's time.
Okay. Bye!
Everything is totally under control.
Atta girl!
Yeah! Go, Natalie!
Van der Waals' states of attraction experiment. Okay,
A myriad of forces causes into molecular attractions.
The strength of these attractions is dependent on
several factors. Understanding these forces is vital to..
Oh, God!
- Be careful, would you?
- Am I gonna be in trouble for that?
Are you gonna punish me for this?
- I might have to.
- 'Cause you know how I feel about all that stuff.
Look, partner, you know the deal.
But those spiky heels really hurt me...
Keith, you've been a bad boy..
..now you're gonna pay the price.
Do you mind?
- So we're on five P.M.?
- For what?
- A bowling-scene.
- Bowling? Serious?
I'm going out.
Tomorrow?
Keith, I can't.
It's not a date.
- Keith, maybe sometime...
- Friday?
I'll just schedule it with your assistant!
Okay, you do that!
You rewrote it?
I swapped the second and third paragraphs
and I got rid of the stuff about the history project.
It's a little bullshitty, you don't really need it.
But a few other tweaks too.
- Great!
- I'm sending it to you right now.
- Yes sir, editor in chief!
- Natalie, phone!
I gotta go. It looks really really good.
- Won't make a difference.
- No, this will work! It will!
Got it.
- Alright, I'll talk to you later. Bye!
- Bye!
- Hello?
- It would not be a date.
- Who is this?
- It's only bowling. Come on, what are you so afraid of?
Keith... hi!
Look, I'll pick you up at five P.M. tomorrow after school.
Did you happen to do the homework?
Homework?
...Homework?
It's your turn to write up
the chem lab notes, remember?
- You're screwing with my grade here.
- Yeah and you're changing the subject!
I told you, I have plans.
Alright, look, you'll be home by nine o'clock...
...plenty of time for a date afterwards.
- I'll see you in school!
- What... maybe.
With the lab notes...
- So who's on the phone?
- Oh, my lab partner.
- Did you have a nice time?
- Yeah.
- What's his name?
- Keith.
- Keith? Oh, I thought...
- Rafael. His name is Rafael.
- The South-American boy?
- Yes.
Well you should invite him for dinner sometime.
We'd love to meet him.
Okay. Sure.
He's really nice.
- So who is Keith?
- Oh, he's nobody. He's just my lab partner.
"A: It's not a date.
B: You are my lab partner.
C: Just to see..."
Clever.
"D: Bowling is the most popular sport in
America and it is important that we fit in.
E: It's not and will never be a date."
What is he, he's like stalking you, or something?
- So what should I do about him?
- Oh, simple...
Ping!
Okay, your papers on the
"Great Gatsby" are due in two weeks.
For those of you without a calculator,
that's May 4th.
The way write to write the paper?
Is to go home, go into your room.
I know it's gonna be strange for some of you,
but trust me something valuable will happen...
"The european heritage two-week-tour is a living classroom.
Students have an opportunity to
acquire a greater perspective on the world
and an increased enthusiasm for learning."
Personally I'm interested in acquiring a deeper
appreciation of french wine-drinking heritage.
What about the Amsterdam wake and bake heritage?
Well don't we have an increased enthusiasm
for learning. It's working already.
- Sign me up, baby.
- I'm in.
Oh, we're totally in.
Hey, can we meet a little later tonight? Like 9.
I forgot I'm supposed to help somebody in english paper.
- The movie is at 8.
- Oh, shit.
- Well, we'll figure out something else.
- Thanks.
I don't know...
You really wanna base your relationship with
a great guy like Raff on lies and deceit?
Why don't you just tell him the truth?
You're spending a couple of
hours with your lab partner.
- What I do with Raff is not your business.
- My point exactly.
I thought we're going bowling.
We're saving that!
Believe it or not, there are bowling balls at the bowling alley.
- But not like these babies.
Cosmo...
Patsy...
- A Walt ball.
- But we only need two.
If we were just bowling.
- Andy is an artist.
- That's great, but you're running out of time.
First things first.
- You're fixing it up with spare parts?
- They're all spare parts.
- We're creating life in that hadn't been matter.
- You and Andy?
Me and my Dad.
- Are you close with your Dad?
- Hold this tighter!
Are you?
He was alive before the days of
electronic ignition. I need him.
So this truck is...
It's like, your thing...
- Yeah, yeah, it's my thing.
- Interesting...
You're so talented, Keith!
You have so much academic potential,
What are you doing wasting your time
with that damn truck?
Well, I did't say that, but... it's kind of true.
Don't listen to her, honey bun! She's just jealous.
So... she's your girlfriend.
Look, you're out of time.
I gotta go. No bowling tonight.
Keep going! Go around the corner!
He's prompt! I like that in a man!
Show up on time and leave him wanting more, baby.
Shut up! Just dirve!
Sneak down the alley to meet your boyfriend.
Sexy.
- Bye!
- I'll pick you up at four.
- Four?
- A.M.
He'll be gone by then, right?
What are we gonna do at 4 A.M.?
- Keith?
- It's not a date.
I'll pick you up right here!
At our secret spot!
What?
What?!
- You ever done this before?
- Kissed?
Is that gonna be a problem for you?
I just don't think this is gonna work out any more, Natalie.
- Oh My God!
- What? I was kidding!
I'm kidding...
You know it's gonna sound really cheesy but...
- when I do that, I just wanted to be...
- Oh, no, no. I've got that all covered.
We'll have a heart-shaped bed that
I ordered and we have candles...
- You know what I'm talking about!
- I know, I know...
- No rush okay?
- Thanks.
Just think, years from now you're gonna have a big huge family
and you're gonna wanna share stories
and one of the stories will be that when you were in high school,
you put a bowling ball at your chemistry teacher's front porch.
And his name was Walt.
I refuse!
Go! Go!
Get outta here, you jerk!
- His last name is Marquez.
- It's the thought that counts.
- I'm gonna be so screwed.
- Ah, yeah.
- If we're caught just swallow one of these!
- It's not funny shit head!
So, who gets these?
Well, you can't give up now,
Patsy, you're gonna be state champion!
My daddy won't let me...
...Cosmo.
Now, what's your daddy know about your bowling?
Well, he's warning in and all
you know and to him it's just a game
- and to him, games is the devil's handiwork.
- Patsy, you're the greatest!
- You can make the nationals!
- I gotta respect my daddy's wishes.
He's had a hard life.
Particularly killed himself
raise us nine kids.
- That was my last game.
- Well, darling...
then it was my last game too.
"Dear waitress,
please find a home...
...for our balls.
Cosmo and Patsy."
- This is the saddest day of our lives.
- Indeed it is.
Natie!
- What's up?
I'm just putting in your last match.
You're now ranked 14th.
Come take a look!
I believe you.
If you stay in the top twenty,
you'll be sent for that scholarship.
- Dad!
- What?
- Did you apply the Duke?
- Actually yes I did.
I didn't get in. It was very compared of year.
You'd ever think about doing something different?
Different?
- For work.
- Such as?
- Something you might actually enjoy.
- Like what?
- Dad!
- What?
He's smart, confident, he's really hot.
I kinda think he's perfect.
- So what did you guys do last night?
- Oh, we just hung out and talked.
Few other things...
Not that!
It's great with Raff, there's absolutely no pressure.
- So I guess Courtney was hallucinating?
- What?
She said she saw you with Keith
Zetterstrom on state street.
- Oh, well I hang out with him for a little bit too.
- Oh!?
- What? I'm not allowed to have other friends?
- Not when they're stalking you.
Keith is cool, he just, he does things his own way.
It's kinda perfect actually.
It's Keith keeps me busy and that
way I don't get all obsessive about Raff.
It works so.
Alright, hey, if it works out for you,
then that's just great.
It does.
I gotta go. I got tennis.
- Bye!
- Call you later.
Do you speak spanish?
That's so cool!
- Are you learning any languages at the school?
- French.
- So have you ever been to Italy?
- Oh, yeah, I actually I used to live there, couple years..
We're planning a trip there. It's my dream.
Oh, yeah! I recommend!
Florence is one of my favourite cites.
Natalie tells us that your planning in attending to Penn State.
Umm, actually it's UPENN, sir.
She also tells us you're quite a sportman.
Oh, yeah, I play football ever since when I was a little kid.
- Oh, you know Pete was a... tell...
- No...
Okay, Pete was a great football player in college.
I wasn't a great great football player.
But I played a little football.
Oh, soccer?
Football.
- Bon appétit!
- My uncle says we can have it any weekend next month.
- After the 14th. After APs.
- Sure.
- So your parents are gonna be okay with this?
- Yeah. Yours?
- Something can be arranged.
- Just you and me... and the fireplace...
- Actually...
...we really need to talk.
I need to be honest with you
about how I feel about this.
- What?
It's beautiful. It's perfect. You're perfect.
Well, I actually thought we were waiting...
- But we can work up to it, right?
- Oh, yeah...
Come in!
Some guy in a truck dropped this for you.
- I got it!
- Okay.
Thanks.
- What's that?
- I don't know. Chem lab notes?
Gross! What is this?
- Carburator tune up kit.
- Just what I always wanted.
"Guaranted not to raise your GPA"
- He's really starting to get in my nerves.
- What's that mean?
- He just does shit like this.
- Is he a little...?
- Something like that.
- He has a crush on you.
- He's crushed on his truck.
- Oh, whatever, just...
- ...don't encourage him.
- I don't!
- Shit!
- Are you ready to go?
- Actually I have to take a shower.
- You want me to wait?
No, that's alright. You go ahead!
I'll meet you there.
Alright. Byebye!
- Bye!
Keith!
We need to talk.
Hop in!
I'm not going to anywhere with you.
Cool, well then I'll come inside and
watch TV with Pete and Caroline.
No. No.
No!
- You can't just deliver shit to my house like that!
- It works, didn't it?
Listen,
I like you.
I like being friends with you.
But if we're gonna hang out from now on,
I gotta be a part of the plans!
- See, but there are no plans!
- Bullshit!
- You got a whole scenario worked out.
- Is that what you think?
- Yeah, and you can't just expect
me that drop everything
because you decided you wanna do some...
- Well, I don't expect you to do anything!
You're free go at anytime! In fact,
what is Nathalie Anderson doing
hanging out a truck geek like me anyway?
This is cool.
This is the scene
where we're at the crossroads.
You're being a jerk.
Oh, come on, miss "the bay queen"
Stud boyfriend, tennis champ!
Do you have any better things to do on a Friday night?
Just go, leave, get out here!
You know I thought you were different,
but you're not different.
You're just another immature little boy!
You're right.
I am wasting my time here.
And what about you?
Mr. Egomaniac?
Why do you always give me gifts and
writing me clever little notes all of the time?
Why don't you leave?
- Go ahead! Drive away right now!
- There's Keith! Stop, Al!
Keith!
Keith, guess what!
They got me Super Smash Brothers and Gran Turismo 3.
They're like beating each other up,
- they got all these characters all brawling each other off...
- Hey, Billy, Al.
They got mario, and they got luigi.
Billy, how's it going buddy,
Listen, this is, this is sophie.
- Natalie.
- Hi! I'm Al.
She's a double agent. You can't trust her.
- they got all these monsters that are
battling and clashing at each other and...
- Oh, good. I'm gonna kick your ass!
I'll kick your ass!
Come on, let's get out here! Come on!
- Let's go to your house!
- Billy... you know... Billy...
I'm on specially assignment tonight, buddy.
How about tomorrow?
- Oh man, I got school tomorrow! Come on, let's go!
- Billy, we gotta go!
- Come on, sleep one more night there! One more!
- Billy, it's time to get in the car right now!
- My parents don't care!
- Come on! Next time.
- Oh, man...
- Atta boy.
- I'll talk to you, Keith?
- Hang in there, Al.
You're doing just fine.
- I'll kick your ass!
So how do you know them?
The neighborhood.
Billy is what? Hyperactive or something?
So you're his...
Counselor?
Tutor? Something like that?
Such a guy...
...turns out you're a softie.
So, what is it?
Church program?
The Y? Volunteer thing?
Let's get outta here!
Come on, let's go!
Got a yellow truck
Road in front of us, and
Nothing but opportunities, right?
Turn right up here!
Right here! This dirt road!
Come on! What?
Why here?
Why?
It's not supposed to be a why, right?
What are you scared?
Whoa, whoa! Slow down!
Just funny!
Really funny!
- What?
- You chose this road.
So that's the Brick!
I've never been on this side.
Never been on that side.
You're not missing much.
Really? I thought you were the Brick Queen.
It's getting a little old.
It's all about what you're wearing and who's
hooking up with who and showing off your boyfriend.
- The essential information.
- Oh, yeah.
Down there they live and die by that crap.
But up here it's like...
...why did I ever care.
But you don't...
What?
You don't care what people think.
You're just...
...you.
Whatever that is.
It's a good thing.
It's a really good thing.
So do you come here a lot?
Cool.
- I found your place.
- I don't know how you did.
Chances are probably one in a billion.
Stranger things have happened, right?
We should probably leave.
- Yeah.
- We're lab partners.
- This is strictly a lab partnership.
- Absolutely.
- And Walter would be very very upset right now. So...
- Hey, Raff!
- Hi, beautiful! Are you ready?
I'm so sorry, I just got out of the shower.
Actually... I don't really feel like
to go to the brick tonight.
- Why? What's wrong with the brick?
- Just that we've gone for the last six weeks in a row.
I know but we've promised to Trisha,
- and you know, Robbie.
- We see them all the time.
Well, you see me all the time.
So you're getting sick of me Natalie?
Of course I'm not getting sick of you
I'm just really beat.
Had a long day, practice after school.
I was gonna call you sooner.
Okay, it's alright. Just get some sleep
and we'll hang tomorrow, okay?
- Yeah, see what's happening.
- Okay.
- Okay, bye!
- Bye!
- Hi!
Natalie!
- Guess, where I'm gonna be next year!
- Notre Dame!
That's great!
We have to celebrate this!
- Okay, partner! Now I've got a scene.
- Shoot!
It's the scene when you tell me the truth.
The big confession scene.
What are you doing after you finish highschool?
Really.
- I'm going to London.
- London?
Me too! With Raff and Brooke and Travis!
We should meet up!
Not that London.
London, Ontario.
There's a classic truckshow
there every year in July.
- So you really are truck geek.
- You see I open up to you and you dump on me.
No, just because I know you have dreams
more than a truck show.
- The sky's the limit, right?
- Yeah, actually it is.
Are you sure?
I'm sure you sell yourself short.
Are we...?
Are we moving?
We are moving!
It's like we're moving through space on a mission.
Keith, we have a problem.
- I think, there's an entry of other space craft.
- Keith! Get up! You gotta get up! Come on!
- Keith, it's gonna go over! Get up! Come on!
-And it's taken over the body of our trusted co-pilot
- Natalie Anderson.
- Keith! It's gonna go over!
- "It's gonna go over!"
- Come on! What are you doing?
She keeps saying that.
- You're gonna get yourself killed!
- "Keith, stop it!"
Keith!
- Natalie Anderson...
- Keith, Hurry up!
Shit! Keith!
"Get up, Keith."
"..Keith,  get up."
Keith, hurry, get up!
you're gonna get killed! Keith!
Stop the truck! Keith!
What the hell was that?
Are you crazy?!
You don't do shit like that,
You could get yourself killed!
Not to mention what would've
happened to my truck...
Oh! Oh, yeah!
Did you wanna go over?
- I wasn't even close.
- Yes, you were!
- You don't know how close is.
- Don't give me one of your stupid lines!
I know what close is!
Good night, partner.
Take care of yourself, okay?
TRIPTOPAX XR IS INDICATED FOR THE TREATMENT OF DEPRESSION
No, not C, Z.
Zetterstrom.
Z, E, T, T, E...
Are you sure?
- What do you think you're doing?
- What?
- Using yourself cellphone in school property?
- Hey... the heck?!
It was Duke, apparently there is
a problem with my transcript.
- Oh, is everything okay?
- Actually now, I have to go wait in line
at the office and deal with this.
Sucks.
- Bye!
Look, he's been gone for a few days now,
so I was thinking I should call him you know
get him caught up in the homework and all.
I'm sorry, we don't give out that information.
But it's kind of an emergency.
I mean Keith, he's falling way behind,
...and it's affecting me.
I need to prepare for the APs.
You'll have to speak to Mr. Miles regarding that.
Okay, look, he's my friend, you know.
He's given me his number,
I just lost it. It's really not a big deal.
- I'm sorry, I can't.
- Where is he? Why doesn't he come?
I'm trying to learn stuff,
it's like he doesn't care!
I think Keith's having a tough time at the moment.
- Tough how?
- Thanks.
That's all I can say really.
Well.. is there anything I can do?
I knew this was a bad idea.
- What?
Partnering you guys.
But it was random.
He chose me?
Keith chose me?
I'll make sure he gets your notes.
Damn it!
Game. Set. Match.
Randy Randerson manages to the semi-finals.
- You want me to come in?
- Maybe. No.
Shit, I don't know. I think, I just need
to get some sleep, or something.
You have plans with Keith?
- Where did that come from?
- Well, do you?
As a matter in fact I have
absolutely zero plans with Keith.
- But you've been hanging with him.
- I hang with a lot of people.
Is there something wrong with that?
Am I only allowed to be seen with you?
No, no. Relax, okay?
The match is over.
Sorry.
Just having a really screwed up day.
So everything's okay?
He's just my lab partner, my friend.
Actually he's not even my friend
- so can we just let it go?
- Yeah, whatever.
So well, talk to you later.
Natalie, we have to talk!
I lost the match.
Get over it, Mom!
Natalie, come back here!
Natalie, I am talking to you!
- Yeah?
- Hi! Is Keith home?
- Keith?
- I'm his lab partner.
- May I help you?
- Are you Mr. Zetterstrom?
- Mr. who?
- This is the Zetterstrom house?
My name's Don. Don Souper.
Sorry.
Wrong house.
Oh, quiz!
Sweet!
What timing!
Morning, Walt! Thank you.
Hey, partner!
Thanks for those notes,
I killed that quiz.
- Where you been the last two weeks?
- Last two weeks?
- What, do you come here every day?
- There's some wrong with you, isn't there?
Yeah, yeah there is...
...with me,
definitely with you,
- with this sexy little freshman right here.
- I don't wanna be funny anymore, Keith.
Oh, well I hate to break it to you, Anderson
but you've never really been funny to begin with.
What are you?
Depressed or something?
Depressed? Yeah, throw that out there.
Chicks find it incredibly sexy.
- I'm being serious, Keith.
- Why?
It never works.
You could have to told me.
Could have told you what?
That... you have problems...
You don't know the half of 'em.
- Hey, Raff.
- What's going on?
What?
- The jacket...
- Oh, you like it? I got it from K-Mart.
Raff, I was cold he lent it to me.
Oh, come on, you don't expect
him to believe that, do you?
You see Raff,
We're part of this jacket smuggling ring,
but if you're quiet enough I swear
there's a fleece in it somewhere for you.
- Look, I'm not talking to you, okay?
- Hey, man, don't get mad at me.
- I only a supply this shit, okay? I don't create the demand...
- Shut the hell up!
Raff! Raff, it's just a jacket.
That's it! Just a jacket.
This is bullshit!
Raff, wait up!
Marquez, it was a joke!
Raff! Raff!
- T'was just a jacket, right?
- Yes!
- That's it?
- Of course, that's all it was!
Raff, come on...
I've class.
- So it's all just a big joke to you, huh?
- I don't know.
- How is it?
- I don't know. I don't know anything anymore.
Why did you choose me your lab partner?
- Me?
- Don't bullshit me! Miles told me!
Walter Miles is CIA, you can't trust him.
- Where do you live?
- What?
Where do you live?
You lied about it!
- Are you losing it partner?
- You lied about everything!
'Cause you know what, I've got some
great pills that you could take.
But I'm sure you already knew that.
I just don't understand, Natalie,
You've always been one of the school's finest students.
- I needed the chemistry notes.
- You know very well that's not the way to get them.
- She made a mistake.
- She's been under a lot of pressure lately...
with her tennis schedule and all of her homework...
I'm sorry but defacing school property's
an automatic week suspension.
- What? What was I supposed to do...?
- Natalie.
- I can make any exceptions to that rule.
- I needed the notes I have to take the AP!
Mr. Miles will make sure you get those notes.
Just don't watch a mess of everything
you've worked so hard for!
Please, can we just not?
- If there's something you need to tell us?
- You know what, stop the car!
What?
- I can't think in here. I wanna get out!
- You'll stay right where you are, missy!
Natalie!
What?
The light was red!
- Hi.
Umm, chapters 14-16 in history
and that's your math take-home test.
Okay, thanks.
Are you okay?
Fine!
- Are you gonna tell me what happened?
Had a hissy fit.
Natalie!
You broke into Keith's locker.
I mean, really what were you looking for?
Oh, that's just great, I'm sure
you're all just gossiping your asses off.
No, I'm just tring to help you, okay?
Look, Keith is a loser! Okay?
He's jealous, and he's obviously
trying to break you guys up.
- That's ridiculous!
- Raff is pissed.
You'd talked to Raff?
- No, no! Natalie, just listen to me for one second!
- Go! Go away!
Natalie!
Keith's a psycho!
He's gonna screw up everything!
I'm going!
- Natalie!
- I'd like to warm up by myself for once in my life, Mom.
- I'll see you at the match!
- Natalie! I'm not ready!
Natalie.
Natalie! Natalie!
What the...?
- I told you I would talk to you later.
- I wanna know what's going on!
What's going on is I have a match!
Whatever is you could tell me about it.
Okay, Natalie?
- It has nothing to do with you.
- Well, because it has to do with Keith?
- It's about me.
- Then it's about me too!
Alright? 'cause you and I is just a little involved
in case you haven't noticed.
I need a little time.
If we want the lake house next weekend,
I gotta call my uncle...
- I'll call you later!
- Natalie!
Idiot!
Hi!
- Are you Keith's dad?
- Yeah.
Keith.
Keith!
I'll get him for you.
Does he have any brothers, sisters?
Just two of us.
I'm sorry.
He doesn't wanna to see you now.
Okay.
Thanks anyway.
I don't...
I don't care
where you're gonna be next year.
I don't care if you're crazy.
God...
I just know I wanna be with you.
I don't understand what you're doing.
It seems so pointless,
I mean everything,
it just seems so pointless!
But when I'm with you, it's different,
I don't know why.
So..
..we should actually go bowling.
- You know like with lanes and pins.
- Yeah, we should.
- Maybe tomorrow?
- Maybe.
- Are you even gonna be in school tomorrow?
- I don't know.
- I don't know about any this actually.
- What?
I mean a guy like me with a truck
gotta keep moving.
Stop it.
I mean, you know, I'm not really one
for the whole attachment thing anyway.
Shut up!
You got Raff.
Raff's a good guy.
Good for you.
Let's just forget about it.
Fuck you!
You just did partner.
If you just forfeit matches
what do you expect?
You're ranking dropped 15 points last month.
Great.
That's just perfect.
I'm gonna talk to Richard Honings,
he's a big guy over at the DTTA.
No, all we need to do is to get doctor to
write a letter saying that you were injured.
But I wasn't injured.
This is a 10,000 dollars scholarship we're talking about.
It's not my fault you wanted me to go to
the most expensive school in the universe.
- Duke is the best you'll ever...
- Why would you sell yourself short?
I didn't even finish any other applications.
Honey, you didn't have to.
You didn't want me to.
There are a billion other schools out there.
I mean, I could get a job.
- or something.
- You don't have to compromise, honey
if we focus on this, we can get the scholarship back.
Maybe I don't want it back.
Maybe I don't wanna play tennis
for six hours a day at college.
Maybe I am sick of it after 10 stupid years!
Did that ever occur to you?
Honey!
There is no reason to give up on your dream now!
- Oh, are you even listening to me?
- It is almost june! It is too late!
You're right!
Everything is just totally screwed up!
- Hey, we're not done here!
- Come right back here!
Hi!
We met. I was with Keith.
- Oh... hi!
How is Keith doing?
I don't really know.
Actually I haven't seen him much.
Does he still see that little boy? Billy?
Billy passed away.
- May I help you, sir?
- 15 on pump number three please.
What?
I'm sorry.
- How do Keith know him?
- Oh they were in chemo together.
- So you were his doctor?
Counselor.
I was...
But he's gonna be okay, right?
How sick is he?
Tell me!
I thought you knew. I'm really sorry.
Keith?
Keith.
Please come outside!
Keith, come on!
Keith, open the door!
Just talk to me please!
Keith...
Thanks for calling.
Sorry. I've been trying to figure things out.
Yeah? And? Did you figure it out?
Raff, we had a good time.
I really like you.
- Then why are you doing this?
I'm just going through a lot of stuff right now.
- Can we just leave it?
- No! We can't actually!
I couldn't find the Caribbean mix
so I'll have to give it to you later.
Yeah, yeah, later.
I've heard that one before!
I wasn't blowing you off!
Okay, things got complicated.
- Yeah, when you started bullshitting me, Natalie!
- You wanna know what really happened?
I know what happened, okay?
You let down that little jerkoff screw with your head!
- Is that what do you think?
- Yes. It's obvious!
- You've no idea what are you talking about.
- Well I would know if you told me!
- Stop it!
- What were you thinking?
What the hell were you thinking?!
What were you giving up for that little piece of shit?
Stop it!
You know I only hoped good things for you.
'Cause really bad shit happens to people!
I hope to God it never happens to you!
Welcome back, bad girl!
Alright ladies, gentleman!
Please leave your final reports on my desk...
I want you to make sure your glasswares are all cleaned,
your beakers, your testtubes, if they're dirty.
You must clean them,
or you will lose points in class.
If any items are missing, please notify me immediately.
Finally, make sure that your labsinks are clean
and that there is no material left in them
Four test cubes, three beakers...
and a Bunsen burner.
Yeah, okay, everything seems to be in order. Keys?
Natalie, key?
The end of chemistry as we know it.
You're such a goddamn glib little actor!
As far as I'm concerned this is
a really chickenshit goodbye!
Excuse me.
Don't worry, Walter.
She was adressing her remarks to me.
Hey!
The truck guy's here.
Said something about going bowling?
- Okay.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Everybody bites it sooner or later.
I'm just in the AP class, ahead of the game.
- Always the joke.
- Al says it's a phase, it'll stop soon.
But, hey! At least it wasn't
about sympathy for the sick kid.
That's not fair!
Is Duke fair?
Is Europe fair?
At this rate I won't even make it
to London, Ontario. Is that fair?
Bowling.
That's what I get.
We're not going bowling.
Why?
We're saving that!
Turn left.
So where are we going?
Sky's the limit!
I haven't lied to you this far.
I'm not gonna start now.
What are we doing?
Really?
- This is the goodbye-scene.
- Let's not...
Okay?
Come on, Zetterstrom!
You can do it!
Okay.
Wake up! Natalie!
Don't you see what happened here?
You had a beautiful life,
and I had shit.
I hated your guts.
I wanted to take you down,
I wanted to make you as miserable as I am
and that is exactly what I did!
Now,
how's that for a goodbye?
- Pretty lame.
- Face it, Anderson!
I screwed you!
I screwed you big time.
So you screwed me.
So what?
Me?
I made love to you.
Try again.
Try again!
I had it all figured out.
So I cut out early, who cares?
It's probably a good thing.
Life sucks, anyway.
Then I met you
and it got weird.
And you were so..
..amazing.
- And I...
What?
I just wanted a little more time.
So all in all,
I'd say you're the worst thing
that's ever happened to me.
Goodbye partner.
I am staying with you until you leave.
I don't care how much time we have!
Get that, you stupid jerk!
I'm starting her up.
Now turn it to the left.
'til it begins to stall, then back a notch.
Okay.
Perfect. Good for another 50,000 miles.
subtitled: randomscitizen