(SOBBING)
Dad.
(WAVES BREAKING)
(MAN GAGS)
(VOMITING)
Clear the ramp!
30 seconds!
God be with you!
Port side, stick.
Starboard side, stick.
Move fast and clear
those murder holes.
I want to see plenty
of beach between men.
5 men
is a juicy opportunity.
One man's a waste of ammo.
Keep the sand
out of your weapons.
Keep those actions clear.
I'll see you on the beach.
(SHELL EXPLODES IN WATER)
(MAN COUGHS)
(EXPLOSIONS)
(ENGINE THROTTLES DOWN)
COXSWAIN:
Open murder holes!
Over the side!
CAPTAIN MILLER:
Port and starboard, over the side!
(BULLETS HISS)
(BULLETS RING ON OBSTACLES)
Jesus.
Thank you--
(SOUND FADES)
(INAUDIBLE)
I said, what the hell
do we do now, sir?
SERGEANT HORVATH:
Captain Miller!
Sergeant HORVATH!
Move your men off the beach!
Go!
OK, you guys!
Get on my ass!
Follow me!
What's the rallying point?
Anywhere but here!
The sea wall!
Move up to the sea wall!
Sir, I'm staying!
Clear this beach!
Make way for the others!
This is all we got
between us
and the Almighty!
Every inch of this beach
has been pre-sighted!
You stay here,
you're dead men!
Mama!
Aaaaah!
SOLDIER:
Stay down! Stay down!
What are you guys?
104th Medical Battalion, sir!
Here to set up
field operations!
Get rid of that crap!
Grab yourselves some weapons.
Follow me.
Aaaaah!
I'm hit!
Briggs!
Get me out of here!
I'm hit low. God!
Medic!
Navy Beach Battalion, sir.
We gotta clear these obstacles,
make holes for the tanks.
All the armor's foundering
in the channel.
Orders, sir.
You go somewhere else.
I'm clearing this one!
Come on, Briggs!
Medic!
Move, move!
Move! Come on!
Move!
Aaaaah!
Shore party.
No armor has made it ashore.
We got no D.D. tanks
on the beach.
Dog One is not open.
Who's in command here?
You are, sir!
Sergeant HORVATH!
Sir!
You recognize where we are?
Right where we're
supposed to be,
but no one else is!
SOLDIER: Nobody's where
they're supposed to be.
Shore party.
First wave, ineffective.
We do not hold the beach.
Say again,
we do not hold the beach.
We're all mixed up, sir.
We got the leftovers
from Fox Company,
Able Company,
and George Company!
Shore party.
Cat-F, Cat-F, C--
REIBEN here, sir!
See anybody else?
JACKSON, but that's about it.
MELLISH here.
Caparzo! We got Deforest
back there with WADE.
He's hurt so bad he said
he sprung 100 leaks.
WADE says
he's all used up.
MEDICAL OFFICER:
Move on to somebody you can help.
He's battalion surgeon, sir!
Get his attention.
- WADE!
- Yo, Doc!
All right,
get him off the beach.
I got it!
We stopped the bleeding!
Fuck!
Just give us a fucking chance,
you son of a bitch!
Son of a fucking cocksucker!
Come on, WADE!
It's MELLISH!
WADE!
We found Miller!
Let's move!
Oh, God, oh, God.
This is all?
This is all that's made it?
We got scattered
pretty bad, sir.
There's bound
to be more of us.
Not enough.
This is not enough.
Dog One exit--
It's gotta be that
cut on the right,
or is it the one
on the left? Shit!
No, no. Vierville
is to the west of us.
This is Dog One.
They're killing us!
We don't have
a fucking chance,
and that ain't fair!
Gather weapons and ammo!
Come on, let's drag
'em in off the sand!
Hey, REIBEN,
REIBEN, REIBEN,
where's your B.A.R.?
Bottom of the channel, sir.
The bitch tried to drown me.
HORVATH:
Find a replacement.
Bangalores!
Bring up some bangalores!
Grenades, grenades!
Get 'em over here!
MILLER:
Bangalores go up the line!
Heads up!
Bangers coming your way!
Come on, come on, come on!
JACKSON here, sir!
REIBEN back, sir!
One more.
Give me one more.
Oh, my God, it hurts!
I'm gonna die!
Oh, my God! Oh, Jesus!
Oh, my God!
Keep it moving.
Almost got it.
Jesus!
Lucky bastard.
Keep it moving.
You got it?
God! God, help me!
You're not gonna die.
You're fine.
Don't look at it.
Bangalores!
Clear the shingle!
Fire in the hole!
We're in business!
Defilade!
Other side of the hole!
(MAN SCREAMING)
MEDICAL OFFICER:
That's it! Let's go!
Inspected. Morphine.
Routine.
Priority.
He's gone.
Son of a--
Get in there.
Fuck. I can't move.
MELLISH,
give me your bayonet.
MILLER:
2 MG-42s and 2 mortars.
Add 20, left 30.
There's a little defilade
over there,
but it's the perfect
firing position
if we get some goddamn
armor on the beach.
We gotta open up
this draw!
We gotta get this draw open.
REIBEN, MELLISH,
let's get into the war!
Grab some cover and put
some fire on that crew.
Davis, Debernardo,
Young, Valk,
get ready.
Covering fire!
Go, go, go!
Goddamn firing squad.
It's the only way
we can get everybody
the hell out of here.
Short, Payton, McDonald,
Parkes!
You're next!
Why not just hand out
blindfolds, Cap?
All we can do here
is die.
Covering fire!
Go, go, go!
Come on!
Come on,
come on!
Go, goddamn it!
JACKSON.
Sir.
Do you see
that impact crater?
Yes, sir.
That should give you
complete defilade
from that machine gun
position.
Get in there and give me
some fire discipline.
Wait for my command.
Go!
Captain, if your mother saw you
do that, she'd be very upset.
I thought
you were my mother.
Be not Thou far from me,
O Lord.
O my God,
I am heartily sorry
for having offended Thee.
O my God,
I am heartily sorry
for having offended Thee.
I detest my sins for having
offended Thee, O Lord.
Listen to me, Lord.
(PRAYING IN LATIN)
O my strength...
haste Thee to help me.
Dog One exit!
Right here!
We're in business!
Move!
REIBEN.
Let's go, Sarge. Go!
Come on, Doyle!
Sarge.
Flame!
Doyle, do it!
Don't shoot!
Let 'em burn!
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
I'll give you "comrade,"
you son of a bitch!
Lie down!
(GERMANS SCREAMING)
Cease fire!
Cut it out!
Sugar Cane.
Sugar Charlie 3.
Say again, Dog One is open.
Send in the 'dozers.
I'm waiting here
to tie in my flanks.
Over.
What?
(SPEAKING CZECH)
I'm sorry,
I can't understand
what you're saying.
What'd he say?
"Look, I washed
for supper."
Ha ha ha ha!
Hey, Fish.
Yeah?
Look at this.
A Hitler Youth knife.
And now it's a shabbat
challah cutter, right?
(GROANS)
SOLDIER:
Keep it moving!
(SOBBING)
HORVATH:
That's quite a view.
Yes, it is.
Quite a view.
(TYPEWRITERS CLACKING)
MAN'S VOICE:
"Dear Mr. Brian Boyd,
no doubt by now you have
received full information..."
SECOND MAN:
"Dear Mrs. Jensen..."
"...about the untimely
death of your son."
"...no words of mine can
ever relieve the grief..."
THIRD MAN: "Our outfit has
felt his loss tremendously."
FOURTH MAN:
"He was a fine soldier,
and he believed
very strongly in..."
FIFTH MAN:
"It's no secret anymore...
that we were involved
in one of the most important
operations of this war."
FIRST MAN: "Al was the one
who held us all together.
he was always the first to
volunteer and the last..."
SIXTH MAN: "...came to
a clearing near a road
where over 4,000 troops
had passed."
SEVENTH MAN: "Your husband
served in a combat unit
whose dangerous duty is
to place itself beyond..."
EIGHTH MAN: "...which we all
cherish and hold so dear.
The loss of Lee
and others like him
is a distinct blow
to the regiment."
NINTH MAN: "I fully
understand your desire
to learn as much as possible
regarding the circumstances
leading to his death."
(VOICES FADE)
(CONVERSATION INAUDIBLE)
Colonel, I've got something
you should know about.
Yes?
These 2 men died in Normandy.
This one at Omaha Beach.
"Sean Ryan."
This man at Utah.
"Peter Ryan."
This man was killed
last week in New Guinea.
"Daniel...
Ryan."
The 3 men are brothers, sir.
I've just learned
that this afternoon
their mother's going to be
getting all 3 telegrams.
That's not all.
There's a fourth brother,
the youngest.
He parachuted in
with the 101st Airborne
night before the invasion.
He's somewhere in Normandy.
We don't know where.
Is he alive?
We don't know.
Come with me.
GENERAL MARSHALL:
Goddamn it.
All 4 of them were
in the same company
in the 29th Division,
but we split them up
after the Sullivan brothers
died on the Juneau.
Well, any, uh, contact
with the fourth son, James?
No, sir.
He was dropped
about 15 miles inland
near Neuville.
But that's still deep
behind German lines.
Now, Mac, there is
no way you can know
where in the hell
he was dropped.
First reports out of
lke's people at Shaef
said the 101st is scattered
all to hell and gone.
There's misdrops
all over Normandy.
Assuming Private Ryan
even survived the jump,
he could be anywhere.
In fact,
he's probably K.I.A.
And frankly, sir,
we go sending some sort
of rescue mission,
flat-hatting through swarms
of German reinforcements
all along our axis
of advance,
they're gonna be K.I.A. too.
I have a letter here...
written a long time ago
to a Mrs. Bixby in Boston.
So bear with me.
"Dear Madam,
I have been shown in the files
of the war department
a statement of the adjutant
general of Massachusetts
that you...
are the mother of 5...
sons who have died gloriously
on the field of battle.
I feel how weak and fruitless
must be any words of mine...
that would attempt
to beguile you from the grief...
of a loss so overwhelming.
But I cannot refrain
from tendering to you
the consolation
that may be found...
in the thanks
of the republic...
they died to save.
I pray that
Our Heavenly Father
may assuage the anguish
of your bereavement
and leave you only
the cherished memory
of the loved and lost...
and the solemn pride
that must be yours
to have laid so costly
a sacrifice
upon the altar of freedom.
Yours very sincerely
and respectfully...
''Abraham Lincoln."
That boy is alive.
We are gonna send somebody
to find him...
and we are gonna get him
the hell out of there.
- Yes, sir.
We expected 32 tanks
on the beach.
27 didn't make it.
Miller, Charlie Company.
Go on in, Captain.
I understand
your situation,
but if we don't off-load
those Shermans by 0600,
we're gonna have
an entire division
stuck at Carentan with
its pants around its ankles.
Well, you let me know.
Have Charlie Company
hold at Vierville
until we can get
some armor up there.
Yes, sir.
Runner!
(TRUCK IGNITION GRINDING)
Airborne was supposed
to win an open door
for the rest of us.
Instead they misdropped,
scattered all their
sticks into the wind.
What's your situation?
Uh, yes, sir.
Sector 4 is secure.
We, uh...
we took out towed 88s
here, here...
and here.
They'd already gotten
4 of our Shermans
and a number of our
deuce-and-a-halves.
These 2 minefields
are actually one big one.
We tried to make our way up
through the middle of it,
but it turned into a mixed,
high-density field--
little bit of everything.
Sprengmine 44s,
Schumine 42s,
pot mines, A-200s--
the little wooden bastards
that the mine detectors
don't pick up.
This road here...
they placed big mushrooms--
Teller mine 43s,
I guess for our tanks--
from here right up
to the edge of the village,
right here.
So we marked 'em,
called the engineers.
Resistance?
We had higher support
expectations, sir.
There was an understrength
company without artillery.
Wehrmacht 346 Infantry,
Von Luck Kampfgruppe.
We ended up
with 23 prisoners.
We turned them over
to M.P.s from the 29th.
What about our casualties?
Well...
the figures...
were 35 dead...
times 2 wounded.
They just...
didn't wanna give up
those 88s.
It was a tough assignment.
That's why you got it.
Yes, sir.
John...
I've got another one
for you.
Yes, sir.
This one's straight
from the top.
MILLER:
I wish.
You and I are taking
a squad over to Neuville
on a public relations mission.
HORVATH:
You leading a squad?
Some private in the 101st
lost 3 brothers,
and he's got a ticket home.
How come Neuville?
They think he's up there
somewhere,
part of all
those airborne misdrops.
It's not gonna be easy
finding one
particular soldier
in the middle of this
whole goddamn war.
Like finding a needle
in a stack of needles.
But what about
the company?
We take the pick
of the litter,
and the rest get folded
into Baker.
Jesus Christ.
They took away
your company?
It wasn't my company,
it was the army's.
So they told me, anyway.
Give me REIBEN on B.A.R.,
JACKSON, WADE, Beasley
and Caparzo.
Beasley's dead.
All right.
MELLISH then.
We got anybody speaks French?
Not that I know of.
What about Talbot?
This morning.
Oh.
All right.
I'm gonna go try to dig up
another interpreter.
Assemble at Battalion
Motor Pool on the beach.
Yes, sir.
What are we gonna do?
Listen up-- What?
What we gonna do?
You're going home wrapped
in an American flag
with a hunk of cheese
in your ass, Caparzo.
I thought you liked it
in the ass.
What?
Attention!
As you were.
I'm looking
for Corporal Upham...
Timothy E.
I'm Upham, sir.
I understand you speak
French and German.
Yes, sir.
How's your accent?
Just a slight one
in French,
but my German's clean.
A touch of Bavarian, sir.
Very good. You've
been reassigned to me.
Grab your gear.
We're going to a place
called Neuville.
Yes, sir.
When was this updated?
Updated as of 0830
this morning.
Uh, sir...
this is
the 12th S.S. Panzer.
These are the 2 axis
that advance south.
Sir, there are Germans
in Neuville.
That's what I understand,
Corporal.
Um, sir,
there are a lot of Germans
in Neuville.
You have a problem
with that, Corporal?
No, sir.
Just if you consider
I've never been in combat.
I make maps,
and I translate.
I need someone who speaks
French and German.
Yes, sir.
My 2 guys were killed.
It's just that
I haven't held a weapon
since basic training, sir.
Did you fire the weapon
in basic training?
Yes, sir.
Well, then get your gear.
Sir, may I br--
May I bring
my typewriter, sir?
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much, sir.
That a souvenir?
Uh, no, sir.
Take your time, Corporal.
You should look
on the bright side
of things, Corporal.
Yes, sir.
For one thing...
you don't need
to carry those.
You'll need that.
Need this. Yes, sir.
Don't need that.
(SHEEP BLEATING)
Hey.
Oh. Hey.
You want your head blown off,
you fancy little fuck?
Don't you ever
fuckin' touch me
with those little
rat claws again.
Get the fuck back
in formation.
I was wondering
where you're from,
that's--
Caparzo, is it?
Hey, drop dead, Corporal.
Got you.
And another thing,
every time you salute
the captain,
you make him a target
for the Germans.
Do us a favor.
Don't do it.
Especially when
I'm standing next to him,
capisci?
Uh, capisci.
Corporal,
what's your book about?
Hey, watch your rifle.
Sorry.
It's supposed to be about
the bonds of brotherhood
that develop between
soldiers during war.
Brotherhood?
(LAUGHTER)
What do you know
about brotherhood?
Get a load of this guy, Fish.
Why don't you ask
the captain where he's from?
Yeah, ask the captain.
He'll tell you everything
you wanna know about him.
You wanna explain
the math of this to me?
I mean,
where's the sense
of risking the lives
of the 8 of us
to save one guy?
20 degrees.
Anybody wanna
answer that?
REIBEN,
think about the poor
bastard's mother.
Hey, Doc, I got a mother,
all right?
I mean, you got a mother,
Sarge has got a mother.
I mean, shit, I bet even
the captain's got a mother.
Well, maybe
not the captain,
but the rest of us
got mothers.
"Theirs not to reason why,
theirs but to do and die."
La la la la la la
La la
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean, huh?
We're all supposed
to die, is that it?
Upham's talking
about our duty
as soldiers.
UPHAM:
Yes, sir.
We all have orders, and
we have to follow 'em.
That supersedes
everything,
including your mothers.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Even if you think
the mission's FUBAR, sir?
Especially if you think
the mission's FUBAR.
What's "FUBAR"?
Oh, it's German.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Never heard of that.
Sir...
I have an opinion
on this matter.
Well, by all means,
share it with the squad.
Well, from my way
of thinking, sir,
this entire mission is
a serious misallocation
of valuable
military resources.
Yeah. Go on.
Well, it seems to me, sir,
that God gave me
a special gift,
made me a fine
instrument of warfare.
REIBEN, pay attention.
Now, this is the way
to gripe.
Continue, JACKSON.
Well, what I mean
by that, sir,
is if you was to put me
and this sniper rifle
anywhere up to
and including 1 mile
of Adolf Hitler
with a clear line
of sight, sir--
Pack your bags, fellas.
War's over.
Amen.
Oh, that's brilliant,
bumpkin.
Hey, so, Captain,
what about you?
I mean,
you don't gripe at all?
I don't gripe to you,
REIBEN. I'm a captain.
There's a chain of command.
Gripes go up, not down.
Always up.
You gripe to me,
I gripe to
my superior officer,
so on, so on
and so on.
I don't gripe to you.
I don't gripe
in front of you.
You should know that
as a ranger.
I'm sorry, sir,
but, uh...
let's say
you weren't a captain,
or maybe I was a major.
What would you say then?
Well, in that case,
I'd say this is
an excellent mission, sir,
with an extremely valuable
objective, sir,
worthy of
my best efforts, sir.
Moreover...
I feel heartfelt sorrow
for the mother
of Private James Ryan
and am willing
to lay down my life
and the lives of my men,
especially you, REIBEN,
to ease her suffering.
He's good.
I love him.
(KISSING NOISES)
(KISS)
(INSECT BUZZING)
Right.
(EXPLOSIONS, GUNFIRE
IN DISTANCE)
(GUNFIRE GROWS LOUDER)
WOMAN:
Les Americaines! Les voila!
lis arrivent!
lis viennent nous sauver!
MAN: Nous sommes la!
Viens par ici!
Thunder!
Flash!
Upham, over there.
REIBEN, you four go.
(MAN WITH GERMAN ACCENT SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON LOUDSPEAKER)
Go, go, go, go, go.
You guys are a sight
for sore eyes.
Sergeant Hill,
our relief showed up.
How many are you?
Just 8 of us.
We're not your relief.
Sorry.
What do you mean, sir?
We're here
for a Private Ryan.
Who? Ryan?
What for?
Is he here?
I don't know.
Maybe with a mixed unit
on the other side of town.
Uh-huh.
It's hard to get to.
The Germans punched a hole
in our center,
cut us right in 2.
What's his name again?
Ryan. James Ryan.
He dropped in with 101st.
Goldman, get me
a runner up here.
Runner!
Come on.
(MAN STILL TALKING ON LOUDSPEAKER)
Jonesy,
make a hole up there!
We got stopped
by some intense rifle action
from the eastward.
The Germans have been
reinforcing 2 regiments all day.
The streets have been quiet
for about 45 minutes.
Most of the German fire now
is concentrated to the west.
Who's that
on the loudspeaker?
That's Dagwood Dusseldorf,
our friendly neighborhood
morale officer.
MAN ON LOUDSPEAKER:
The Statue of Liberty is kaputt.
"The Statue Of Liberty
is kaputt."
That's disconcerting.
Take the second left...
Your father
was circumcised
by my rabbi,
you prick!
...looking for
Private Ryan, James,
probably misdropped
with the 101.
Got that?
Cover!
(MACHINE GUN FIRE)
Go!
Those sadistic
fuckin' animals!
Get down.
They know we're not
in direct contact.
They're gonna single out
the runners.
Why do they keep
shooting him up?
Long as his lungs
have breath in them,
he still carries
the message.
We do the same thing.
No, we wouldn't!
WADE!
Get 'em ready to travel.
Yes, sir.
Boyd!
Try again.
See if you can let
Captain Hamill know we're coming.
MILLER: What's the rest
of Neuville like?
Uh, next block's
got 2-story buildings
both sides of the street.
Backtrack, copy? Over.
And then there's a square
with good cover on the left.
Show me.
Sarge, hold right here.
HORVATH:
Yes, sir.
Right, let's stay out
of this enfilade
and use the buildings.
Try a left hook.
Shoot 'n' scoot.
2 of yours, 2 of mine.
Hastings, Goldman,
up front!
Let's go.
REIBEN, Caparzo.
Boyd:
They're still jamming us.
Fundamentals.
Short runs.
High and low
at the corners.
Gonna be tight.
Be prepared
for close contact.
Go.
Upham, you stay
with Sergeant HORVATH.
Stay right here.
I'll wear him like
underwear, Captain!
Stay with me.
Past the end of
the block to the left,
those are the gates
to the square.
Good.
REIBEN, where's
the captain from?
You figure
that one out,
you got yourself
a nice prize.
300 bucks,
last I heard.
Company's got a pool.
5 bucks gets you in.
Oh, easy.
Ow.
It's around this corner.
Defilade right up
to those gates.
Somebody must know
where he's from,
what he did
for a living.
I've been with him
since Kasserine Pass,
and I don't have a clue.
My ankles
are killing me, man.
I'm gonna need a wheelchair
before this war is over.
Ow! That's it.
Oh, my God.
Got ankles
like an old woman.
Like an old...
Ow.
God.
REIBEN...
so you don't even know
where he went to school?
Captain didn't go to school.
They assembled him at O.C.S.
out of spare body parts
of dead G.I.s.
You gotta pay attention
to detail.
I know where he's from
and exactly what he did
'cause I pay attention
to detail.
Hey, Upham...
careful you don't step
in the bullshit.
Do it.
Thunder!
Thunder,
or we will fire on you!
WOMAN:
Ne tirez pas!
On est Francais!
Upham, tell them
to show themselves.
Montrez-vous!
MAN:
On n'est pas armes!
(CHILD CRYING)
Pourquoi tirez?
Mais baissez vos fusils!
On est Francais!
Ask them if they know
where the Germans are.
Ou sount les allemands?
Ca vas pas!
lis sont partout!
Il faut vous emmener
les enfants!
MILLER:
What is he saying?
UPHAM:
Something about the children.
They want us to take
the children.
MILLER: No, no, no.
We can't take the kids.
Non ne pouvons pas
les prendre avec nous!
MILLER:
We can't take the kids!
No!
UPHAM:
Mais non! Mais non!
Nous ne pouvons pas
les prendre avec nous!
They think
they'll be safe with us.
MILLER: It's not gonna be
safe when they're with us!
Are you nuts?!
Listen to the captain!
They think they'll be
safe with us, sir.
MILLER:
Not gonna be safe anywhere.
Caparzo!
Put that kid back!
It's OK.
Caparzo...
put that little girl back!
Caparzo,
get that kid back now!
Upham, how do you say
"It's OK"?
I can't. She reminds me
of my niece, sir.
Caparzo, get the kid
back up there!
Captain,
the decent thing to do
is to take her down the road
to the next town.
We're not here
to do the decent thing!
We're here to follow
fuckin' orders!
Sarge,
take this goddamn kid!
(GUNSHOT)
Cover!
(GRUNTING)
Oh!
FRENCH COUPLE:
Jacqueline! Jacqueline!
- Come on.
- No!
HILL: Goddamn it!
Where'd that come from?
He was on the ground
before we heard the shot.
That's where I'd be.
I didn't see it.
450 yards, Captain.
Maybe a shade under.
I wouldn't venture out there,
fellas!
This sniper's got talent!
Jacqueline!
Mama!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Please don't cry.
I'm gonna take you back
to your mama and papa.
Please don't cry.
Come on.
Carpy.
Captain.
Hold on, Caparzo.
Help me up.
I can walk.
Caparzo, stay still!
All right.
2 clicks, left wind.
(WOMAN SHOUTING
IN FRENCH)
Fish!
Cherie, il faut
surtout pas bouger!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
Captain, can you see him
from there? How is he?
WADE, you stay put.
Where's he shot, Captain?
Captain, can you
see him from there?
You stay there!
Damn it, stay down!
What's the matter with you?
Am I gonna take care of you
if you get hit? Huh?
Fish, come over here.
Carpy,
put your head down.
Put your head down.
(GRUNTING)
O my God,
I trust in Thee.
Let me not be ashamed.
Let not my enemies
triumph over me.
Copy it.
Copy it
and send it for me.
Carpy, you're gonna
send it yourself.
Put it down!
It's got blood!
Carpy, I see it.
It's-- It's...
It's to my dad.
It's got blood on it.
We got him.
Stay down.
MAN:
Jacqueline!
WOMAN:
(FRENCH COUPLE
SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
MELLISH:
How bad is it?
Chest, maybe lung shot.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Get that 30
up the street!
MILLER:
Detail!
HORVATH:
Clear up!
MILLER:
Clear down!
That's why
we can't take children.
Sergeant HORVATH,
do an ammo check.
Upham...
canteens.
Fill 'em up.
Sergeant Hill.
HILL: Yes, sir.
MILLER:
Gather your men.
We'll form up
at the northwest corner
of the square.
JACKSON!
JACKSON:
Sir!
MILLER:
MELLISH, check the tower,
hustle back here.
Right now. Go!
Fuck Ryan.
Thunder!
Flash!
Come on in.
Hey, guys, we're looking
for Captain Hamill.
Somewhere down there,
across the square.
Across the square.
SOLDIER: Go easy.
Watch for snipers.
Take it easy.
Sit down.
All right. Jimmy T.,
go find Captain Hamill,
bring him in here.
What? Up there?
How the hell
should I know?
Would you just go look,
please?
Thank you, you moron.
All right.
You guys just...
flake out here
for a while.
Ohh.
Let me get this goddamn
hitchhiker out of my boot.
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Jesus!
Drop your weapons!
Drop 'em now!
Drop the fucking weapons!
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
I'll shoot you!
Drop! Drop! Drop 'em!
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Now! Put 'em down!
(MACHINE GUN FIRE)
Clear up!
Shit.
Shit!
HAMILL: Clear up!
Clear down!
(GROANING)
Enough to make you old.
Let's hope so.
Fred Hamill,
Pathfinders 101st.
John Miller,
2nd Rangers.
Thank you.
We're here looking for
a Private James Ryan.
He's part
of your outfit.
Any chance at all
you policed him up?
HAMILL:
How was the road in?
MILLER: Scenic.
We lost
most of our ammo.
HORVATH: Not to mention
one of our men.
Lieutenant,
redeploy that bazooka
to the right side
of the road.
LIEUTENANT:
Yes, sir!
And get Ryan up here.
LIEUTENANT: Ryan!
Ryan, front and center!
SOLDIER: Ryan!
Here comes
our boy.
Told you
he was an asshole.
Sir, Private Ryan
reporting as ordered.
At ease.
CAPTAIN MILLER,
2nd Rangers.
He wants a word
with you.
This way.
All right.
Take a knee.
(SIGHS)
Private, I'm afraid I have
some bad news for you.
Well, there isn't
any real easy way
to say this, so, uh...
so I'll just say it.
Your brothers are dead.
We have, uh, orders
to come get you...
'cause you're going home.
Oh, my God,
my brothers are dead.
(SOBBING)
I was gonna take 'em fishing
when we got home.
HAMILL:
I'm so sorry, James.
I can't tell you how much.
How-- How did
they die?
They were killed
in action.
No, that can't be.
They're both--
That... That can't be.
My brothers are still
in grammar school.
You're James Ryan?
Yeah.
James Francis Ryan
from lowa?
James Frederick Ryan,
Minnesota.
Well, does that-- does that
mean my brothers are OK?
Yeah, I'm sure
they're fine.
Are you sure that
they're OK though?
We're looking for
a different Private Ryan.
This is just a big foul-up.
How do you know?
How can you be sure?
How do you know
the foul-up
isn't that his brothers
are OK and that--
Lieutenant.
I'm sorry
for the trouble.
I just wrote them a letter
before I left.
I got to get home.
I got to get home
right now.
I want to go home.
LIEUTENANT:
Shh, take it easy.
So where in the hell
is our Ryan?
I don't know.
Are you in touch
with your C.O.?
That figures.
What unit's
your Ryan in?
Baker Company,
5-0-6.
The guy with the broken
foot, he's 5-0-6, right?
Yeah. Charlie,
I think.
- You think?
- Yeah.
Ryan? Don't know-- Man!
MILLER: Where was
your drop zone?
Just inside of Vierville.
Vierville?
How the hell did you
end up way up here?
You got me, sir.
C-47 took heavy fire.
Pilot went crazy trying
to get out of there,
turning every which way,
took more fire in the drop,
got messy.
I ended up here.
I haven't seen a single guy
from my stick, sir.
God knows
where they are.
Anybody from Baker Company
have a big mouth?
Say where the drop zone
might've been?
No, sir,
but I know Baker Company
had the same rally point
as us.
Show me.
My men are beat.
We're gonna hold up here
for about 3 hours.
We'll pull out after dark.
Got anything left
in this town
like a 3-star hotel,
something with clean sheets
and soft pillows
and room service?
How about
a nice comfy church?
We'll take that.
What have you heard?
How's it all
falling together?
Well, we got
the beachhead secure.
Problem is Monty's taking
his time moving on Caen.
We can't pull out
till he's ready. So--
That guy's overrated.
No argument here.
You got to take Caen,
so you can take Saint-Lo.
You got to take Saint-Lo
to take Valognes.
Valognes,
you got Cherbourg.
And Cherbourg,
you got Paris.
Paris, you get Berlin.
And then
that big boat home.
We sure as hell could
use you around here,
but I understand
what you're doing.
You do?
Yeah. I got a couple
of brothers myself.
Oh.
Good luck.
Thank you.
No, I mean it.
Find him.
Get him home.
HORVATH:
What's with your hand?
I don't know.
It started in Portsmouth
when they brought us
down for embarkation.
It comes and goes.
Well, you may have to get
yourself a new line of work.
This one doesn't seem
to agree with you anymore.
What?
Nothing.
What was the name
of that kid at Anzio?
The one that was always
walking around
on his hands, you know,
and he was
singing that song
about the man
on the flying trapeze?
Vecchio.
Yeah.
Yeah, Vecchio.
He was a goofy kid.
I remember he used to pee
a "V" on everybody's jacket
for Vecchio.
For victory.
Vecchio.
He was so short.
He was a midget,
wasn't he?
"How did you
get to be a ranger?"
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
He got shot in the foot once,
didn't he?
And he was walking
on his hands.
Yeah, well, he could
walk faster on his hands.
He could run faster
on his hands than...
Vecchio.
Yeah.
Caparzo.
You see, when...
when you end up killing
one of your men, you see,
you tell yourself
it happened
so you could save
the lives of 2 or 3
or 10 others.
Maybe a hundred others.
Do you know how many men
I've lost under my command?
How many?
94.
But that means
I've saved the lives
of 10 times that many,
doesn't it?
Maybe even 20, right?
20 times as many?
And that's
how simple it is.
That's how you...
That's how you
rationalize
making the choice
between the mission
and the men.
Except this time,
this mission is a man.
This Ryan
better be worth it.
He'd better go home
and cure some disease
or invent a longer-lasting
lightbulb or something.
'Cause the truth is,
I wouldn't trade 10 Ryans
for one Vecchio
or one Caparzo.
Amen.
(GRUNTS)
Look.
There it goes again.
Sir...
are you all right?
Now, look, we're gonna
move out in 2 hours.
Why don't you
get some sleep?
REIBEN: I don't know
how he does it.
MELLISH: What's that?
Falls asleep like that.
I mean, look at him.
The guy's lights out the minute
his head hits the pack.
Clear conscience.
Yeah, what's that saying?
"If God's on our side,
who the hell could
be on theirs?"
"If God be for us,
who could be against us?"
Yeah, what did I say?
WADE: Well, actually,
the trick to falling asleep
is trying to stay awake.
MELLISH:
How is that, WADE?
WADE: Well, when my
mother was an intern,
she used to work late
through the night,
sleep through the day.
So the only time
that we ever got
to talk about anything
was when she'd get home.
So what I used to do,
I used to lie in my bed
and try to stay awake
as long as I could,
but it never worked
'cause the harder I tried,
the faster
I'd fall asleep.
Yeah, well, that wouldn't have
mattered none in my house.
My ma, she would've come home,
shook me awake,
chatted me up till dawn.
I swear, that woman
was never too tired to talk.
Yeah, that's probably
the only time
she could get a word in.
Funny thing is,
sometimes she'd
come home early,
and I'd pretend
to be asleep.
MELLISH: Who?
Your-- Your mom?
Yeah.
She'd stand in the doorway
looking at me.
And I would just
keep my eyes shut.
And I knew she just wanted
to find out about my day,
that she came home early...
just to talk to me.
And I still wouldn't move.
I'd still pretend
to just be asleep.
I don't know why I did that.
MILLER:
We only got a couple hours.
Shut up and go to sleep.
Captain?
UPHAM: Sir?
Corporal?
How you doin' there?
You all right?
Yeah, I think this is
all good for me, sir.
Really?
How is that?
"War educates
the senses,
calls into action
the will,
perfects the physical
constitution,
brings men into such
swift and close collision
in critical moments
that man measures man."
Yeah, well, I guess
that's Emerson's way of...
finding the bright side.
You know Emerson, sir?
I know some.
So where are you from,
Captain?
What'd you do
before the war?
What's the pool up to?
You know, I think
it's around 300, sir.
Well,
when it gets up to 500,
I'll give you the answers
and we'll split the money.
How about that?
Well, if that's
the way you feel, sir,
I feel it's my duty
under your command
to suggest that we wait
until it gets up
to a thousand, sir.
What if we don't
live that long?
500?
500 would be good,
yeah.
Yes, sir.
Yeah.
Get some sleep,
Corporal.
Yes, sir.
SOLDIER:
Who's got sulfa powder?
SOLDIER: Medic!
My buddy's bleeding!
He needs a tourniquet!
WADE.
WADE: Yes, sir?
See what you can do.
Yes, sir.
Hold on, fellas.
It won't be
much longer.
How we doing here?
All right.
Yeah, doing all right.
Don't worry about it.
Doc's in town.
JACKSON: It's all right.
It's all right.
Don't worry, fellas.
The 29th Infantry's
breaking through.
They'll be here soon.
SOLDIER: Plasma.
Anybody got plasma?
Captain.
Hey, Captain.
Soldier,
you want to fill me in?
Uh, yeah.
Lieutenant Dewindt, sir.
99th Troop Carrier Squadron
carrying in
327th Glider Infantry.
This one was mine, sir.
I was the pilot.
22 men dead.
I ended up over there
without a scratch.
It took my copilot's head
right off.
Well, where's the unit?
Who are these people?
Well, the guys
we came in with, sir,
they headed off first night.
Haven't seen them since.
Meantime, other guys
keep showing up,
1, 2, half-dozen
at a time.
Then some officer'll come along
and patch together a mixed unit,
head off to make trouble, sir.
We're looking for
a Private James Ryan.
He was in Baker Company
5-0-6 of the 101st.
No, you got me, sir.
A lot of guys
come in and out of here.
- Upham.
- Yes, sir?
Check out that squad.
See if Ryan's in it.
Yes, sir.
REIBEN.
Smell that leg
right there.
Find out if it's
south of cheese.
(SNIFFS)
Phew.
WADE: What?
Juden.
SOLDIER: Keep moving.
Keep moving!
Juden.
I'm Juden,
you know?
Ju-den.
Yeah, I couldn't
pry him out of there
hard as I tried.
I'd need a winch.
HORVATH: Yeah.
HORVATH: Stars.
Yep,
Brigadier General Amend,
deputy commander, 101st.
Some fucking genius
had the great idea
of welding a couple
of steel plates
onto our deck to keep
the general safe
from ground fire.
Unfortunately, they forgot
to tell me about it
until we were just
getting airborne.
Well, that's like trying
to fly a freight train.
OK?
Gross overload.
Trim characteristics
all shot to hell.
I nearly broke both my arms
trying to keep her level.
And when--
And when we released,
you know, I cut
as hard as I could,
tried to gain
some altitude
and still keep her
from stalling.
We came down
like a fucking meteor.
And this is how
we ended up.
And the others,
they stopped easy enough
OK, though, you know?
We were just--
We were just too damn heavy,
you know?
The grass was wet.
Downward slope and all.
22 guys dead.
All that for a general?
One man.
Lot of that going around.
FUBAR.
Y'all got that right.
I looked up "FUBAR" in
the German dictionary.
There's no "FUBAR"
in there.
- Upham.
- Yes, sir?
There's more paratroops
out there.
Find out
if one of them's Ryan.
Yes, sir.
Oh, you might want to
check these out, sir.
Dog tags.
More than I really
want to count, sir.
I've-- I've covered
a lot of bodies, sir.
MILLER: JACKSON...
start going
through those.
Yes, sir.
I'll help.
What do you think,
JACKSON?
Do you think that
little prick's in there?
Well, if he is,
I'm gonna find him.
I bet that
son of a bitch is.
REIBEN: I got big money saying
this guy's still alive.
MELLISH: 10 bucks
says I nail him first.
Let's see
who we got in here.
You mugs don't
stand a chance.
All right, you think this little
shit bird's in here or what?
Just keep looking.
All right.
Gary lanico.
Ben Rubino.
Mike Cessacchio.
I swear, all the guineas
are buying it, huh?
MELLISH: Oh, come on,
not the right name.
Wee Willie Winkie,
that's a buddy of yours.
REIBEN:
We gotta find this prick.
Where is
this son of a bitch?
Don't mix them up,
JACKSON, all right?
Keep them in your
own fucking pile.
How am I supposed
to know who we got?
Why don't you just shut up,
REIBEN, all right?
MELLISH:
Everybody be friends.
REIBEN:
Cranky there, huh?
I think
I got a winner.
What are you
talking about?
Ryan.
Ryan?
Take a look at that,
MELLISH.
You know what? You're a genius.
You really are.
R-I-E-N-N-E.
That's Rienne.
And that's French, all right?
You know what that means?
JACKSON:
It's means nothing.
MELLISH:
What beats 3 of a kind?
JACKSON:
I got shit here.
I got all guys
from New York.
REIBEN: Do you need
a hand with that?
MELLISH: Ah,
I got a full house.
REIBEN: Got you beat.
Straight flush.
You were looking
at my tags.
You're cheating.
You know?
Ryan.
REIBEN: Fuckin' unreal,
this guy.
Do you need a hand
with that?
Can you read that shit?
Jesus Christ, look at
this poor bastard, huh?
MELLISH: I guess they're
not bulletproof, huh?
REIBEN: Guess not.
All right?
MELLISH: I don't like what
he's got between his ears.
JACKSON: Sort of
what you fellas got
between your legs.
MELLISH:
We got to give him that.
Not bad for you,
JACKSON.
I got 3 of a kind.
Full house.
The whole goddamn
airborne's watching.
These aren't poker chips.
MELLISH:
All right, all right.
WADE:
Put 'em back in there!
He's not here.
WADE: Put 'em back.
Maybe we should bust up
into a couple of
different groups, huh?
And wander the woods
like Hansel and Gretel,
calling his name.
He's bound to hear us
sooner or later.
Ryan!
That might be a little
hard to do, Captain.
Maybe the locals
have seen him.
Hey, you know--
uh, excusez-moi.
Parlez-vous Ryan,
James ryan?
Merci. Merci beaucoup.
Ryan! Anybody know Ryan,
101st Airborne?
Ryan? You know
a guy named Ryan?
Private James Ryan
from lowa?
Anybody know a Ryan?
James Ryan?!
Hey, Joe,
doesn't, uh, Michaelson
pal around with a Ryan
from "C" Company?
Yeah, I think so.
Well, bring him
up here, would you?
You know
Private Ryan?
You're gonna have
to speak up, sir.
to speak up, sir!
My hearing
is not so good!
It comes and goes!
A German grenade went off
right by my head!
(LOUDER)
Got it, got it.
Do you know
Private Ryan?
Who?
James Ryan?
Jimmy Ryan?
James.
James Francis Ryan.
No, no, no.
Get me a pencil.
Something to write on.
Quick! Quick!
Come on, a pencil!
Here you are.
A small one, sir.
Write this down.
James Francis Ryan,
Question mark.
Iowa, question mark.
Do you know him?
Does he know him?
Read the message. Look.
Yeah. Of course
I know him, sir.
Does he know
where he is?
Yeah, yeah.
MICHAELSON: We missed our drop zone
by about 20 miles,
ended up way over by
Bumville or some damn place.
Him, me, and a couple
of other guys
were coming here
to the rally point,
ran into a colonel
who was gathering up men
to go to, uh... Ramelle...
Ramelle.
To baby-sit a bridge.
That's the last
I've seen of him, sir.
Great! Great!
Thank-- Thank you.
MILLER: Write thank you.
Read and thank you.
MICHAELSON:
You're welcome!
Assemble on me.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Ramelle.
We're here. There.
Ramelle...
is on the Merderet River
right here,
just to the southwest
of us.
You know anything
about this bridge
he was talking
about, Captain?
Yep. The target has
always been Cherbourg.
We can't push on Paris until
we take a deep water port,
and Rommel knows that.
So he's gonna try
to get his armor
across the Merderet River
anywhere he can.
That way, he can hit
our invasion forces in the flank
when we make the big
right turn to Cherbourg.
That makes any village
on that river
with an intact bridge
solid gold real estate.
(COMPASS RATTLING)
Let's go.
WADE: Captain.
HORVATH:
What the hell is that?
MILLER: A radar site.
It's got to be
out of action.
Well, it looks like we
got something in that...
sandbag bunker
right under the station.
See it?
Yeah.
That's my guess, too.
What is it?
Machine gun.
Probably MG-42.
Jesus. Is that
what got those guys?
Maybe one of them's
our boy.
MILLER: No, their
patches are 82nd,
so your luck's
not that good.
I don't know how fast
the rest of you Betties are,
but I'm thinking we detour
this way quick and quiet,
the krauts will never
even know we were here.
So, Captain, what I'm
trying to say is,
why don't we just
go around the thing?
I hear what
you're saying,
but we can't
go around it.
I'm with Reiben
on this one, sir.
I mean,
we left them 88s.
For the air force.
The air force isn't
gonna spend ordinance
on one machine gun.
MELLISH: Uh, Captain.
We can still skip it and
accomplish our mission.
I mean, this isn't
our mission, right, sir?
Oh, that's what you
want to do, Mellish?
You just want
to leave it here
so they can ambush the next
company that comes along?
No, sir, that's not
what I'm saying.
I'm simply saying, it seems
like an unnecessary risk
given our objective, sir.
Our objective
is to win the war.
Sir, I just, uh,
I don't have a good feeling
about this one.
Well, when was
the last time
you felt good
about anything?
All right, 3 runners
with suppressing fire.
Mellish,
you hook to the right.
I'll go up the middle.
Who's going left?
I'll do it.
I'll go left.
All right.
Upham, switch off
with Jackson,
and you linger
in the rear.
UPHAM: Yes, sir.
We advance
and keep pressure on him
till he has to change out
his barrels.
I think we should be able
to hit him from grenade range.
Maybe I should go up
the middle, sir.
The way you run?
I don't think so.
Maybe I should
go left, sir.
Maybe you
should shut up.
Reiben, base of fire.
Mags and clips where
you can reach 'em and...
and extra grenades
for the base runners.
(PANTING)
HORVATH: Hill's clear!
4 down and dead!
MILLER: Upham, grab the gear
and get up here!
We need water
and extra dressing now!
Get the morphine out of
the extra medical kit!
HORVATH:
Son of a bitch.
MILLER:
Get some sulfa on there.
WADE: Move my legs up.
Move my legs up.
More sulfa, MELLISH.
MELLISH:
Listen to my voice.
You're gonna be
all right, Doc.
WADE: How's it look?
WADE, you're fine.
You're going
on a hospital ship.
MILLER: More sulfa!
WADE: Put my legs up,
put my legs up.
I got 'em, I got 'em,
I got 'em, I got 'em.
MILLER: You're
gonna be OK, WADE.
Upham,
give me your canteen!
HORVATH: Come on.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
HORVATH: Put some
pressure on it.
MILLER:
You're gonna be ok.
WADE: How's it look?
MILLER: Give him
some morphine.
How's it look?
MILLER:
It's all right.
How's it look?
HORVATH:
You're gonna be OK.
Here comes
the morphine.
Am I shot
in the spine?
JACKSON:
You're OK, Wade.
Am I shot
in the spine?
MILLER: Lift him up.
Easy, easy, easy.
HORVATH: Put some
pressure on him.
Easy, easy.
HORVATH:
Lift him up.
It's OK, Doc.
It's all right.
Wade, you got
an exit wound.
It's in the small
of your back.
How big-- How big's
the hole in the--
It's about the size
of an acorn.
MELLISH: You're fine.
You're fine.
(GAGGING)
(COUGHING)
HORVATH: Put some
pressure on it.
Put some pressure
on it.
It's all right.
HORVATH: Put some more
pressure on it!
Is there anything bleeding
worse than the others?
Yeah, right here.
Do you know what it is?
No.
Right here. I'm gonna
put your hand on it.
JACKSON: We got some
pressure on her.
Right there. OK?
That's the one.
Oh, my God, my liver!
Oh, my God, it's my liver!
Tell us what to do.
Tell us how to fix you.
What can we do?
Tell us what to do.
MELLISH: Oh, shit.
I could use-- I could use
a little more morphine.
More morphine, sir?
OK. OK.
Give it to him.
I don't wanna die.
MELLISH:
Here you go. WADE.
Here you go.
Here it comes. Shh.
JACKSON: There you go.
There you--
Give him another one.
Mama?
I want to go home,
I want to go home.
Mama! Mama! Mam--
Mama, Mama,
Mama, Mama, Mam--
(BLOWS LANDING)
(SOLDIER GRUNTS)
Aah!
MELLISH:
Reiben, hold him!
Unh!
(SHOUTING)
Bitte!
Totet mich nicht!
Ich will mich ergeben!
Vater unser im himmel,
geheiligt werde den name,
dein reich komme...
Not yet.
First make him mark and cover
Wade's body for grave detail.
Same thing for
those paratroopers down there.
Strip that stuff off him.
Check him for intelligence.
Ask this piece of shit if
he's the one who shot WADE.
Ask him!
It doesn't matter.
It does matter!
Warst du am
maschinengewehr?
Nein. Ich hab nachgeladen,
ich hab nicht geschossen.
Shut up with that
filthy pig latin.
Sprichst du deutsch?
Jackson,
you're hit.
(MUTTERING IN GERMAN)
Shut up.
I guess it just
skinned the arm, sir.
MILLER: Get it
cleaned and dressed.
You and Sarge
watch the perimeter.
Bitte, totet mich nicht.
Ich will mich ergeben.
He says
please don't shoot.
I don't care what
he says, Upham.
Sir? Sir, you're gonna
let them kill him?
This is not right, sir.
You can help him
with the bodies.
What is happening?
This is bullshit.
(SOBBING)
American. (SNIFFS)
I like American.
Steamboat Willie.
Toot, toot.
Yeah, Steamboat Willie.
American.
Ich bin noch nicht fertig!
Ich muss hier noch
viel tiefer graben!
Ist noch lange
nicht tief genug!
He's says he's
not finished.
That's what you think.
Come on.
- Nein!
- Yeah.
Nein! Ich bin
noch nicht fertig!
Please...
I like America.
Fancy schmancy!
What a cinch!
Go fly a kite! Cat got
your tongue! Cool beans!
(PANTING)
Betty Boop! What a dish!
Betty Grable. Nice gams.
(PANTING)
I say can you see
l-- I say...
Fuck Hitler.
Tut mir leid um den mann,
den ihr verloren habt.
Den sanitater.
Es ist halt krieg, nicht?
Sir, he says
he's sorry about WADE.
He says he's sorry
about WADE, sir.
Captain!
Captain,
this isn't right!
You know this.
He's a prisoner.
He surrendered.
He surrendered, sir!
Tell him...
(COCKS RIFLE)
to march a thousand paces
in that direction.
Then he can take off
the blindfold.
We'll be gone,
and he turns himself in
to the first Allied patrol
he comes across.
You gotta be kidding.
We're letting him go?
He's a P.O.W.,
Reiben.
Can't take him with us.
Our guys'll pick him up
sooner or later.
(SOLDIER MUTTERING)
Only if he doesn't get picked up
by his own wehrmacht first,
then thrown back
into circulation.
Captain, you just let
the enemy go.
This is
such bullshit.
Y'all got that right.
Bullshit?
This is bullshit?
Shooting a prisoner,
that'd be OK?
It's against
the goddamn rules!
The goddamn rules
just walked off
with your new friend.
But I guess that was
the decent thing to do,
huh, Captain?
Get your gear.
Let's go.
HORVATH: You heard him.
Gear up.
The captain
just gave you an order.
Yeah.
Like the one he gave to
take this machine gun.
That was a real doozy,
wasn't it, Sarge?
Soldier, you are
way outta line.
Yes, sir, that was
one hell of a call,
coming to take
this nest,
but, what the hell,
we only lost one of
our guys going for it.
I hope Mama Ryan's
real fuckin' happy
knowing that
little Jimmy's life
is more important
than 2 of our guys!
Then again, we haven't
found him yet, have we?
Huh?!
Get the hell off me!
HORVATH:
Reiben, get up.
Gear up. Fall in.
I'm done with
this mission.
Hey! Hey!
Don't you walk away
from your captain.
Reiben, get back in line.
I'll spend the rest of
my life in the stockade
if I have to,
but I'm done with this.
I'm not gonna ask
you again, soldier.
Captain!
JACKSON:
This is bullshit!
Fall in!
You gonna shoot me
over Ryan?
No, I'm gonna shoot you
'cause I don't like you.
Sir!
If he wants to go,
just let him go!
Are you letting
this happen?
Captain!
You see this?
Captain? Sir?
Sir, Ryan's dead.
Bullshit!
Sir, we have
a situation.
I have a sixth sense
about these things.
I know it
in my bones.
You don't kill that
son of a bitch kraut.
Now you're gonna
shoot me?
He's better than you.
Then why don't you
just do it, Sarge?
Do it, man.
Put one in my leg--
I'm gonna shoot you
in your big goddamn mouth!
Well, put your money
where your mouth is--
You don't know when to shut up.
You don't know how to shut up.
Captain, please!
What's the pool
on me up to?
What?
You are a coward
son of a bitch!
I'm waiting,
Sarge.
Mike, what's the pool
on me up to right now?
What-- What's it up to?
What is it, $300?
Is that it, 300?
I'm a schoolteacher.
I teach English composition
in this little town called
Addley, Pennsylvania.
The last 11 years,
I've been at
Thomas Alva Edison High School.
I was the coach
of the baseball team
in the springtime.
I'll be doggone.
Back home, when I'd tell people
what I do for a living,
they'd think,
"Well, that figures."
But over here,
it's a...
a big...
a big mystery.
So I guess
I've changed some.
Sometimes I wonder
if I've changed so much,
my wife is even going
to recognize me
whenever it is
I get back to her.
And how I'll ever
be able to...
to tell her about
days like today.
Ah, Ryan...
I don't know anything
about Ryan.
I don't care.
The man means nothing to me.
He's just a name.
But if...
(SIGHS)
you know,
if going to Ramelle and...
finding him so he can go home,
if that earns me the right
to get back to my wife,
well then...
then that's my mission.
You want to leave?
You want to go off
and fight the war?
All right.
All right,
I won't stop you.
I'll even put in
the paperwork.
I just know that
every man I kill,
the farther away
from home I feel.
(GRUNTS)
(SOFTLY)
By memories
Of days gone by
In my solitude
You taunt me
With memories
That never die
I sit in my chair
Filled with despair
There's no one
Could be so sad
With gloom everywhere
I sit and I stare...
(RUMBLING)
Half-track! Cover!
(BAZOOKA FIRES)
Who's doing the shooting?
(GUNFIRE)
Aah!
Get ready to move on
their left flank!
Take their left flank!
MELLISH: Hold on and
make sure they're down!
Corporal Henderson: 101st!
We're coming out!
Corporal Henderson: That was
a recon element, Second S.S.
We've been expecting a probe.
That must have been it.
CAPTAIN MILLER,
Charlie Company, 2nd Rangers.
Corporal Henderson,
Easy Company, 501st.
Ryan, first of the 506th.
P.F.C. Toynbe,
third of the 506th.
James Francis Ryan?
RYAN: Yes, sir.
How'd you guess that?
MILLER: Looks like you guys
got hit pretty hard.
HENDERSON: Yes, sir.
Small unit action.
They came in and beat
the hell out of us with 88s.
Tell you what, sir,
if you're our relief,
I'm gonna file a complaint.
I wouldn't
blame you.
Who's your C.O.?
It would have been
Captain Jennings, sir.
I'm afraid the best
we can muster up
right now is a corporal.
So, what are you guys
all about?
MILLER: We're here
for him. Ryan.
RYAN: Me, sir?
MILLER: James Francis Ryan
of lowa?
RYAN: Yes, sir. Payton, lowa,
That's correct.
What is this about?
MILLER: Your brothers
were killed in combat.
RYAN: Which--
Which ones?
MILLER: All of them.
Uh...
RYAN: on-- on the level?
MILLER: Yeah.
I'm afraid so.
Uh...
you might want to take
some time with this.
If there's someplace
you want to go and...
What's this all about?
Ryan lost
his brothers.
Which one?
All of them.
RYAN: You--
You came all the way
out here to tell me that?
Well, you're--
you're going home.
Our orders are
to bring you back.
Bring me back?
Corporal Henderson...
I don't mean to leave you
even more shorthanded,
but orders are orders.
Any communication
about when you're going
to be relieved up here?
Sir, there's
no way to tell.
We have no idea what's
happening south of us.
I have my orders,
too, sir.
They don't include me
abandoning my post.
I understand that,
but this changes things.
I don't see
that it does, sir.
The chief of staff
for the United States Army
says it does.
Sir, our orders are to hold
this bridge at all cost.
Our planes in the 82nd
have taken out every bridge
across the Merderet
with the exception of 2.
One at Valognes
and this one here.
We let the Germans
take 'em,
we'll lose our foothold
and have to displace.
Private, your outfit wants
to stay, that's one thing.
Your party's over here.
Sir, I can't leave until
at least reinforcements--
You got 3 minutes
to gather your gear.
Sir, what about them?
There's barely enough--
REIBEN: Hey, asshole!
2 of our guys already died
trying to find you, all right?
Sir?
That's right.
What were their names?
Irwin Wade and
Adrian Caparzo.
Wade and...
Caparzo.
It doesn't make any sense.
It doesn't make
any sense, sir.
Why? Why do I
deserve to go?
Why not any of
these guys?
They all fought
just as hard as me!
Is that what they're
supposed to tell your mother
when they send her another
folded American flag?
Tell her
that when you found me,
I was here with the only
brothers I have left.
And that there's no way
I was gonna desert them.
I think
she'll understand that.
There's no way
I'm leaving this bridge.
(SIGHS)
What are your orders?
Sergeant, we have crossed
some strange boundary here.
The world has taken
a turn for the surreal.
Clearly, but the question
still stands.
I don't know.
What do you think?
You don't want to know
what I think.
No, Mike, I do.
Well...
part of me thinks
the kid's right.
What's he done
to deserve this?
If he wants
to stay here, fine.
Let's leave him
and go home.
Yeah.
But another
part of me thinks...
what if by
some miracle we stay
and actually make it
out of here?
Some day we might look
back on this and decide
that saving Private Ryan
was the one decent thing
we were able
to pull out of
this whole god-awful,
shitty mess.
That's what
I was thinking, sir.
Like you said, Captain,
if we do that...
we all earn
the right to go home.
Oh, brother.
TRASK:
This is everything.
You got the 2 30-caliber
machine guns,
17 grenades,
11 Hawkins mines.
You got the 2 bazookas, but
they only got 8 rounds left,
and assorted small arms.
We had a 60 mortar,
but an arty round
took it out.
Might as well be spit wads
if they roll on us with tanks.
Which they're sure to do.
What you thinking, sir?
Well...
I'm thinking
they're going to try
to whip around
the flanks--
MILLER: Unless we can draw
them up this main road here
in-between these buildings
where all the rubble makes
a bit of a bottleneck.
Disable 'em?
If we can.
Make that tank
a 60-ton roadblock.
We do that, we got a fighting
chance at their flanks.
Yes, sir, that's good.
Split them up.
Don't let them mass anywhere.
Hit them hard as we can
one-on-one
and fall back
to the bridge.
Machine gun
on the move down here,
number 2
up high somewhere
to piss a little bad
news on their heads.
MILLER: That would be
the idea.
Jackson?
If we can, I'd like to get
you up in that bell tower.
Yes, sir.
Give you a little company
if you need it.
Yes, sir. Some company
couldn't hurt.
I'd say a...
a 30 with about
a thousand rounds
would be OK.
Parker,
job opportunity.
REIBEN: It's not the worst
idea ever, Captain.
It's just that everything
depends on getting the tank
down this main road for us
to knock out, right?
So, how the hell do you
plan on doing that?
HORVATH: Reiben's right.
As our esteemed colleague
from the airborne pointed out,
what we got here are
a bunch of spit wads,
so how do we stop the tank
if we get it to commit?
Give it a rabbit
to chase.
We could hit the tank
in the tracks.
Yeah, but with what?
Well, we could try
a sticky bomb.
RYAN:
Sticky bomb, sir?
Sir, are you
making that up?
No. It's
in the field manual.
You check it out
if you want to.
Well, we seem to be
out of field manuals, sir.
Perhaps you can
enlighten us.
All right, you have some
demolition, don't you?
Some TNT or
some composition "B"?
That, sir, is the one
thing we got plenty of.
I got that bridge wired
with enough composition "B"
to blow it twice.
All right, you can
spare some, then.
You take
a standard-issue G.I. sock,
cram it with as much
comp "B" as it can hold,
rig up a simple fuse,
then you coat the whole
thing with axle grease.
That way,
when you throw it,
it should stick.
It's a bomb that sticks.
It's a sticky bomb.
You come up
with a better way
to knock the tracks
off a tank,
I'm all ears.
This is good.
Now we got
to surrender our socks.
Haul away.
All right, select
the field of fire.
Cross fire with the one
in the bell tower.
All right. I can cover
12 to 9 from here.
SOLDIER: Easy!
JACKSON: I got her!
Here are the mines.
For being the best
we can do,
that forward machine gun
is not in a terrible
firing position.
And this position
right here...
this is the Alamo.
They push us back
this far,
last man alive
blows the bridge.
We only got a 30-second
delay on that fuse,
so let everyone know that
if you are that last man,
you better hurry
your ass off,
or you're not going
to be alive long.
Captain?
Where am I during all this?
Never more than 2 feet
away from me,
and that's not negotiable.
I'll get some ammo.
Come on.
- Hey, Upham.
- Yes.
Listen to me, all right?
Yeah.
You listening?
- Yes.
- All right.
We're going to be
displacing
and falling back like
crazy sons of bitches...
right up there.
So you got to be
Johnny-on-the-spot
with the ammo,
or we're dead.
Right.
You understand that?
- Johnny-on-the-spot.
- Yeah.
You all right?
(SIGHS) Yeah.
- Hmm?
- Yes.
You know, when we were
shipping out of England,
the supply sergeant was handing
out cartons of cigarettes,
and I said, "No, thank you.
I don't smoke.
I don't smoke."
Quite a situation, huh?
Unbelievable.
Here.
Fucked up
beyond all recognition,
right?
Yeah,
you got that right.
FUBAR.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Ouch. Ahem.
Yeah, well...
FUBAR.
It's going to be
a real show, huh?
(SIGHS)
Yeah, OK.
Take it easy.
FUBAR.
(WOMAN SINGING IN FRENCH)
Who's that
singing, sir?
Edith Piaf.
RYAN: What's she
so upset about?
Her lover left her,
but she still sees his face
everywhere she goes.
That would do it.
(SINGING CONTINUES)
Even life itself
only represents you.
Sometimes I dream
that I'm in your arms.
What was that part?
She sang that before.
That's the chorus.
The chorus.
And you speak softly
in my ear...
and you say things
that make my eyes close.
And I find that
marvelous.
Uh, again...
Upham, uh...
to be honest with you,
l-- I find myself
curiously
aroused by you.
(LAUGHTER)
Marvelous.
No, it's-- You know, it's
a really melancholy song.
At the beginning
of the song, she says,
"And then one day,
you left.
You left me, and, uh...
I've been desperate
ever since.
I see you all over the sky.
I see you all over the Earth."
HORVATH: Jesus, Upham,
any more songs like this,
the krauts aren't going
to have to shoot me.
I'm just going to slit
my own wrists.
REIBEN: You know, you're
a strange bird, Upham.
Ohh. I'm sorry.
It's Edith, you know.
You know what that song
reminds me of?
It reminds me of
Mrs. Rachel Troubowitz
and what she said to me
the day I left
for basic.
What, "Don't touch me"?
(LAUGHTER)
No.
Mrs. Rachel Troubowitz
is our super's wife.
She comes
into my mom's shop
to try on a few things,
all right?
And she's easily, like,
a 44 double "E."
Double "E"?
These things
are massive, right?
Those are big.
No.
And I've got her convinced
that she's, like,
a 42 "D," all right?
So we're
in the dressing room.
She's trying to squeeze
into this side-cut,
silk-ribboned,
triple-panel girdle
with the shelf-lift
brassiere.
And it's beautiful,
because she's just pouring
out of this thing, you know?
Is it really tight?
No, no. It's beautiful.
And she sees me,
and she can tell
I got a hard-on the size
of the Statue of Liberty.
And she says to me,
"Richard, calm down."
And she says,
"When you're over there,
if you see anything
that upsets you,
or if you're ever scared,
I want you to close
your eyes
and think of these.
You understand?"
So I said, "Yes, ma'am."
(SONG ENDS)
RYAN: Are you
all right, sir?
Yeah. I'm just
keeping the rhythm.
(NEW SONG BEGINS)
(SNAPS FINGER)
Is it true you were
a teacher back home?
Yes.
See, that's something
I could never do, you know?
Not after the way
me and my brothers
treated our teachers.
No, sir.
(LAUGHS)
I had a thousand kids
like you.
I can't see
my brothers' faces.
And I've been trying,
and I can't see
their faces at all.
Has that ever happened
to you?
You got to think
of a context.
What does that mean?
Well, you don't just think
about their faces.
You think about
something specific--
something you've done
together.
Well, when I think of home,
I think of something specific.
I think of my hammock
in the backyard or...
my wife pruning
the rose bushes
in a pair of
my old work gloves.
Well, this one night,
two of my brothers came
and woke me up in
the middle of the night,
and they said they had
a surprise for me.
So they took me to the barn,
up into the loft, and...
there was
my oldest brother Dan...
with Alice--
Alice Jardine.
(LAUGHS)
I mean...
picture a girl who just
took a nose-dive
from the ugly tree
and hit every branch
coming down.
(LAUGHS)
And-- And Dan's
got her shirt off.
So he's working
on this bra,
and he's trying
to get it off,
and all of a sudden,
Sean just screams out...
"Danny, you're
a young man!
Don't do it!"
(LAUGHS)
And so Alice Jardine
hears this,
and she screams
and she jumps up
and she tries to get
running out of the barn,
but she's still got
this shirt over her head.
She goes running
right into the wall
and knocks herself out.
So now Dan
is just so mad at us.
He-- He starts
coming after us,
but at the same time,
Alice is over there
unconscious.
He's got to wake her up.
So he grabs her
by a leg,
and he's dragging her.
At the same time,
he picks up a shovel,
and he's going
after Sean.
And Sean said, "What are you
trying to hit me for?
I just did you a favor."
And so this makes Dan
more angry.
He tries to swing
this thing.
He loses the shovel.
It goes out of his grasp
and hits a kerosene lantern.
The thing explodes.
The whole barn
almost goes up
because of this thing.
Uhh.
That was it.
That was the last--
That was-- Dan went off
to basic the next day.
That was the last night
the 4 of us were together.
That was 2 years ago.
Hmm. Oh, my.
RYAN: Tell me
about your wife
and those rose bushes.
No.
No. That one I save
just for me.
(EDITH PIAF SINGING IN FRENCH)
(FAINT RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING)
(SOLDIER TURNS OFF RECORD PLAYER)
Enemy from the east.
He sees Tiger tanks,
2 of them;
Panzer tanks, 2 of them;
infantry,
50 plus change.
Disperse.
You know what to do.
Reiben,
get on the rabbit.
Yes, sir.
HORVATH: Upham,
get some cover.
Mellish and Henderson,
lock and load!
Everybody
check your ammo!
Good luck,
Reiben.
I don't need
any luck, Sarge.
I was born lucky.
One in five tracer?
Yep, and tracers
point both ways.
Yeah? Why don't you
check the head space,
and she should run.
Upham!
Hustle up!
Corporal Upham?
Yes, sir.
We don't have
a 30-caliber machine gun
in this position.
Either Mr. Mellish
or Mr. Jackson in
the bell tower needs that.
Yes, sir.
Upham! Jackson's fine.
Turn around to Mellish.
(MACHINE GUN FIRES)
There's a ton
of infantry, Captain.
I don't know if they took
the bait, though.
(TANKS APPROACH)
You got any more of that?
Panzers didn't take
the bait.
Infantry's
moving to the left.
Half-track just went by
with about 20 troops.
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
MAN: Dies war
die zweiten kompanie!
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(RUMBLING)
Mellish!
Henderson!
Displace!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
You! Do it now!
Light it up!
You! Light it!
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
30 infantry
on the right flank!
Get over there,
find a hole, and stop them!
Displace!
MELLISH: Upham!
Clear!
Krauts!
Right flank!
SOLDIER: Sanitater!
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
SOLDIER:
Bleiben panzer!
Get down!
Upham! Upham!
30 cal! Hurry!
And find the captain!
This flank's going to fold!
(BULLETS WHIZZING PAST)
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(SCREAMING)
Disperse!
He's still in this fight!
No, no, Ryan,
get down! Get down!
SOLDIER: Aah! Aah!
Ryan!
Ryan.
RYAN:
Get off of me!
MILLER:
Are you all right?
Uhh! Get off of me!
REIBEN: I'm fine, too,
Captain. Thanks.
MILLER: OK, both sides!
Get aboard!
Get a grenade in there!
(COUGHS)
HENDERSON: Grenade!
20 mil!
Flak gun, 20 millimeter.
Take it out!
Heavy weapon
in defilade below!
I ain't got a shot!
Pincer move, Parker!
Targets 8 o'clock low!
PARKER: Shit!
God grant me strength.
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Come on! Displace!
Come on!
(SCREAMING)
(EXPLOSION)
MILLER: Cover,
Upham! Cover!
Cover!
Aah!
PARKER: I'm out
of 30 caliber.
Blessed be the Lord,
my strength,
which teaches
my hands to war
and my fingers to fight.
My goodness
and my fortress...
my high tower
and my Deliverer.
My shield
and He in Whom I trust.
Here you go, baby.
Parker, get down!
Captain, that 20 millimeter
is killing us.
We got to try
to flank it somehow.
Well, let me get over
for the top shot.
Upham!
Crap.
(EXPLOSIONS)
Upham!
Upham, ammo,
goddamn it!
(TANK APPROACHES)
(MEN SPEAKING GERMAN)
MAN:
Haben sie handgrenaden?
I'm jammed!
You got any 30 cal?
HENDERSON:
I'm out.
Shit.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Upham?
Upham!
(BODY FALLS)
(GAGS)
Aah!
(GAGGING)
(SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
REIBEN!
Come on! Aah!
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(MEN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
I'm out!
I need another bandoleer!
Anybody got a bandoleer?
(MELLISH, SOLDIER FIGHTING)
God!
Aah!
You stupid...
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Aah!
Ow!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Unh! Unh! Unh!
Haah!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Let's stop. Let's stop.
Let's stop. Listen to me!
Listen to me!
Stop! Stop!
No! D-D-D-D--
Stop. Stop.
(GAGS)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Shh, shh.
Shh.
(SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
Aah!
Son of-- Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch!
(SOBS)
(BOTH SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Zuruck!
Zuruck! Ja, genau!
Gut so!
Geh nach rechts!
Nach rechts!
I'm out.
Those 60 rounds.
We can use them
without the tube.
How?
Fuse-arming wire,
set back,
heave it!
Uhh!
(MEN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Panzer schreck!
Uhh!
(MAN SHOUTS IN GERMAN)
(MAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Ow!
We're going
to the Alamo.
Alamo! Alamo!
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Aah!
We'll take it!
You fall back!
You be right behind us!
Soon as we're in business!
Displace.
REIBEN.
Reload.
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Yaah!
All right, go.
MILLER: We're
blowing the bridge!
Get off!
Clear the bridge!
Oh!
Sarge!
Mike, are you
all right?
I just got the wind
knocked out of me.
Well, get out of here!
Take cover! We're going
to blow this bridge!
Ow!
Come on, come on!
Tiger coming!
Coming across the bridge!
Das haus
auf zwei hundert meter,
elf uhr.
(SOUND FADES)
(MUFFLED VOICE) Captain,
get behind something!
Come on, Captain,
move it!
Mike.
Mike!
(GUNFIRE)
REIBEN: Captain.
Captain, where the hell
are you going?
Captain, get back here!
Hande hoch!
Die waffen niederlegen!
Ich kenne
den soldaten.
Ich kenne den mann.
Und haltet die schnauzen.
Upham.
(BODY FALLS)
Haut ab.
Verschwindet!
(AIRPLANE PASSES)
Hang in there, Captain.
MAN: First squad on me.
MAN: Drivers,
keep moving.
Get the 60 set up.
MAN: See if we can
cut them off.
MAN:
Clear the intersection!
Medic!
We got a medic?
They're tank-busters,
sir-- P-51s.
Angels on our shoulders.
What, sir?
MILLER: James...
earn this.
Earn it.
GENERAL MARSHALL:
My Dear Mrs. Ryan,
it's with the most
profound sense of joy
that I write to inform you
your son,
Private James Ryan,
is well and,
at this very moment,
on his way home from
European battlefields.
Reports from the front indicate
James did his duty in combat
with great courage
and steadfast dedication
even after he was informed
of the tragic loss
your family has suffered
in this great campaign
to rid the world of tyranny
and oppression.
I take great pleasure in joining
the secretary of war,
the men and women
of the United States Army,
and the citizens
of a grateful nation
in wishing you good health
and many years of happiness
with James at your side.
Nothing,
not even the safe return
of a beloved son,
can compensate you
or the thousands
of other American families
who have suffered great loss
in this tragic war.
And I might share
with you some words
which have sustained me
through long, dark nights
of peril, loss
and heartache.
And I quote,
"I pray
that our Heavenly Father
may assuage the anguish
of your bereavement
and leave you only
the cherished memory
of the loved and lost
and the solemn pride
that must be yours
to have laid
so costly a sacrifice
upon the altar of freedom.
Abraham Lincoln."
Yours very sincerely
and respectfully,
George C. Marshall,
General, Chief Of Staff.
My family
is with me today.
They wanted
to come with me.
To be honest
with you,
I... I wasn't sure
how I'd feel
coming back here.
Every day I think about
what you said to me
that day on the bridge.
And I've tried
to live my life
the best I could.
I hope
that was enough.
I hope that,
at least in your eyes...
I've earned
what all of you
have done for me.
James.
"Captain
John H. Miller."
Tell me I've led
a good life.
What?
Tell me I'm a good man.
You are.